Hey
friends, let's
talk about the
confrontation between the Federal Reserve and the White House today. Don't be fooled by
Trump's frequent
bombshell policies that
shock the market;
I feel that the
real risk, severely underestimated by the market, lies in the conflict between him and the Fed. If
this isn't handled well, it wo
n't just be a black swan event; Harwell could
become
a "
fishing stone." Harwell's ability to manipulate public opinion is undeniable. He's been relentlessly attacking
Powell for months,
never repeating himself. From his
first day in office, he bombarded the Fed,
saying he should have cut rates immediately,
repeatedly criticizing Powell for acting too late and too slowly. "
Look at Europe, they
started cutting rates much earlier, already
seven times in a row.
Why is it only you, this 'stubborn old man,' who's slow to cut? Of course, we'll stop for him. He's already cut rates seven times in a row, why is it only you, this 'stubborn old man,' who won't cut?" "
We don't rely on our data." "We, the old man, don't
rely on our
data." "
We, the old man, don't rely on our data." "
We are all dependents. We must maintain the independence of the Federal Reserve and
not be
affected." But
in April, Trump seemed to enter a berserk mode. It's not just tariffs sweeping the globe; if the Fed
doesn't cut interest rates soon, the US is doomed.
The
sooner Powell leaves, the better. I want him gone;
he won't stay long.
Meaning, I want to fire him. You thought the conflict was escalating, but the next day Trump softened, saying, "I didn't intend to dismiss Powell. I was just saying
that. You misheard me." But then he started
giving Powell nicknames, calling him "Too Tate Powell" or "Mr. Too Late." "Mr. Too Late" is a fool, doesn't understand anything, and doesn't even understand as much as I do.
Actually, the conflict between the two sides boils down to Trump wanting Powell to
cut interest rates quickly. That's all. The logic behind this isn't hard to understand. As we analyzed in the last video, the US government, while having many goals, currently prioritizes, without exception,
alleviating fiscal pressure. And the most crucial aspect is lowering the government's borrowing costs, which means
lowering interest rates. At the same time, another
major goal is to depreciate the dollar to alleviate the pressure of manufacturing outflow. You see, both of these goals require
lowering interest rates. This is the White House's main demand. To get Powell to cooperate, Trump played the bad cop, while Treasury Secretary Bessant played the good cop, meeting with Powell for breakfast
every week, subtly pressuring him. The
Fed's core objective is to control inflation. In the past year, US
inflation has actually been kept below 3%, so last year the Fed cut interest rates by 100 basis points. However, this year, due to the high uncertainty surrounding Trump's policies, especially tariffs, which could potentially trigger a resurgence of inflation, Powell paused rate cuts, saying he needed to see clear data proving that prices had indeed cooled down before
cutting rates again. In fact,
the demands of both sides are simple,
clear, and conflicting,
leading to Trump's aggressive pressure on Powell.
Today, let's use this opportunity
to discuss the relationship between the Federal Reserve, the US government, the
Treasury Department, and the White House. Don't
think Trump is an exception. The
relationship between the Federal Reserve, the world's most important central bank, and successive US presidents, arguably one of the most powerful people in the world, has always been very delicate. It's
not simply about independence,
nor is it about them being in cahoots.
To gain a deeper understanding of the
love-hate relationship between the Federal Reserve and the White House, and to
grasp the logic behind it,
I think the best way is to
quickly review the
eight major battles the Federal Reserve has experienced over the past century—its
own "war of independence."
Then
we'll analyze
how Trump might deal with Powell now. Let me
tell you, this is quite interesting. Enough with the
chit-chat, let's begin. In
1913, the U.S. Congress passed the Federal Reserve Act, establishing the Federal Reserve as a central bank composed
of 12 reserve banks.
Legally, it was
stipulated that it was "independent but subject to supervision,"
able to
independently implement
monetary policy. However, in
reality, at that time, if its
independence
was out of 10,
I'd give it a 5—
not even a passing grade.
Soon after, the Federal Reserve faced its first battle: the
gold war of the 1930s. When the
Federal Reserve was first established,
the U.S. was still on the gold standard.
The law required that for every dollar issued,
40% must be backed by gold.
Therefore, the Federal Reserve was
somewhat like an ultimate gold merchant, controlling how
much gold it held. Regarding the corresponding amount of
money printed,
while the gold standard sounded very reasonable,
strictly limiting the amount of currency issued, it
actually had a very serious problem:
it forced the Federal Reserve to tighten monetary policy
even during periods of severe recession,
exacerbating economic turmoil. When the
Great Depression broke out in 1929,
people kept going to banks to exchange for gold. The
Federal Reserve's gold reserves plummeted from $4.5 billion
to $3.2 billion,
greatly limiting its ability to issue currency.
At the height of the crisis, when stimulus policies were most needed, the
Federal Reserve was instead severely constrained and forced to tighten monetary policy.
Therefore,
President Roosevelt took the lead in the White House,
enacting the Gold Reserve Act in 1934,
abandoning the gold standard.
From then on, the dollar was no longer backed by gold,
and gold was nationalized.
All citizens had to surrender their gold, but
crucially, the recipient was not the Federal Reserve,
but the U.S. Treasury Department. Furthermore,
he required the Federal Reserve to transfer the vast majority of its gold to the
Treasury Department.
This move
almost completely reclaimed the Federal Reserve
's function regarding gold; on the
other hand, regarding
monetary policy, the
discount rate controlled by the Federal Reserve was
essentially dictated by the Treasury Department.
Prioritizing the issuance of Treasury bonds
essentially rendered the Federal Reserve powerless. The
then-Federal Reserve Chairman later recalled jokingly
saying that while he was nominally the chairman of the central bank, a position of great
prestige,
he actually
felt like he was just
doing very basic administrative work for the Treasury.
Soon after, World War II broke out,
and to cope with the war, the
Federal Reserve even lost its superficial independence.
The Treasury was essentially
subservient to the Federal Reserve, which had the
authority to purchase Treasury bonds at rates below 0.5% to
help finance the Treasury.
So, you see, during this period, although the Federal Reserve was
nominally
still an independent central bank,
it was actually
an appendage of the Treasury. The Federal
Reserve lost the "Gold War," and its
independence score was 2 out of 10.
After World War II, the Federal Reserve
should have become more independent and
no longer had to bail out the Treasury.
However, with the US government about to start another war, the Federal Reserve
should have become more independent and no longer had to bail out the Treasury.
North Korea wanted to
continue the Federal Reserve's model of printing money to buy Treasury bonds.
This time, the Federal Reserve stood firm,
because the previous excessive money printing had already caused
US inflation to exceed 9%. If
this continued, the
economy would really be in trouble.
Therefore, the Federal Reserve told Truman... The Federal Reserve
did not agree to Truman's demands.
After several very difficult fiscal negotiations,
and through communication with
one of Truman's friends,
in January 1951, Truman publicly announced that the Federal Reserve
had agreed to the Treasury's plan to purchase Treasury bonds. The
Federal Reserve Chairman was immediately alarmed, asking, "
When did I agree to that?" The
conflict escalated. After all, the Federal Reserve was legally independent and had some leverage. He said, "If the Treasury continues to be so stubborn, our policy decisions will be completely unreliable." After a month of intense public conflict, the
Treasury finally conceded, and the Federal Reserve
and the Treasury
signed the famous 1951 Monetary Agreement. The
Treasury agreed that the
Federal Reserve would no longer purchase Treasury bonds at a fixed interest rate.
The market generally believes that the
Federal Reserve's true independence
began with this 1951 agreement. The Federal Reserve won the
battle for independence, and the
chairman resigned.
He was replaced by
an Assistant Secretary of the Treasury who was in charge of negotiations at the time,
named William Martin.
This name is important; remember it.
You see, the
Treasury originally thought it was a good idea: "
I'll put one of my own people in the Federal Reserve so that
even if I sign the agreement..." Policy support
could be provided,
but what they didn't expect was that the person
they planted in the
Federal Reserve—the so-called "longest-serving chairman in history, with nearly 20 years on the job, and a Fed building
named after him"—I'll
say a few words about Martin. Just
looking at his resume, you can tell
he's incredibly intelligent.
He graduated from Yale University, and
after graduation, his
first job was at a brokerage firm, where he became a
partner within two years. At
29, he became a
member of the NYSE board of directors; at 31,
he was a "prodigy." He
enlisted during World
War II,
becoming a colonel.
After the war, he joined the Treasury Department, becoming Assistant Secretary of the Treasury, and then Chairman of the Federal Reserve, serving for 19 years. Quite impressive. I feel his 19 years in office profoundly influenced the Fed's policy logic and its power dynamics with the Treasury. Protected by the legal agreements signed previously,
Martin's attitude was
significantly more accommodating than previous Fed chairmen. In
most cases,
controlling inflation was the
primary consideration.
From 1952 to 1965, the
average inflation rate in the United States was only 1.3%, a period
known as the "Martin Miracle." In
1965, the United States was mired in the Vietnam War and its
finances were strained.
President Johnson pressured Martin
to ease monetary policy.
Martin refused, saying
he wouldn't lower interest rates and
would raise them by 0.5%.
President Johnson was furious, saying, "
Our children are dying in Vietnam,
and you won't print money!"
Frankly, Martin, if he were alive today, would be a hawk among hawks.
At the time, US inflation was less than 2%,
but Martin felt the unemployment rate was too low and there was a
risk of overheating.
So he raised interest rates to 4.5%.
However, this didn't mean Martin
was
completely inflexible and ignored government demands.
His style, in
short,
was principled
but intermittently yielding.
For example, he conceded when Eisenhower pressured him in 1953 and
Kennedy in the 1960s,
cooperating with the Treasury's monetary policy.
Overall,
Martin did establish a very good
independent Federal Reserve,
but his independence
didn't entirely stem from power; it came from
legal protection.
Many of these differences stem from his balancing act.
He created a "quartet"
consisting of the Federal Reserve Chairman, the Treasury Secretary, the
White House Budget Director,
and the Chairman of the Council of Economic Advisers.
These four individuals regularly dined together, facilitating
thorough communication
and helping the Federal Reserve
maintain its relationship with the White House.
So, you see, the
tradition of Powell dining with Bessant daily
is a continuation of that era.
This Martin era—
I'd also consider it a battle—
can be seen as a victory for the Federal Reserve, with its
independence rating rising to 7 points. Are
you curious when it will go up further? Let
me just say,
this score
is my personal subjective assessment and has no authority. If you disagree, then
you're right. Speaking of which, have you already noticed that the Federal Reserve and the US government, ultimately, mostly disagree? When the
Federal Reserve
feels the need to raise interest rates or tighten monetary policy, the US government doesn't allow it.
Economist Hertzel commented that the
Federal Reserve Chairman often faces a president and Congress hostile to interest rate hikes.
Why is he hostile?
Actually, as a government, there are two main reasons why it dislikes raising interest rates: one is that
raising interest rates would stifle the economy. A key indicator
people use to measure a president's performance is the economic performance during their
term. Therefore, the period when US presidents exert the most pressure on the Federal Reserve is generally the year before an election, especially the
year before a
re-election election. Another reason is that the higher the interest rate on government debt, the
higher the government's borrowing costs. So, whenever there's a war and money is needed, the Treasury puts immense pressure on the Federal Reserve. Economic development costs are the core, fundamental interests of the government.
So, presidents and governments are sometimes quite helpless. If you have a very hawkish Federal Reserve chairman, prices may be tightly controlled, but the economy might be very bad during your term. And the
Federal Reserve chairman can
still be re-elected, which is more understandable
than your own situation. A simple reaction will make
you jump up and complain. Conversely, when interest rates are lowered, the president is very happy.
Look at Trump's first term; Powell raised interest rates four times in 2018, and Trump openly criticized Powell and the Federal Reserve. But when the pandemic hit,
Powell quickly and urgently lowered interest rates to 0%. They also initiated quantitative easing and the
Federal Reserve provided a lot of support,
but when the pandemic hit,
Powell quickly
cut interest rates to 0% and
also started quantitative easing! "Okay, let's go back to the Martin era. Still Martin? He's about to be removed. By 1969, US inflation had begun to rise rapidly. Martin aggressively raised interest rates by 1%. The newly elected President Nixon was
furious. He had promised American voters during the previous election to revitalize the US economy, but upon taking office,
he faced Martin's promise, which plunged the country into recession. Martin, who had served as Chairman of the Federal Reserve for almost 20 years, stood firm and completely
ignored Nixon's pressure. Nixon wanted to replace
Martin quickly, but the problem was that, legally, the US president
couldn't simply dismiss the Chairman of the Federal Reserve. So Nixon used a subtle method to force him out of office: he announced in advance that the new Chairman of the Federal Reserve would be Burns, one of his own. This shifted all market attention and focus to Burns, effectively sidelining Martin and effectively
removing him from office prematurely." Isn't this quite similar to Powell's situation?
Powell's term is also expiring, which is why many people speculate that Trump will use the same tactic Nixon employed,
prematurely announcing Powell's
successor to sideline him. Back then, Burns, who was promoted by Nixon, had a policy style that can be summarized in four words: obedient. He immediately lowered interest rates, and then in 1972, to help Nixon's re-election, he
lowered rates again. Moreover, he frequently lowered rates, and often not proactively at all. How do
I know
this? Because of the infamous Watergate scandal. The White House recordings conveniently revealed some conversations between Nixon and Burns. For example, on December 10, 1971,
Burns called Nixon and said, "Mr. President, I want you to know that I have lowered the discount rate. Good, good." On another occasion, Burns said, "In my opinion, I have done everything I can to
help you become president and establish your reputation and status in American history." See how cooperative
he was? You don't even need to ask; I'll have already fulfilled your wishes. Of course, I'm being a little joking,
haha. It
makes you feel like Burns is a sycophant. In reality, he's also a highly accomplished economist. He did try to negotiate with Nixon, but not enough. In the end, during Burns' tenure, the Federal Reserve essentially surrendered its independence—a mere 3 out of 10. However, as the saying goes, extremes beget their opposites, and without destruction, there is
no construction. Burns' tenure did bring some
benefits. Because he was such a terrible chairman, Congress began to strictly scrutinize the Fed's policies, preventing him from acting recklessly, especially not under the president's direction. The Fed's dual objectives of price controls and employment were clearly defined, requiring the
Fed chairman to submit a "Monetary Policy Report" to Congress every six months and attend a hearing in both houses of Congress. And let me tell you, during that hearing, I felt sorry for the Fed chairman. Despite his high position, sitting in the middle of Congress for
two hours felt like being a prisoner, subjected to
endless
interrogations: Why did you raise interest rates? Why is inflation so
high? Why did you print
money? Why this? Why that? A million whys! And it happens twice a
year. When I first saw it, I was really scared by the scale of it. I felt like if I were
sitting there, I would definitely cry. Anyway, I'm getting off-topic. Let's get back to the point. In short, after the Burns era, Congress greatly strengthened its institutional oversight of the Federal Reserve. And then came the
Fed's moment of glory, with its next
chairman, Paul Volcker. You see, this moment of glory, first of all, he was exceptionally tall, over
two meters tall. Even inflation had to bow down. When Paul Volcker took office in 1979,
he faced what could be described as the worst period for the US economy in nearly 100 years: an inflation rate of 14%, an unemployment rate of 7.5%, and runaway gold prices. The
US economy was in stagflation. After Volcker took office, he was extremely tough. His goal was to protect prices and suppress inflation. The federal funds rate rose from 11% to over 20%, and then inflation was instantly suppressed, from 13.5% in 1980 to 3.2% in 1983. This is known
as the "Volcker Miracle." (I added this myself.) Let me tell you... Don't think that his interest rate hikes were as simple as a few words. He was under
immense
pressure. Raising rates to 20% directly led to the worst economic recession in the US since World War II. The unemployment rate soared to 10.8
% in 1982, and many small and medium-sized enterprises and farmers went bankrupt. He frequently received death threats. President Carter complained privately, and President Reagan tried to intervene, but nothing worked. Volcker said it was his way. He even directly refused an invitation from the White House, saying that the Federal Reserve would not serve any political party. This period can be said to be the most intense period of conflict between the Federal Reserve and the
US government. But time proved that Volcker's choice was correct, not just right, but extremely correct.
After a brief period of pain, the US
economy regained its vitality for at least 20 years. At that time, the US had just left the Bretton Woods
system. Volcker's strong approach of maintaining dollar inflation greatly enhanced market confidence in the dollar, and can be said to have laid the foundation for the dollar's status as the global reserve currency for the next half-century. Also after
Volcker, although the Federal Reserve had a dual mission, when the two conflicted, inflation generally took precedence. The independence rating of the Federal Reserve during the Volcker
era... I
give him a 9 out of 10. Greenspan, the successor to Walker, served as Chairman of the Federal Reserve for 18 and a half years, the second longest term. If I had to summarize his tenure in one word, it would be "muddling through." Let me tell you,
Greenspan is a master of language, taking the art of
language to its
extreme. He's incredibly ambiguous; you
can interpret it however you want. For example, he often says, "If you think you understand me, you've misunderstood me. What do you mean?" He
also loves using metaphors. For instance, when he says the market is experiencing irrational exuberance, is it truly exuberance or overheating?
And when he answers questions at congressional hearings, he's always noncommittal, always
presenting a seemingly plausible
argument. I feel like he's mastered some Eastern linguistic art. But Greenspan was actually very good at balancing the needs of the market and the Treasury. It was also from him that the Federal Reserve emphasized full communication and synchronizing market expectations. As a veteran serving four presidents, his prestige during his tenure reached the pinnacle of all
Federal Reserve chairmen. In the end, even the US president dared not complain. His independence score is 8 out of 10. Of course,
Greenspan had prestige;
he maintained
the Fed's independence, but he didn't make any mistakes. His excessive relaxation of regulations on financial derivatives can be considered one of the most fundamental reasons for the 2008 subprime mortgage crisis. Have
you noticed a pattern? The job of a Federal Reserve
chairman isn't just about controlling inflation. Essentially, he's an intermediary between the market and the US government. He can influence the market, and the government can influence the Fed. The Fed can't simply stand firmly on the market's side; otherwise, the White House will definitely try to punish him. And if he sides with
the government, it's even more serious; the market might retaliate against the dollar, impacting both the Fed and the US government. Therefore, the Fed needs to find a very delicate balance: maintaining independence and winning
market trust
while avoiding displeasing the government and the
president. Look at Martin and
Greenspan—why were they able to serve for so long? It's not that they were simply tough, but rather that they were very adept at maintaining a balance and maneuvering between the two. They had a very good grasp of the nuances. As we just mentioned, Martin was tough in principle, but intermittently yielded. Greenspan, on the other hand, was more conciliatory. Both were very adaptable, upholding independence while knowing when to be tactful. This way, every time there was a change of administration, although the president could appoint a new chairman, there was always the feeling that the current chairman was just a bit stubborn, but
could still cooperate when necessary, and the market still trusted
him. Otherwise, there would be no change. Then, after the financial crisis, how independent were Chairs C and Yellen? I can only say that on the surface, the government didn't interfere much with their decisions, but their actual
independence wasn't very apparent. Because during this period, the Fed's policies were almost perfectly aligned with the
government's needs. To cope with the financial crisis, the Fed had been implementing low interest rates, massive quantitative easing, and printing money for over a decade. These policies not only utilized the past ten years of low interest rates, massive quantitative easing, and printing money, but also met market demands and what the government wanted to see. With both demands synchronized, the
Fed, as the middleman, found it very easy to act. Therefore, during this period... You rarely hear the president raise objections to the Federal Reserve. The only occasional congressional hearings that still generate a bit of tension are the congressional hearings. So, in this
post-financial crisis era, I'd give the Fed's independence a 7 out of 10. As we just discussed, the
Fed and the Treasury have been locked in a legal battle for years, mainly revolving around monetary policy, such as interest rate cuts. However, after the financial crisis, the Fed significantly strengthened
its regulatory power—regulation of banks and financial institutions. The Fed has always had this
regulatory power,
but we did
n't mention it much before
because its role wasn't prominent. But after 2008, the
US passed the important Dodd-Frank Act, greatly strengthening regulatory
requirements
for large financial institutions. A key enforcer is the
Fed. So now, Wall Street investment bankers dread this act; various risk indicators, capital adequacy ratios, etc., are extremely stringent. Is this a bit of an overreaction? I think it's definitely a little, but without proper overreaction, it's difficult to go too far. Even with such stringency, some
small banks like Silicon Valley Bank have collapsed. The struggle over
regulatory independence didn't face much resistance before 2020, given the Fed's massive money printing at that time. The unprecedented quantitative easing had everyone on edge, which was understandable. But now, with
profits rising and tightening coupled with stringent regulations, resistance has increased.
Don't be fooled by Trump's constant calls for the Fed to cut rates; you can see from Bessant's interviews that, institutionally, what they want to crack isn't the Fed's
monetary policy,
but its regulatory power. Finally, we've arrived at the post-pandemic era, the trade war era, or the Trump era, the Powell era.
The feeling of the
Powell era is that monetary policy will be implemented more independently. It can be firm when necessary, but it will also
compromise slightly under pressure. That is, it will cooperate with the Treasury and the President. For example, it has begun to comply with Republican demands, gradually relaxing regulations on financial institutions. During the pandemic, it also worked with the Treasury to provide loans to local governments and small and medium-sized enterprises. You can't say the Fed has given up, because it was indeed
necessary, but overall, it feels relatively relaxed. It maintains
independence while also considering the White House and the Treasury. So, its independence score is 8 out of
100. Looking back over the past 100 years, do you get a sense of this?
At its core, the Federal Reserve Act protects the Fed's independence, but in reality... It still requires a specific inter-personal game. Let's see how Trump plans to play this game. What methods does the White House and the Treasury Department have to pressure the Federal Reserve? The first move is personnel. Can Trump fire Powell? The simple answer is no, unless Trump
can provide
sufficient legitimate reasons, such as proving that Powell broke the law, seriously neglected his duties, was morally corrupt, or mentally unstable. It seems that if Trump wants to
fire Powell, he would have to
go through labor arbitration. Currently, this possibility is very low. The appointment mechanism for the
Federal Reserve Chairman is as follows: the US President nominates, then the Senate confirms, and the term is four years, with the possibility of re-election. The President cannot fire an incumbent Chairman simply
because he is dissatisfied with the Fed's policies.
So even if Trump wants to replace him, he has to wait until his four-year term ends before he can appoint a new Chairman. Powell was nominated in 2018 during Trump's first term and was re-elected during Biden's term, so his term expires in 2026.
Trump could, like Nixon did with Martin, announce the next Chairman in advance and use this "shadow chairman" to sideline Powell, but so far he hasn't done that. Let me tell you, if Trump actually wants to
influence the Federal Reserve, he does
n't necessarily have to arrest Powell alone. Because the Federal Reserve has a very important characteristic: it's
not a single entity. In fact, all
major decisions at the
Federal Reserve are made by a 12-member Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC). Each person has equal voting weight, so theoretically, the chairman doesn't have greater voting power, nor is everyone's opinion
solely determined by the chairman. Therefore, for Trump, if he could control a majority of these 12 people, he could control and influence the Fed's decisions. Mechanistically, seven of these 12 are appointed by the government, and five are presidents of regional reserve banks. For those interested in the rotation details, you can watch our video about the Federal Reserve. In short,
he has so many people involved in decision-making to balance the relationship between the government, the banks, and the market. But even the seven people appointed by the government can't be replaced easily. Each person has a very long 14-year term, expiring every two years. For example, although Powell's term as chairman expires in 2026, his term as a board member doesn't end until 2028. So even if
he steps down next year... He will most likely remain on the
12-person board as a governor, retaining his voting rights. In fact, the government's attempts to influence the Federal Reserve, besides appointing a chairman, have consistently focused on filling the
FOMC with more dovish members—those who advocate for monetary
easing.
Analyzing the Fed's monetary policy typically involves analyzing which of the 12 members are hawkish and dovish, and what their individual
leanings are. It's clear that the seven chosen by the government are mostly dovish, while the hawks are primarily from the Federal Reserve Banks. The White House is continuously
influencing the Fed's decisions indirectly
through
personnel appointments. However, at this juncture, it's impossible for him to replace all seven at once, making immediate results difficult. Another possible way for Trump to interfere with the Fed is through executive orders. While amending legislation is difficult, the president
can temporarily
restrict the
Fed through executive orders. For example, in February of this year,
Trump issued Executive
Order 14215, requiring all independent agencies to submit major regulations to the White House for review before issuing them, and to communicate with the White House regularly. This is essentially the same as the Trump-Bessant situation we mentioned earlier. To
limit the Federal Reserve's regulatory power and to get it to loosen regulations, Trump's most common
way of influencing the Fed, besides these two tactics, is through public opinion. He criticizes European countries for cutting interest rates while arguing that the US economy will collapse if things continue like this, and criticizes Powell for always being too late and making mistakes. He tries to pressure the Fed by influencing public opinion. However, this tactic seems ineffective and has even backfired. Despite Trump's high position as President of the United States, arguably arguably more
powerful than most, one of the institutions
he finds most helpless is the Federal Reserve. He can readily implement major policies against other departments, organizations, and even countries, but he
criticizes the Fed more harshly than anyone else. However, he doesn't resort to any concrete physical attacks. He threatened to fire
Powell
but backed down less than a week later. For example, the executive order requiring all actions to be reported to the White House, while weakening
the Fed's power, only applies to regulatory matters.
The executive order specifically includes a clause excluding the Fed's monetary policy. Take the Federal Reserve's monetary policy,
for example. It
doesn't need White House review. Why? Because there's absolutely no need for this clause.
This actually indirectly confirms a logic: the White House doesn't dare. Although it wants to, it doesn't dare to interfere too much with the Fed's policy. Even if it wants to try, it's done with extreme caution. This is because the Fed isn't simply an independent institution; it has powerful backers. What deters the US government is market trust. Look at
Martin Volker, Greenspan, Bernanke, Yellen,
Powell—they've built up this sustainable market trust bit by bit from 1951 to
the present. It's this trust that supports the dollar as an international reserve currency, allowing global capital and central banks to invest in the dollar without too many concerns. I dare say
this trust far exceeds the market's trust in the
US government. Look at tariffs—they sound very significant, connecting so many
countries. As we analyzed last time, its imports only account for $3 trillion of GDP. The scope is broad, but the connection isn't that tight.
But the financial market is different. You could say it's deeply connected to the very core of the US economy. Whether it's
government bonds, all large corporate bonds, or all large corporate stocks, they are all built on the global market's trust in the US financial market. Trust in the US dollar is at stake, and the main stabilizing force behind this is the
Federal Reserve. So, Trump pressuring him to cut interest rates is one thing,
but if he inadvertently shakes the foundation of the dollar, that would be disastrous. Bessant has repeatedly
warned the White House that firing Powell could trigger market turmoil. However, Trump's recent actions have indeed shaken the market's trust in the dollar to some extent. Other countries are
more or less de-dollarizing. Although the market generally believes that Trump wouldn't dare touch the Fed, wouldn't dare weaken the Fed, and wouldn't dare
undermine the Fed's independence, there's still concern that if he's in a bad mood one day, he might release a policy. If that really happens, it would be a true black swan event for the
market. "
Mr. President, I want you to know that I've
lowered the discount rate, helping you become president." How shameless! This ushered in the Fed's moment of glory. Paul Walker even bet on what's known as the "Walker Miracle" (
I added it myself!). This ushered in the Fed's moment of glory. Paul Walker even bet on what's known as the "
Walker Miracle" (
I added it myself!).