Hello everyone, this is Brain Boss.
Today I'm going to talk about something I'm becoming increasingly certain of: the
clever weak
use their intelligence to invent excuses for their failures.
My mother had a huge regret.
Around 2000, the
best middle school in a district of Shenzhen had just been established and was
recruiting teachers from inland areas. They
even offered my mother
very good terms and conditions,
but she didn't go.
At the time, she thought her biggest reason for not going was
ridiculous, even in her own reflection. It was the
common saying in the 1990s that
Guangdong was so chaotic.
My father was a civil servant, and it wasn't something he could just
leave on a whim. Back then,
as a woman with a child, she
felt unsafe living away from home.
Actually, she could have just gone there for
a week
and found out if it was really as bad as the rumors said.
My mother was a college graduate,
but she actually believed that kind of talk and
ended up staying where she was,
leaving a regret in her life. Have you ever had a
moment like this in your life? You
clearly know you should do something,
you've even figured out how to do it,
but you just don't do it.
Then time passes, the
window closes, the
opportunity disappears, and when
you look back,
all the reasons you didn't do it seem
absurd and laughable.
Don't tell me there isn't.
So I want to answer this question seriously today
because I've observed many people,
including myself, those
around me, and all sorts of people
among the tens of thousands of viewers on this channel.
I'm increasingly convinced that
a person's success or failure is
n't as closely related to whether they know or understand as you think. What
truly determines everything at the bottom
is something I call "
mental strength." With strong mental strength, what you know can become what
you do. With
weak mental strength, no matter how much you have in your head, when it's time to
act, your
body will find all sorts of reasons to stay still.
In this episode,
we'll explain this thoroughly. In a
previous video about building an intelligent trust system, I
mentioned a framework:
imagine a person as a computer.
The body is the hardware, and
mental strength and spirit are the operating system.
The knowledge, skills, and cognitive methodologies you learn
are the application software installed on it.
What you ultimately output in life—your
judgment,
your action,
your final success or failure,
your sense of happiness—are all
results of this application running.
Once this framework is established,
you'll find something absurd. Look around at the
people around you—
those who spend a lot of money on courses, classes, and
various book clubs...
People who spend a lot of time browsing knowledge bloggers—their
state of mind,
their final life outcomes—often differ greatly from
your expectations.
This isn't an isolated case;
it's a systemic phenomenon.
Why? Because they keep buying apps
but never seriously maintain the hardware
or truly upgrade the operating system.
A broken machine won't run even the best software, it wo
n't even complete the installation process. This is common sense. But there's something even more critical. Do you
know what a computer system is like when it crashes? It won't display a blue screen, won't pop up a window
saying "I'm down, my output is unreliable." It will continue to run, continue to output; the interface looks normal, but the underlying logic of everything it outputs is flawed. Similarly, when a person is physically weak, mentally exhausted, and emotionally drained, the brain won't honestly say, "
I'm
incapable of making judgments right now, don't believe what I'm saying."
It will
continue to output judgments, continue to give you all sorts of analyses and reasons. However, the
underlying driving force
behind these analyses and reasons is no longer the pursuit of truth; it becomes something else entirely: how to quickly
relieve physical and mental discomfort. So, have you ever seen that kind of person? He speaks with great logic and analyzes
problems systematically, but his life is a complete mess. He can explain every single instance clearly: why it wasn't his fault, why it was an external problem, why the timing was wrong, why it was someone else's fault. This isn't him lying; it's
his system outputting its best possible outcome. But that outcome serves his weakness, not the truth. This has happened repeatedly in history. Let me read
you a quote from Liu Zhongjing, about his own experience—I think it's one of
his
most brilliant statements. I read a
historical account about the Umayyad Caliphate in Damascus. When the Umayyad Caliphate collapsed, the newly established Abbasid Caliphate wanted to kill all the princes of the previous dynasty.
Two princes, Abdul Rahman and another, fled
across the river. The pursuers shouted, "Come back! The emperor has pardoned you! You can come back and live the life of a pampered member of the CPPCC!" One prince returned, while
Abdul Rahman
refused to go back, swam to the other side, escaped to Spain, and established his own dynasty. The remaining prince... Unsurprisingly, he was killed. Why? Because he wasn't a good swimmer. He wanted to escape because he knew the conqueror's promises were untrustworthy, but as he swam, he found it too difficult and his physical weakness gave way. He took a chance, thinking, "Instead of struggling, I might as well try my luck." When
Cicero was
wanted by Octavian, he tried to escape by
boat. According to Russell,
he didn't escape
because of seasickness. This sounds ridiculous, but it's actually quite possible. During the Battle of Austerlitz, look at the private letters of Louis Philippe and others.
They seemed completely unaware of the major events unfolding, talking about their children's
illnesses and so on. Shi Dakai didn't cross the Dadu River in time because he had a newborn son and decided to stop to
celebrate for ten days. Ten days later, the Qing army arrived, and
he could no longer escape. Therefore, even supposedly brilliant figures are influenced by physical habits, or rather, by weaknesses and inertia, far more than we are willing to admit. We generally imagine that we
make decisions based on causal analysis. We might analyze the results and then act decisively, but that's
not always the case. We often betray ourselves simply because of laziness. I might also betray myself because of
laziness. For example, if someone suddenly offered to be my sugar daddy—this is what Liu Zhongjing said—and I suddenly thought about the
difficulties of independent living
and the discomfort of being in an unfamiliar environment, I might suddenly lose my will. For instance, before 2009, I wasn't sure I would leave. I knew my laziness might keep me there
forever. But if I had stayed until today, I definitely wouldn't have left. At that point, I would definitely use my remaining intelligence to invent a set of
reasons to argue why the environment couldn't deteriorate and could continue until disaster struck. But
I might have made such a decision due to physical weakness.
In the end, this didn't happen; there were too many lucky factors. I absolutely dare not say it was due to my personal brilliance. I would rather say that God mercifully
saved me, using a series of seemingly completely accidental phenomena to
allow me to escape at the last moment. So I don't know if I will have enough determination and perseverance to escape before the last moment. Or perhaps I'll simply succumb to laziness, even knowing the path leads to a downward spiral,
and adopt a passive, wait-and-see approach. I've read this passage many times. What I admire most about him isn't the historical examples in the first half, but the second half. He calmly examines his potential weaknesses with a Christian-esque, original sin-like attitude. Most people are accustomed to
weakness and dare not face their true selves. When you become weak, your intelligence doesn't disappear, but is misappropriated. What was originally meant for pursuing the truth now becomes a tool
serving laziness and fear. The smarter you are, the more sophisticated
and convincing your reasons become, and the
harder it is to extricate yourself from this trap. This is why many intelligent people ultimately lose to those who seem less intelligent at the most crucial moments—because they are clever enough to deceive themselves deeply enough. There is neuroscientific evidence for this. When a person is in a state of chronic weakness,
fatigue, and
sleep deprivation for a long time, their body continuously secretes cortisol, the stress hormone. Short-
term cortisol is life-saving, making you react
faster in the face of danger. However, long-term high cortisol systematically damages your prefrontal cortex. What is the prefrontal cortex? It's where you make long-term judgments, exercise self-control, and delay gratification. It's the place where you can say, "I'm feeling terrible
right now, but I know it's the right thing to do." Once prefrontal cortex function declines, the amygdala takes over. What is the amygdala? It's the primitive response center for fear, impulses, and the instinct to
seek pleasure and avoid pain. It has only one logic: to make me feel comfortable now, to get me out of discomfort now. So, the prince who turned back
halfway through his swim, his prefrontal cortex, soaked in cortisol, wasn't telling him whether his decision was right in the
long run. It was the amygdala howling, "Too tired, stop! Find a reason to stop!" This wasn't due to a
lack of cognition; it was because his nervous system was hijacked by his body's state. Psychologist William James said something counterintuitive: "It's not that you're afraid, so you tremble; it's that you tremble, so you feel afraid." Emotions aren't the cause; emotions are your brain's
retrospective interpretation of bodily signals. In other words, you're not weak because of a misjudgment; your body weakens first, and then your brain concocts a story of "I can't do it, it's
not worth it, let it go" to explain that feeling of weakness.
So, from a neuroscience perspective, the sophisticated reasons invented by clever people aren't cognition, but rather the
secretion of cortisol. Okay, now you
know... How does physical weakness
hijack the brain? And how does the brain fabricate reasons after being hijacked? Actually,
philosophers noticed this phenomenon earlier than scientists and described it more vividly. Nietzsche called it slave morality. Many people have heard this term, but few truly understand it, or rather,
they understand it but do
n't realize how prevalent and insidious it is in daily life. Nietzsche said that there are two moral systems in human history. One is called master morality. The logical starting
point of master morality is the self. It starts from "I am strong, I am good," and then defines what is worth pursuing, what is bad, and
what should be surpassed. This morality is proactive, outward-growing, and productive.
The other is called slave morality. The logical starting point of slave morality is not the self, but the other. It starts from "He is bad," "He is a liar," "He is exploiting me," "He
doesn't deserve those things," and then deduces that "So I, as the victim, as the oppressed party, am kind, pure, and morally superior." Do you see the difference?
Master morality says, "I want to become stronger, I want to move forward, I want to achieve greater things." Slave morality says, "He is bad, he has a problem, what he has
received should not belong to him." The former is creation, the latter is negation. The former is moving
forward. The latter is going in circles. But Nietzsche's greatest insight was
n't pointing out the difference between these two kinds of morality, but rather explaining why slave morality is so
vital and so difficult to eradicate. It's because it makes people feel good, and it requires absolutely no cost. You don't need to
become stronger, you don't need to work hard, you do
n't need to take any risks. All you need is a redefinition of value, and you can go from loser to victim, from incompetent to fighter, from penniless to morally victorious. This deal is too good to pass up, so it's everywhere. In the few months I've been running this channel, you can find tons of
this
slave morality in the comments. For example, in my video about my years in the crypto world and China's gilded age, many industry leaders were exposed. Just the other day, someone commented that back then it was like carrying a coffin on the road. On one hand,
you had to be bold and prepare for the
worst—even if it meant going to jail, you couldn't let down the brothers who fought alongside you—on the other hand,
you had to apply the brakes and have a backup plan.
This kind of person clearly has done great things, is much more capable than me, and has definitely achieved much greater results. Do you
think Jack Ma didn't take risks back then? When he created Alipay, he was risking illegal fundraising. Around the same time he was building Alipay, Zhejiang province saw the nationally shocking Wu Ying case. The protagonist illegally raised 700 million yuan and was ultimately sentenced to death. Do you think
Jack Ma would have panicked if he knew this news? Similarly, shouldn't Didi have
taken the
risk of operating unlicensed taxis from the beginning? Before that, police entrapment of unlicensed taxis became a hot topic online. Not to mention, even email services were considered
illegal postal services. I've heard firsthand accounts of police arresting people and confiscating hard drives. The development of the internet has almost always been a step along the legal line. However, many who missed the blockchain wave, didn't make money, or even lost money,
see the industry as nothing more than a scam. Those four words encapsulate the entire history. Think about what happened behind those four words. In the years since the rise of cryptocurrency, some have made a lot of money and changed their lives; some have been watching and regretting it; some have become
gamblers in this hellish arena, suffering heavy losses. What did those who did
n't make money go through? You say there are too many cryptocurrency scammers and it's too chaotic. But what about Bitcoin, which accounts for more than half of the cryptocurrency world? Did Satoshi Nakamoto fleece you? Ethereum and Binance Coin have increased thousands of times, creating far more wealth than those worthless cryptocurrencies that fleece you. Even Justin Sun—
look at the Tron chart; its price has seen huge
increases. These are the facts. But acknowledging these facts requires admitting my judgment was
flawed, or that I was too cowardly, or that I didn't actually
understand it. Saying these things is
too painful. People with weaker hardware skills can't even bear this psychological burden. So, slave mentality comes into play, providing them with a low-cost way
out. The crypto world is full of scammers. His failure to make money isn't his fault; it's because he didn't want to be a scammer, because his conscience wasn't dead, because he clearly saw through the
scam. You see, his
losses or inaction become proof of his noble character in this narrative. Failure becomes a medal, weakness becomes a virtue. Moreover, this
narrative has a natural advantage in dissemination; it can gather like-minded
people. "I also think the
crypto world is full of scammers, yes, they fleece
you. Luckily, I didn't get involved." Everyone comforts and confirms each other in the comments section, forming an alliance of the weak. This alliance relies on a common enemy, not a common goal. Second case. When I first launched paid content, some trolls clamored about "harvesting." I
observed this closely. These people genuinely wanted my content; they found it valuable. Otherwise, they would have simply unfollowed, and there wouldn't have been such a strong reaction. Some had even been following for a long time, perhaps watching every episode. But they didn't want to pay,
or they couldn't afford to. This was their situation. However, admitting this is tantamount to admitting that while I believe this content has value, I
don't have it, or I'm unwilling to exchange it for something of
equal value. This sounds
awkward because it exposes either financial constraints or an unwillingness to reciprocate with respect for
value. So, the slave mentality kicks in again, redefining the issue: "It's not that I can't
afford it or am
unwilling to pay; I'm refusing to be deprived. You're not providing a service; you're harvesting. My refusal isn't a sign of my inadequacy, but rather an awakening." It's a shift in identity, a moral transformation. They've gone from someone unwilling to pay to a fighter refusing to be oppressed. All their problems are packaged as a sense of justice. The pink line is the same. Prison A
follows the same logic. They can neither change the
country
nor risk the costs and uncertain returns of changing their nationality. So, this rhetoric... This perfectly protects their fragile self-esteem. East rises, west falls, winning is all that matters. Especially those misogynistic remarks, those spreading rumors about women, and those who join in the clamor about things like "Three
Tongs and One Da" (referring to companies like STO Express, YTO Express, ZTO Express, and Yunda Express). Those who have been ignored, rejected, and treated like air by women since childhood, their dignity and desires simultaneously bankrupted,
can only
rely on spreading rumors
to fantasize, "I'm not good enough for you, you're unclean." That feeling of being educated like Dong Zhimin is almost overflowing the screen.
This typical psychological
protection mechanism is what Nietzsche called the deepest poison of slave morality. It doesn't make you feel bad, it makes you feel good, while keeping you stuck in the same place forever because it shuts down all the things that require a price to pay. Changing
the path, returning to my initial framework,
this thing is like a background virus running at the operating system level. It does
n't show on the desktop; you can't perceive it, but it continuously consumes your system resources, making all your applications run with the virus. The worse the hardware, the more active and harder this virus is to remove,
because
removing it itself requires mental effort, and mental effort is precisely what you lack most. Finally, there's an even deeper layer. There's a research direction now called embodied cognition, and
in the AI ​​field, it's called physical AI, studying the same thing: why, no matter how many parameters are piled up
in a large model... No matter how powerful the computing power, without a body, there is
no true intelligence. This question sounds like an AI issue,
but it actually speaks to a more fundamental thing:
cognition is not a calculation done independently by the brain. Cognition is a loop formed by the constant interaction between the brain, body, and the real world. In this loop, the
body is the terminal receiving feedback from the real world. The resistance and feedback from the real world constantly correct the model in your brain. Without this loop, the model you build in your brain has not been
calibrated by the real world. It may be
very self-consistent and very smooth, but there is a gap between it and the real world. This is why AI, without a body, cannot truly understand what it feels like to be hot, tired, or about to collapse. It's not because it does
n't have these words, but because the meaning of these concepts grows from bodily experience, not from language.
The same is true for humans. Where is the cognition embedded in the body of someone who is physically weak and whose life is highly outsourced? It's embedded in other people's narratives, embedded in screens, embedded in all kinds of second-hand information. Their understanding of the world is all filtered and processed by others, all a patchwork of language and
concepts. Without their own body directly contacting the real world, such a person can be very knowledgeable. He can quote extensively and discuss various frameworks and theories, but the longer you talk to him, the more you'll sense his superficiality, his detachment from reality. This is because there's a glass wall between his
understanding and the real world. He thinks he's seen through it, but he's only seeing a reflection in the glass. And
without feedback from the real world, his understanding cannot be corrected by the truth. A person who acts in the
real world, if they make a mistake, they make a mistake; events will tell them; they will feel the pain; they will correct themselves. A person whose understanding is only embedded in narratives, if they make a mistake, the
narrative
can explain it; the narrative can incorporate the mistake into their existing framework, and
they will
never correct themselves. This is the material basis for physical weakness leading to mental weakness, then to using
intelligence to justify weakness, and finally to slavery morality. Having said so much
negative, let me share a recent case that impressed me deeply. A young man who hasn't yet succeeded, but whose hardware quality is immediately apparent, received an email a few days ago from a programmer born
in the 2000s. It was a very long letter. He said he was deeply moved after seeing a channel and wanted to
join a private board,
but he couldn't afford it at the moment, so he proposed a solution. He was willing to be a free assistant, doing everything from editing videos and replying to comments to organizing
materials, exchanging his labor for a ticket to the event. He
said he was currently unemployed and could join anytime, telling me not to feel pressured. Although I've been very busy these past
few days, I read his letter and replied to him
very carefully, saying everything I could think of to offer guidance. It wasn't because of his many skills or how many nice words he uttered,
but because every sentence in that letter revealed the
hardware quality of his machine. If you break it down, he saw someone he considered valuable; he recognized this as an opportunity. This is the first step. Many people can't even take this step. They see the
opportunity,
but after reading it, they close the page and continue watching videos. He realized he didn't
have enough resources and couldn't afford the annual fee—a real obstacle. Many people stop
here, thinking it's hopeless, that the conditions aren't right, and then leave. He didn't leave. He sat
down and thought about what I could offer. He took stock of his assets and found that he had time, skills, and execution ability. Then he designed a
value exchange plan. He even anticipated my possible concerns—whether I would feel like I was taking advantage of him, or whether I would feel
awkward. He proactively addressed these concerns, asking me not to feel embarrassed. Throughout the entire process, he didn't complain once about how expensive the annual fee was. You should lower the price. Not a single word is waiting for others to
lower the bar, not a single word is demanding anything; every word is offering. This is the
prototype of hostility. Start with what I have, not what I deserve. I replied that his action impressed me, but I don't need manpower right now, and that in the future, when faced with similar situations, he should focus on showcasing his skills and achievements. This way, the other party will easily remember him. I suggested he find a profitable online business, thoroughly research every detail, and then strive to imitate it, even if he only achieves 10%. This would be more meaningful for him than joining my private board. Then I talked to
my wife about this for a long time because I have two
relatives who are about the same age as him, and even better off, but their situations are completely different. One cousin studied computer science. When he was in college, I was making waves in the cryptocurrency world.
I encouraged him to learn Bitcoin, Ethereum, smart contracts, wallets, and exchange technology. I knew how scarce and lucrative technical talent was in the cryptocurrency world. I even found him a top-tier tech expert as a mentor so he could learn from him and ask questions
whenever he didn't understand. The
mentor later told me that after one conversation, nothing came of it. The other
cousin stayed home after graduating from university. During
his senior year... I introduced
him to an internship at an investment consulting firm. I knew about the company; the founder had only graduated from university three years prior and discovered the opportunity to sell courses via short videos. He figured out all the details, assembled a team, raised funds from netizens he met
on Xueqiu (a Chinese investment platform), and migrated the Douyin (TikTok)
strategies he learned to WeChat Video Accounts. Within a year, they had generated tens of millions in
revenue. One of the team
partners was a young woman from
an ordinary university who single-handedly accounted for more than half of the company's performance. At 25, her income far surpassed that of public fund managers who had graduated from prestigious universities and worked for over a decade. I sent my cousin there for an internship, thinking it was the best environment for
him to see real peers, how high achievers work, and experience that atmosphere and pace. After a while, he told me he wanted to go abroad and quit his job to prepare for the IELTS exam. He
studied at home, but his efforts were inconsistent, and he failed the exam. Then, Canadian policy changed, and his post-graduation work permit was no longer available. He then said he wanted to switch to French. After studying for more than half a year, one day he suddenly asked me, "What do you think of Japan?"
I immediately understood: French was
no longer an option. He asked about Japan because French was too difficult, and he couldn't handle the discomfort. He was looking for another way out. I told him, "You should take the civil service exam. Studying abroad and immigrating isn't for you." Look at this complete stranger, emailing me, going to great lengths
to create opportunities, pooling their limited resources, and trying to get into circles they deem valuable. Two relatives, with resources right in front of them, never even bother to
ask me.
I've presented them with
mentors and opportunities, yet they still let them slip away.
This difference isn't about intelligence or luck; it's about the hardware—whether the machine continues operating or shuts down
automatically when faced with resistance or discomfort. My wife and I talked about this for a long time, pondering this question. We're the same age, from the same era, so why is there such a huge gap between people? What are those two cousins ​​lacking, and how did they lose it? How can we learn from their mistakes to educate our own children? I suspect their fundamental problem is precisely because they were
never forced to rely on their circumstances. They had support at home, and every
time they encountered resistance, they had a way out. The cost of giving up wasn't painful enough. French is too difficult? They could go to Japan. Japan isn't suitable? They could
think about it again. At worst, they could stay home. With food and drink readily available and no one forcing you, in such an environment, there's never a chance for the "
hardware" (i.e., the ability to develop and refine one's skills) to be forged. This is because what's needed to forge hardware is precisely what's been protected: real resistance, real costs, and the real feeling of "I must do this." The easier something is to obtain, the less likely it is to
activate the "hardware." How long did Abdullah Rahman struggle in that icy river before his "hardware" could contain the decision to swim to the other side? Next, I
'll talk about something many people might relate to: immigration. I know quite a few people who have been talking about immigrating for years, and they genuinely mean it. But they haven't moved. If you ask them why, they'll give you all sorts of reasons: "At this age, I
can't learn the language anymore; I'll have to shovel snow and mow the lawn myself—it's too hard; I won't be used to the food—there aren't many good snacks or takeout options;
I'll be unfamiliar with the place, and building a social circle from scratch will be too difficult." These are all real feelings; these
discomforts are real. But have you noticed that as time goes by, these reasons begin to evolve, to upgrade, becoming more profound, more like a well-thought-out strategic judgment? Finally, you'll hear the saying: "The smartest strategy..." The truth is, it's about making money in countries with inflation
and spending it in countries with deflation. Before, it was said that China's economy was developing rapidly, offering many opportunities to make money. Now that
the economy is struggling, it's become that China has a low cost of
living and plenty of opportunities for food,
drink, and entertainment.
From a financial perspective,
this seems like the optimal solution. Listen to how clearly and logically this
argument sounds—it
seems like a wise decision.
But think back:
many people initially decided to emigrate. Was it solely because of
deflation?
No. What
ultimately stopped them was the fatigue of learning a language, the imagined hardship of shoveling snow and mowing the
lawn, the anticipated discomfort
in an unfamiliar environment, and the real fear signals on a physical level. This is the first layer—the
body sends out signals first.
Then rationality is commanded and begins to serve this signal, finding increasingly convincing reasons for not
wanting to move, until it develops into the seemingly shrewd framework of making money in countries with inflation and spending it in countries with deflation. Slave morality completes the final packaging, transforming my physical discomfort into in-depth financial planning. Now I want to say something very important.
Listen carefully: if it happened again, like in 1949, like the Great River and the Great Sea, like Saigon falling
again and fleeing to the raging sea... If history were to present another moment of personal and familial destiny, these
people standing on that ship would feel extreme exhaustion, confusion, and fear. That unfamiliar place would instill a deep unease in them. Then, the program in their minds would kick in: perhaps the situation isn't so bad; perhaps there's a turning point; perhaps staying
would offer a
chance. Is such a high price of leaving one's homeland worth it, especially when earning money
in a country with inflation and spending it in a country with deflation? This theory would be very complete and very convincing because
it's meticulously constructed by their own intelligence. Then they didn't board the ship. Many who stayed in 1949 weren't truly
without a chance to leave; their bodies couldn't withstand the strain at the last moment. Then, reason helped them find the
reason to stay—the same mechanism as the prince who turned back halfway through the river. History's sieve works like this; it doesn't sift through intelligence, it sifts through whose body can withstand the discomfort and not turn back. The Israelites, after leaving Egypt, constantly resented Moses in the wilderness, longing for the Egyptian meat pots. There is nothing new under the sun. Okay, here's my conclusion, and I'll tell you what to do. Mental fortitude is paramount. It's not just one of the most important
things, but the foundation upon which everything else is built. Without this foundation, everything built upon it is a precarious structure. Without strong
mental fortitude, knowledge is used to justify cowardice, and wealth becomes a tool for accelerating decline. How many
cases of sudden wealth leading to utter ruin have you seen? Connections and
resources are wasted in the "not yet conditions are right" mentality. With strong
mental fortitude, even if you have nothing for the time being,
resources will come naturally. This is because this "machine" transforms every encounter, whether favorable or unfavorable, into fuel.
As the saying goes, "Heaven's movement is ever vigorous; so should
a gentleman constantly strive for
self-improvement." A person with good "
hardware"
and a strong
system is inherently in motion—moving forward, overcoming obstacles, and seizing opportunities. A person with poor "hardware" and a weak
system is inherently in a state of stillness—waiting, seeking reasons not to move. Continuous self-improvement is our top priority, and for the next generation, it's the only thing worth cultivating first. The first thing is to
strengthen the body,
establishing neural circuits that recognize discomfort as not stopping. Sports like football and rugby involve contact with others. Mountaineering and wilderness survival—
sports that confront nature; long-distance running and cycling—sports that confront oneself. These train
not only your physical fitness, but also the protocol your body and brain have. Discomfort is not a signal to stop. A regular cyclist, halfway through a ride, feels tired and hot, and his knees hurt. His body tells him it's uncomfortable, but his
brain knows that discomfort is not the end, but a process. Endure this, and there will be even more beautiful scenery ahead. Once this protocol is established in your body, it will play a role in every key moment in your life. When you encounter a bottleneck in your business,
it's uncomfortable,
but discomfort is part of the
process. When your career is at a
low point, you're tired,
but tiredness is not a reason to stop. When you immigrate to a new
place,
everything is unfamiliar,
and discomfort is normal.
This is why sports have been considered a core part of education in almost
all great civilizations—
not just for fitness,
not just for teamwork. It's because it's a resistance training system with precisely
controlled dosage.
You can't run anymore,
but you won't die. You grit your teeth and cross the finish line, and
your hardware has been upgraded.
Your body and brain have remembered that discomfort is not a signal to stop, but a signal to
continue.
Once this program is written into
you, it will save your life at some key moment in your life. The
second thing:
keep your hands connected to the real world.
Here's a small but important example: learning to cook isn't about
becoming a master chef, but about developing an active, not dependent, relationship with food. Someone who can cook themselves a good meal anywhere knows they can thrive in any unfamiliar place, independent of their familiar food ecosystem. On a deeper level, mental dependence begins with physical dependence. If you consistently rely on external systems for your basic needs like
food, clothing, shelter, and transportation, your brain subconsciously learns that your needs must be met
externally. This pattern permeates every aspect of your life, including how you handle opportunities and react to obstacles. This is the material basis of a slave mentality—it doesn't start
mentally, it starts physically. The third point is building
muscle memory for execution. Regarding entrepreneurship and action,
I want to emphasize that creating
this channel and producing content weekly is building the neural circuitry for execution. Someone who writes content daily, when they
see a new topic, their hands are already moving; they do
n't need to hesitate or wait. They have a feeling of being ready because their
body has memorized the
next steps. Someone who
writes code daily, when they see a product opportunity, their first reaction isn't whether it's feasible, but how to do it. Because his body has the confidence to execute. Conversely, someone who does nothing but think in their head and waits until they're fully prepared, when the opportunity actually arrives, there's a huge gap between their consciousness and their actions. This gap consumes all their willpower, and in the end, nothing is started, and the opportunity slips away. The
essence of entrepreneurship isn't daring to think, it's daring to act. It's about starting even
when not fully prepared. This daring to act isn't something suddenly sparked at a crucial moment; it's something cultivated little by little over time. Here, I also want to mention something many people haven't thought through: a deep-seated misunderstanding of aristocratic life
among slaves. What does
aristocratic life look like in the slaves' imagination? Being waited on hand and foot, not having to lift a finger, doing nothing all day, and taking pride in not needing to
work. But
this is a completely misguided imitation. Aristotle once said that the purpose of having slaves do repetitive physical labor is to earn leisure for themselves. What is this leisure for? Philosophical thinking, political participation, military training, artistic creation, civic life. The ancient Romans distinguished between daily
routine labor and meaningful leisure labor. Roman nobles saved
daily routine
labor... It
's about meaningful leisure work: studying law, writing, debating, governing, and waging war. So the true logic of the
aristocracy is to liberate oneself from lowly labor to
do
higher-level work, not to be liberated from labor and then do nothing. It's about being liberated from shoveling manure to fight, from doing odd jobs to write books, and from using the time saved from takeout to create content
and output truly valuable things. But what do many slaves do with the time saved from takeout? They watch short videos, play mahjong, consume, and flaunt their food and sex.
Because they don't have the concept that being
liberated is for
doing something higher. Their template is the lords in movies and
TV shows—
consumption and laziness. They construct a slave version of freedom with the imagination of slaves, a
slave's dream paradise—a place where nothing needs to be done. A strong person's dream paradise—a place where they can freely do awesome things. I'll ask you a question you don't need to answer; you know the answer yourself. What have you done with the time you save from takeout? The answer to this question will
silently determine,
without you even realizing it, whether you become an
aristocrat or a higher-level
slave. I've started my own business, navigated society, and had a lot of contact with all sorts of people. I also have children. I started seriously thinking about something: how can I raise a child to be a resilient and strong individual, instead of a useless person who, even with abundant resources, can't be
moved by relatives? You can give a child money, but money will run out. You can give them the best education, but knowledge will become outdated, and diplomas will lose value. You can give them connections and networks, but
you can't support them for life. The only thing that won't depreciate after being given is the quality of their operating system. Once this is established, they can grow
naturally wherever they go and whatever they
face. If they don't have this, no matter how much you give them, it's just a
waste, not an accumulation, because their system can't handle it. But how do you cultivate this? Here's a counterintuitive answer:
you can't directly equip a child with powerful hardware;
you can only manage the amount of resistance you give them. Too little resistance will ruin the
hardware. Look at how many children from wealthy families are lazy and give up at the slightest discomfort. This isn't their innate problem; it's that their
upbringing shields them from all the resistance they should be able to withstand. Too much resistance without any support is also bad; it's
childhood trauma that will cause the system to collapse, leading to another extreme. The best balance is having enough resistance to force them to exert effort, but with you by their side, they know they won't truly fail. He gritted his teeth and persevered. His "hardware" (physical attributes) upgraded. He gained a new understanding of himself: "I can do it. I
can handle it." Let's wrap things up for today. We can use a computer to describe a person: the
body
is the hardware, mental strength is the operating system, knowledge and skills are the applications, and success, failure, and happiness in life are the outputs of those applications. The cold reality of
this framework is that it reveals a truth many are unwilling to face: most people's problem isn't a lack of applications,
but rather that their hardware is too weak, their system too poor. And when the system is running in a state of collapse, intelligence is hijacked to
invent increasingly sophisticated reasons to serve weakness, inaction, and remaining stagnant. Slave morality is the system's protective mechanism, making you feel good and keeping you perpetually stuck in the same place. A
strong body isn't something you do after you've accomplished everything; it's not a side job. It's the foundation of everything, the prerequisite for the
operating system to function.
History will constantly push you to that riverbank. Sometimes it's an investment window, sometimes an opportunity to immigrate, sometimes something you must start immediately, sometimes a true life-or-death situation. Each time is the same test. Whether you swim across or not doesn't depend on whether you know what's on the
other side, or how many grand principles you possess. It doesn't depend on how sophisticated your analytical framework is, but on how
strong your body and mind are so that you don't turn back halfway through the swim. That concludes
this video.
May we continue to climb higher and
swim to the other side of every river.