Hello everyone, this is Brain Master.
Today we continue the Taleb series,
discussing the books *Antifragile* and *Asymmetric Risk*.
But before diving into the specifics,
I'd like to provide a broader context: two drastically different paths in the
critique of modernity.
This isn't a new issue;
since the birth of modernity,
reflection and critique have never ceased.
However, one phenomenon is noteworthy:
in current mainstream academic discourse and cultural discussions,
almost all critiques of modernity you hear
come from the left.
From Marx's critique of capitalism to the
Frankfurt School of the 20th century,
postmodernism, cultural studies, and critical theory—
these theories, while each with their own emphasis, share
a common logical starting point: the
problem with modernity is its lack of radicalism, and the
solution is more radical change.
But here lies a profound paradox: when these critics point to the alienation of
capitalism and the
chaos of the market,
they often place their hopes on a rationally planned social form. The most radical experiment in
rational planning in the 20th century—
the Soviet Union's centrally planned economy—was precisely one of the most extreme manifestations of modernity.
It attempted to reconstruct the entire society using science and reason, but the result was systemic disaster. This raises a question... Is there
another critique of modernity? Not that modernity isn't radical enough, but that it's too arrogant; not that it demands more planning,
but that it acknowledges the fundamental limitations of planning; not that it seeks to deconstruct tradition,
but that it
restores the wisdom destroyed by modernity. The answer is yes, and it has a complete intellectual lineage. In the following content, I will do three things: First, I will outline this intellectual tradition obscured by mainstream discourse, allowing you to see clearly Taleb's position in an intellectual movement that has lasted for two
and a half centuries.
Second, using
this framework, I will dissect several core problems created by modernity, helping you understand the source of vulnerability. Finally, I will discuss the strategies individuals can adopt based on this understanding. So let's begin this intellectual journey. Our story begins in 1789, at the moment known as the "triumph of
reason." On July 14, 1789, the people of Paris stormed the Bastille. This event sparked jubilation among intellectuals throughout Europe. The bastions of the old regime had been overthrown; the age of reason had finally arrived. Humanity could redesign society according to the principles of reason. But one voice
said,
"Wait, this could be a disaster." Edmund Burke, British Whig politician and philosopher,
November 1790 Just over a year after the outbreak of the French Revolution, he published *Reflections on the
French Revolution*.
This book was fiercely attacked by radicals at the time, but later history proved his predictions
accurate. Burke's core arguments can be summarized in three levels. First, tradition is not superstition, but the crystallization of the wisdom of generations. Those seemingly irrational institutions, customs, and traditions have been formed in the long course of historical
evolution. Their survival
to this day
demonstrates their adaptability. You may examine them with contemporary rational standards, find them illogical, and then overthrow them to establish new rational institutions. But the problem is that your rationality is limited; you only see the surface logic of things. The wisdom inherent in
tradition is often
implicit, situational, and difficult to articulate. Burke gave the example of the English common law system. This legal system was not designed by a single legislator, but accumulated case by case. On the surface, it
appears chaotic, contradictory, and lacking in systematicity. But it is precisely this chaos that allows it to be
applicable to various specific situations and to be fine-tuned while maintaining continuity. In contrast, the French Revolution attempted to start from scratch
and
establish a completely new legal system based on rational principles. The result? Frequent constitutional changes, constant legal alterations,
and the collapse of social order. Secondly,
society is an organism,
not a machine. A mechanistic view of society prevailed during the Enlightenment, viewing society as a clock, composed of
various parts that could be disassembled and reassembled according to a blueprint. Burke argued this was a fundamental error. Society is
more like a large tree,
slowly growing over generations and centuries. It has unseen roots, complex nutrient cycles, and countless delicate balances. You can prune branches and graft new shoots, but you cannot uproot it and expect to replant it. The French Revolution's mistake was treating society as a machine. They thought they could reassemble French society according to a
rational blueprint of liberty, equality, and fraternity.
The result? The Reign of Terror, the Jacobin dictatorship, Napoleon's military dictatorship, and years of war in Europe. Thirdly,
gradual reform is superior to radical revolution.
Burke did not oppose reform; in fact, he supported American independence and internal reforms in Britain. However, he advocated a conservative reform—gradual and prudent adjustments based on respect for tradition. British history is a prime example of this gradual reform, from the Magna Carta to the Glorious Revolution, from the expansion of parliamentary power to the gradual popularization of suffrage.
Each step was an adjustment within the existing framework, preserving what was good. Eliminating the bad is a
slow process, potentially
taking generations,
but it's relatively safe and won't lead to the overall collapse of society. The French approach is radical: overthrowing everything
and starting from scratch.
This process is fast and seems satisfying, but it's extremely dangerous because you're destroying not only bad institutions but also unseen but crucial social connections, customs, and trust.
Burke famously said that society is a partnership—not just between the living, but between the living, the dead, and the unborn. What does this mean? When undertaking social change, you can't only consider the demands of the living; you must also
respect the legacy left by predecessors—those time-tested institutions and wisdom. You must also be responsible for future generations; you can't deprive them of their choices for the sake of present rational ideals.
This is the starting point of conservatism. It's important to emphasize that conservatism here is
not about clinging to the old ways or rejecting all change, but about preserving what has stood the test of time. In Taleb's
later terminology, it's the Lindy effect: the longer something exists, the longer it's expected to continue existing. Burke
tells us that tradition has value, but he didn't delve into the underlying epistemological mechanisms: why tradition contains wisdom, and why rational planning fails. Hayek, an Austrian economist and 1974 Nobel laureate in economics, systematically answered this question in the 20th century. His core contribution to the critique of modernity is a seemingly simple yet profoundly influential insight: the problem of knowledge. In 1945, Hayek published a paper, "The Application of Knowledge in Society," a work of less than 20 pages that fundamentally changed our understanding of planned economies. He posed the question:
Why is central planning impossible? Note that it's not about
difficulty or inefficiency, but about impossibility. This is a fundamental epistemological obstacle. Traditional critics of socialism would say that planned economies fail because of bureaucratic corruption, insufficient incentives, and abuse of power.
Hayek argued that even if all these problems were solved, even if you had a group of completely honest and diligent planners, planned economies would still fail. Why? Because knowledge is dispersed. Countless pieces of knowledge
exist in the world,
but this knowledge is not concentrated in one place, not held by a single brain or computer. It is dispersed in everyone's mind, and most of it is context-
specific and tacit. Let me
give you an example: a farmer in a mountain village in Yunnan who has been growing tea for 30 years. What does he know? He knows the soil characteristics of this hillside, and he knows which plots of land are suitable for which varieties. Knowing there's been more rain this year, how to adjust the harvest time, knowing which month's tea is of the best quality—this knowledge is specific, accumulated from 30 years of experience. Can you write this knowledge into a
manual? You
can, but you can never fully convey it because it involves too many subtle judgments, too many unspoken secrets.
This is what Michael Polanyi calls tacit knowledge—that is, we know far more than we can articulate. Now the question arises: how can an
agricultural bureaucrat sitting in Beijing grasp the
tea-growing knowledge of a certain mountain village in Yunnan?
Impossible. But if he needs to formulate a national agricultural plan, he must make decisions. What can he do? He can only simplify, using statistical data, averages, and standardized indicators. Yunnan Province has 1 million mu of tea plantations, with an estimated yield of 100,000 tons. This
figure seems scientific, but in reality, it erases all local differences and all contextual knowledge. The result? The plan is out of touch with reality, resource allocation is inefficient, and ultimately the entire system malfunctions. So how does the market solve this problem? The answer is the price mechanism. Price is a signal system; it compresses scattered knowledge into a number. Suppose a certain
area in Yunnan experiences
drought this year, resulting in reduced
tea production. This information doesn't need to be reported to Beijing or analyzed by experts; it will immediately be reflected in tea prices. Prices rise, and tea merchants will adjust their purchasing plans. Consumers will reduce their purchases or seek alternatives; farmers who grow other crops will consider switching to tea. The entire adjustment process requires no central planning; everyone simply needs to make decisions based on price signals that suit their own circumstances.
This is what Hayek called spontaneous order—the result of human action, but not a product of human design.
Markets are spontaneous orders; no one designed them, yet they function well. Languages ​​are spontaneous orders; no one designed English or Chinese, yet
they have evolved complex grammars and rich expressive capabilities. Common law is a spontaneous order; cases accumulate to form a legal system. These spontaneous orders share a common characteristic: they can utilize dispersed
knowledge, adapt to changing circumstances, and achieve coordination without central control. In contrast, rationally designed orders, such as planned economies, Esperanto, and codified laws, often function poorly because they cannot utilize local knowledge or adapt to complex situations. In his 1973 book, *Law, Legislation, and Liberty*, Hayek proposed a key concept:
constructive rationalism. This is the core ailment of modernity. What is constructive rationalism?
It is the belief that human reason can design everything and construct society from scratch. The philosophical origins of
this thought can be traced back to Descartes, who said, "I think, therefore I am." His method began with questioning everything, retaining only the certain, and then rationally reconstructing the knowledge system. This method achieved great success
in the natural sciences and mathematics. However, the problem is that
people
apply the same method to the social sphere. The leaders of the French Revolution said that the old regime was irrational and that we should rebuild society using rational principles. The Soviet Bolsheviks
said that capitalism was chaotic and that we should plan the economy scientifically. Hayek called this kind of thinking fatal arrogance. You think you know a lot, but in reality you know very little. You think you can
design society, but in reality you ca
n't even design a village. Why? Because the knowledge upon which social order depends far exceeds what any individual, organization, or even any era can grasp.
Those spontaneously evolved institutions, customs, and rules contain the trial-and-error experience of several generations over hundreds of years.
You use
rational standards to examine them, find them unreasonable, and then try to replace them with a better design. But your "
better" is often based on simplifying complexity and ignoring tacit knowledge. As
Burke predicted, those rationally designed social experiments often end in disaster. Hayek theoretically demonstrated the impossibility of central planning, but one question remains unresolved: what is the
specific mechanism of failure? How did those
ambitious
social reform projects gradually turn into disasters? This question was systematically answered by Yale University politician
James Scott in his 1998 book, *The State Perspective: Why Projects Seeking to Improve the Human Condition Fail*. Scott's work can be seen as an autopsy report on the social engineering disasters of the 20th century. He studied a series of
cases, including German scientific forestry, Soviet collective farms, the village of Ugama in Tanzania, and Brasilia, the new capital of Brazil, attempting to find
common patterns of failure. Scott first defined an ideology he called High Modernism, a belief system that reached its peak in the first half of the 20th century. Its core tenets were: first, science and technology could solve all social problems; second, rational planning was superior to
tradition and custom; third,
society could be
designed like a machine; fourth, standardization, simplification, and measurability were signs of progress; and finally, experts knew better than ordinary people what was beneficial to
society. This ideology
transcended left and right. The Soviet planned economy was High Modernism; the American urban redevelopment movement was High Modernism; Le Corbusier's Radiant City design was High Modernism; and Robert Moses's transformation of New York City was also High Modernism. The allure of modernism lies in its promise to end chaos and disorder with
reason and science, creating a
better world. The technological advancements of the 20th century—electricity, steel, concrete, automobiles—seemed to prove this promise achievable.
Scott's second
key concept is readability. For a state to manage society, it needs to understand it. However, traditional societies were
unreadable. Village layouts were chaotic, landholdings were irregular, surnames were inconsistent, and units of measurement varied from place to place. This posed
a problem for the state: how to collect taxes, how to conscript soldiers, how to control
population movement. Thus, modern states initiated a series of readability projects: standardizing surnames (previously many only had given names), standardizing units of measurement, land surveying and registration, censuses and household registration systems, and grid-based urban planning. On the surface, these were all advancements; they indeed improved administrative efficiency. However, the problem is that in the pursuit of readability, those unreadable but crucial elements were often
destroyed. Let me give you a
concrete example:
scientific forestry in Germany. At the end of the 18th century, Prussian forestry officials faced the problem of how to increase timber production. What were traditional German forests like?
A mixture of various trees: oak, beech, maple, spruce, varying in height and age. The understory
also contained
shrubs and herbaceous plants. For forestry officials, this type of forest was unreadable; they couldn't accurately calculate timber reserves, predict future yields, or manage them effectively. So they invented scientific forestry. First, they cleared the existing mixed forests,
then planted a single tree species, usually spruce, planted in neat rows with uniform spacing, and harvested simultaneously. The result was a forest that became a timber factory, appearing from the air
as orderly as an army formation. Forestry
officials could now accurately
calculate how many trees were per hectare and how many cubic meters of timber could be harvested in 10 years. The first generation was a huge success; timber production increased dramatically, and
Prussian forestry science became
a model for all of Europe. The second
generation? Disaster! Trees began to die off in large numbers, pests and diseases spread, and the soil degraded. By the second harvest cycle, yields had plummeted. What happened? Those chaotic traditional forests had complex ecosystems. Different tree species were interdependent; understory plants protected the soil; dead branches and leaves provided nutrients; and birds controlled pests. This was a balanced system that had evolved over thousands of years.
Monoculture
plantations destroyed this system. Without diversity, pests and diseases spread easily; without understory vegetation,
soil erosion occurred; and
without dead branches and leaves… Nutrient cycling is disrupted. The first generation relies on the reserves accumulated by the original forest. The second generation depletes these reserves, leading to system collapse. This is the readability trap. To make forests easier to manage and calculate, you simplify their complexity. But it is precisely this complexity that maintains the health of the forest. Let's look at a
larger-scale case: the Soviet collective farms. In 1929, Stalin launched a comprehensive collectivization movement. The logic was simple: small-scale farming was inefficient, fragmented, and wasteful of resources. If land were centralized, mechanized
farming, and scientific management, yields would
certainly increase significantly.
Experts in Moscow developed detailed plans. Each collective farm had standards for what to plant, how much fertilizer to use, and when to sow and harvest. However, there was a problem: these standards were based on averages. In reality, every piece of land
is unique. What do
farmers in a Ukrainian village know? They know that the land north of the village has poor drainage and is prone to waterlogging in spring, making it unsuitable for
wheat. They know that the soil on the eastern slope is poor but suitable for buckwheat.
They know that this year's rainfall is heavy, requiring a few days' delay in
sowing, otherwise the seeds will rot in the ground. This knowledge is what Hayek called local knowledge, and Scott called Metis, or practical
wisdom. However, after collectivization, this knowledge was neglected. Moscow's directive was to plant wheat, so wheat was planted regardless of the land's suitability. The directive was to sow on March 15th, so March
15th was sowed, regardless of the year's
weather conditions. Farmers knew this would lead to failure, but they had no decision-making power, and even if they objected, they were suppressed as
wealthy
peasants. As a result, the Ukrainian famine of 1932-1933 saw millions starve to death in Europe's breadbasket.
This was not a natural disaster, but a
man-made, systemic catastrophe—the inevitable consequence of expert knowledge attempting to replace practical wisdom. Scott introduces two ancient Greek concepts in his book, which form the core of his analytical framework: one is Techne,
technical knowledge—knowledge that can be coded, taught, and standardized, such as knowledge in agricultural textbooks, soil pH, nitrogen, phosphorus, and potassium ratios, and pest and disease control plans. The other is Metis, practical wisdom—situational, experiential,
and ineffable knowledge, such as an old farmer's judgment in a specific situation: whether to water more this year, or whether this land is suitable for planting corn.
A core assumption of modernity is that Techne can replace Metis; as long as we scientize and standardize knowledge, we no longer need those empiricist elements. Scott argues that this is a fundamental mistake. It's not that Techne is unimportant, but rather that it cannot replace Metis. An agricultural
PhD might know all the theories of soil science, but if he hasn't actually farmed, his knowledge is
abstract.
A farmer who has farmed for 30 years, while not understanding chemical equations, possesses the wisdom to handle specific situations. The best scenario is a combination of both: Techne provides general principles, while Metis allows for flexible
application in specific contexts. The worst scenario is using Techne to suppress Metis, with experts sitting
in offices directing thousands of specific situations using standardized procedures.
Scott summarizes four necessary conditions for the failure of high-modernism projects: First, administrative order and readability—the state needs to simplify complex social realities; second, a high-modernist ideology—believing that scientific planning is superior to traditional experience;
third, an authoritarian state—having the power and will to implement radical change; and finally, a lack of checks and balances—no civil
society or local power to resist. Disaster occurs when all four conditions are present. If any one is missing, the project may only be inefficient, not a major catastrophe. For example, urban redevelopment in the United States also has high-modernist characteristics,
but
because of a relatively active civil society, the degree of destruction is limited. In contrast, authoritarian states like the Soviet Union and Tanzania... The
damage caused by the high
modernist ideology was far greater. Now let's shift our focus from forests and farmlands to cities. In 1961, a housewife with no urban planning degree or architectural background
published a book that revolutionized the entire urban planning industry. Her name was Jane Jacobs, and the book was *The Death and Life of Great American Cities*. Jacobs lived in Greenwich Village, New York, a typical chaotic neighborhood where old and new buildings were mixed together, the streets were narrow and winding, and small shops, cafes, and bars lined the ground floors of residential buildings. According to the
prevailing urban planning theories at
the time, such neighborhoods were slums and should be demolished to make way for
modern residential areas. Robert Moses, the urban czar of New York, was preparing to do just that. He planned to build a highway through Greenwich Village, cutting the neighborhood in half.
Jacobs organized residents to protest and ultimately stopped the project. But more importantly, during the protest, she began to ponder a question: why were the neighborhoods that experts thought should be
demolished the most vibrant and livable? Her answer challenged the theoretical foundation of the
entire modern urban planning system. Through observing Greenwich Village, Jacobs summarized four elements. The first was mixed-use: residential, commercial, and
office spaces were mixed together. Why was this important? Mixed-use development means the streets are active all day. Commuters pass by in the morning, people eat lunch nearby, delivery trucks come and go in the afternoon, people buy groceries and go to bars in the evening, and small restaurants are still open late at night. With people, there are eyes on the street – shop owners, residents, and passersby form an informal monitoring network, more effective than any police patrol.
The second is short blocks. Long blocks and wide roads may seem grand, but they
reduce people's choices; you're limited to fixed routes, and chance encounters are fewer. Short
blocks mean you can walk down one street or turn into another alley, encountering different people and discovering different shops each time. This randomness is the source of urban vitality. The third is a mix of old and new buildings. Why not
all new
buildings? Because new buildings have high rents, only affordable for large corporations and chains. Old buildings are cheaper, affordable for small
shops, entrepreneurs, and artists. A mix of old and new buildings means rent diversity, allowing people from different income levels to coexist, and creating ecological diversity within the neighborhood. The fourth is high density. This is the most counterintuitive. Traditional
planning theory
equates high density with overcrowding, dirt, and unhealthiness, so density should be reduced to make people comfortable.
Jacobs was wrong. Moderate high density is a prerequisite for urban vitality. Too few people make the
streets deserted; too many people exceed the infrastructure's capacity, which certainly causes problems. However, in the middle ground, density means enough customers to support various
small shops, enough neighbors to form communities, and enough street life. Robert Moses's
modern urban planning is exactly the opposite: functional zoning, residential areas for living, commercial areas for commerce, office areas for offices, wide boulevards to reduce corners,
demolishing and rebuilding old
buildings, constructing modern high-rise apartments, reducing density to allow the city
to breathe. Sounds rational, right? But what happened? Take the Pruitt Igor Apartments as an example. This public housing project in St. Louis, built in the 1950s, was designed by a famous architect and reflected the most advanced
planning concepts of the time. High-rise buildings allowed more open space for
greenery. Functional zoning, residential areas away from commercial areas, wide spacing for good lighting, modern facilities, elevators, heating, and indoor toilets—it won architectural awards after completion. Ten years later, it became a high-crime area. Elevators broke down and no one repaired them; the hallways reeked of
urine; drug trafficking was openly conducted; residents moved out en masse. Completed in 1972, less than 20 years later… In 2000, the government decided to demolish it. Why did it fail? Because the functional zoning left the streets empty most of the time.
People who worked during the day went to other areas, leaving only the elderly
and children. At night, the shops were closed, and without people, the streets lacked
vigilance and safety. Because high-rise buildings in
large blocks destroyed the sense of community.
You might live upstairs for 10 years and still not know your upstairs neighbor. Without small shops, without street corner encounters, there was no daily interaction. Because demolishing
old buildings eliminated rental diversity, only low-income people remained, creating a concentration of poverty and a lack of economic vitality. What was Jacobs' insight? The city is a complex self-organizing system, not a machine that can be designed from scratch. Those seemingly chaotic traditional neighborhoods, winding streets, mixed old and
new buildings, and
mixed residential and commercial spaces, precisely contain the wisdom accumulated over generations. This chaos is functional, a delicate balance that maintains the city's vitality. When you replace it with rational planning, demolishing and rebuilding neat grid functional zoning, you destroy not only buildings, but the entire social network, informal order, and local knowledge.
This is completely consistent with Scott's analysis. High modernist
urban planning simplified the complexity of
the city for readability and ignored residents' local knowledge for the sake of scientific management. The result is not a rational city, but a dead city. Now all the pieces of the puzzle are ready. Let's see how Taleb synthesizes this tradition and makes original contributions. What did Taleb inherit from
Burke? First, the Lindy effect: the longer something exists, the longer its expected remaining lifespan. Second, respect for tradition: time is the most rigorous selection mechanism.
Third, gradualism: small improvements are better than large revolutions.
From Hayek, Taleb inherited the limitations of knowledge: we know far less than we think. He inherited the idea that spontaneous order is superior to rational design: market language and common law are evolutionary. He also inherited opposition to centralization: centralized power equals the risk of single-point failure. From Scott, Taleb learned about Metis versus
Techne: practical wisdom cannot be replaced by expert knowledge. He learned to oppose
high modernism: standardization often destroys complexity. He also learned the importance of local knowledge: every situation is unique. From Jacobs, Taleb saw that bottom-up is superior to top-down: organic evolutionary order is more robust. He
saw the value of diversity:
uniformity is a sign of fragility. He also saw that apparent chaos may be a deeper order; don't be misled by appearances. So what are Taleb's original contributions? First, there's the mathematization. While Burke, Hayek, Scott, and
Jacobs all presented qualitative analyses—insights, case studies, and arguments—Taleb reformulated these insights using mathematical language. For example, what is fragility? It's not a vague concept, but rather mathematical concavity: when volatility increases, your losses increase more than when volatility decreases. What is antifragility? It's convexity: the ability to benefit from volatility. The greater the
volatility, the greater your gains. What are the benefits of this mathematization? It allows intuition to be precisely expressed, arguments to be rigorously proven, and strategies to be quantified and implemented. Second, there's the
concept of "skin in the game," Taleb's core original concept. Scott distinguished between Metis and Techne, but his primary focus was on the nature of knowledge. Taleb asks who bears the consequences. Why
is Metis reliable?
Not because it's more scientific, but because those who possess Metis must bear the consequences.
Farmers who plant wrong crops starve; captains who make wrong judgments sink. Why is Techne dangerous?
Not because it's inaccurate,
but because those who possess Techne often don't bear the consequences.
Economists who predict wrong continue to collect consulting fees. When a city planner's design fails, they can try designing another
city. This transforms an epistemological problem into an
ethical one: who has the right to make decisions? The answer is those who bear the consequences. The third original contribution is the concept of
antifragility itself. This transcends traditional robustness. Traditional risk management aims for strength—the ability to withstand shocks
and remain unchanged, like building a sufficiently strong bridge to withstand a once-in-a-century flood. Taleb argues that this is insufficient; better is antifragility—not only able to withstand shocks but also to benefit from them. For example, the human immune system doesn't maintain health by isolating itself from all pathogens, but by developing
antibodies through contact with a small number of pathogens, becoming stronger. A completely sterile environment actually weakens the immune system. This insight is missing in traditional conservative thought. Burke and Hayek emphasize non-destruction, a defensive approach. Taleb points out an offensive strategy: proactively seeking moderate pressure and benefiting from
chaos. The fourth contribution is the integration of disciplines.
Taleb is
not a philosopher, economist, or mathematician; he is a hybrid of these three, plus
history, biology,
and religion. He uses option pricing theory to analyze social phenomena, evolutionary biology to understand institutional change, and probability theory to critique economic models. Using the ethics of Mediterranean merchants to reflect on modern finance—this interdisciplinary synthesis allows him to examine the same problem from multiple angles, discover connections others cannot see, and understand the genealogy of thought.
Now let's use this framework to dissect the specific problems created by modernity. We now know the core logic of right-wing criticism: constructivist rationalism is a fatal arrogance; experts' knowledge is far more limited than they think; spontaneous order is superior to rational design. So, in reality, what systemic problems has modernity caused? I'll analyze five core lesions for you. Lesion one: over-optimization eliminates redundancy, which equals
vulnerability. Modernity has a core
tenet:
efficiency above all else, eliminating
waste. The classic expression of this tenet comes from Adam Smith's *The Wealth of Nations*: division of
labor increases efficiency. Then there's Taylor's *The Principles of
Scientific Management*: every action should be optimized. Then there's Toyota's lean production, just-in-time, zero inventory. Throughout the 20th century, industrial society pursued the same goal: eliminating redundancy and increasing efficiency. But is redundancy really waste? Taleb says redundancy is insurance; eliminating redundancy eliminates the buffer and creates vulnerability. Let's
analyze the case of the just-in-time supply chain. In the 1970s, Toyota invented the just-in-time
production method. The
logic is simple:
inventory ties up capital and space, which is wasteful. If demand can be accurately predicted, and parts are
delivered precisely when needed,
inventory is unnecessary. This seems perfect under normal circumstances: reduced costs, improved cash flow, and shareholder satisfaction. Manufacturers worldwide are learning this approach, and by the 2000s,
it had become an industry standard. Not only the automotive industry,
but also electronics, clothing, and food—all
manufacturing industries were reducing inventory.
Further, to reduce costs, the supply chain became globalized: chips were manufactured in Taiwan, assembled in China, and parts were imported from Japan, South Korea, Germany, and the United States.
This leveraged the comparative
advantages of each location. Further still, to
avoid
redundant construction, many key components had only one supplier.
For example, only TSMC could produce certain special chips, and the main production area for certain rare earth materials was in China. This achieved economies of scale, reducing costs. The
entire system operated with the precision of a Swiss watch during normal times. Then, in 2020, the pandemic hit. China locked down cities, factories shut down, and parts supplies were cut off. Within weeks, global car
production lines came to a standstill, not because of a lack of workers or demand, but because of a shortage of a small component—perhaps a sensor or a chip.
In 2021, a global chip shortage occurred. Automakers could
n't buy chips and had to reduce production. Consumers wanted to buy cars, but… 4S stores have no cars in stock, and you have to wait several months. In 2022,
Shanghai was locked down for two months, and Tesla's Shanghai factory stopped production, affecting the global supply chain. This is a perfect example of
concaveness. Normally, small profits are made, and inventory costs are reduced by 5% to 10%. During a crisis, huge losses occur, and the losses from production stoppages can be several times the normal profits. But why do companies still do this? "Asymmetric Risk" tells you the answer. The
CEO's incentive mechanism: The CEO's term is usually 3-5 years. His bonuses and stock options are tied to short-term performance and stock price. Reducing inventory immediately improves financial statements,
increases profit margins, and raises stock prices. The CEO receives a large bonus during his term and then jumps ship or retires. Supply chain disruptions are a problem 5 or 10 years later, and it's the next CEO's problem. He gains the upside, while shareholders, employees, and consumers
bear the downside risk. This is systemic risk transfer. It should be noted that Taleb is not criticizing Toyota's
original "just-in-time
" concept. The original Toyota approach actually contained many antifragile elements, emphasizing the geographical proximity of suppliers, valuing long-term relationships, and maintaining a certain buffer. What Taleb criticizes is the version later transformed by Wall Street's financialization, with single-supplier
extreme inventory spanning long supply chains, and
financial indicators as the sole objective. This is the distortion of manufacturing caused by excessive
financialization. A similar logic is even more evident in the financial sector. During the 1990s and 2000s, when Greenspan was Chairman of the Federal Reserve, his policy philosophy was to eliminate small fluctuations and pursue
stability. A slight economic downturn would lead to interest rate cuts and a slight stock market decline; the goal of quantitative easing was to ensure stable economic growth and a stable market rise.
This was
known as the Greenspan put option. The market knew that
if there was risk, the Federal Reserve would bail it out. The result? A decreased risk awareness. Since the Federal Reserve would
bail out, why
not increase leverage? Thus, leverage ratios increased, the
real estate bubble grew larger, and financial derivatives became increasingly complex. Small fluctuations were eliminated, but people became less and less risk-averse. It's like the paradox of forest fire prevention. The
US Forest Service's policy used to be to
extinguish every spark, which sounded very responsible, right? The result? Decades later, the accumulation of dead branches led to massive fires that burned for months. Why? Because in nature, forests experience small fires every few years, burning away dead branches and clearing space. These small fires are the ecosystem's
cleaning
mechanism. If you extinguish all the
small fires, fuel accumulates, eventually leading to a massive fire that burns down the entire forest. The same applies to the financial system. Small crises and recessions, which are mechanisms for cleaning up excessive speculation and eliminating bad assets, are smoothed out. Risks accumulate in the shadows, eventually erupting into systemic crises. The
subprime
mortgage crisis nearly caused the global
financial system to collapse. This wasn't a black swan event, but the inevitable result of over a decade of policies aimed at eliminating volatility. Planners, in order to control the system,
need to make it readable, simplified, standardized, and noise-eliminating. However, the resilience of complex systems comes precisely from those seemingly chaotic diversityes and seemingly wasteful redundancies. If you eliminate them all for optimization, it may seem more efficient under normal circumstances,
but the system becomes fragile.
Once a shock occurs, the entire system collapses. Extreme specialization
equals single-point failure risk. Another core tenet of modernity is that the more specialized the division of labor, the higher the efficiency. Adam Smith, in the opening of *The Wealth of
Nations*, uses the example
of needle makers to illustrate the benefits of specialization. One worker completes all the processes, making 20 needles a day. After specialization, 10 workers make 48,000 needles a day, increasing
efficiency by 240 times. This is indeed the foundation of modern industry. Without specialization, there would be no Industrial Revolution, and no current level of productivity. However, modern society has pushed the division of labor to
extremes. It's no longer about being a doctor, but an orthopedic surgeon specializing in left knee cartilage degeneration; no longer about being an engineer,
but a software engineer specializing in React front-end frameworks and Redux state management; no longer about understanding economics, but a macroeconomist studying monetary policy transmission mechanisms and the asymmetric effects in emerging
markets. What's wrong with this extreme specialization? It turns people into cogs in a machine. Imagine an ancient
craftsman who understands the entire process of making a chair: selecting wood, designing the style, cutting, carving, polishing, and painting. He possesses complete skills and can work independently. What about the workers in modern factories? They tighten a screw on an assembly line, repeating the same action for eight hours. They are cogs
in the system. What are the
characteristics of a cog?
Replaceable. If one part breaks, just replace it. Low cost, high efficiency. But what about the cog itself? It's being optimized out at 35 because younger cogs are cheaper.
Industry decline, skills depreciate, nowhere to go.
This is vulnerability. In the past few years, Silicon Valley has experienced massive layoffs, with major companies
laying off over 100,000 people. Many of these people were highly specialized; they were
n't software engineers, but backend engineers specializing in maintaining the Meta
Newsfeed algorithm or data scientists specializing in optimizing specific modules of
Google Ads' bidding system. Their skills are valuable within their current company, but outside of that company, many find it difficult to find similar work because their skills are too narrow, too reliant on a specific company's technology stack, toolchain, and
business logic. Switching companies significantly diminishes the value of this experience. In contrast, consider those with "barbell" skills—note, we're talking about the barbell itself, not just being argumentative. Leonardo da Vinci was a painter, engineer, scientist, and anatomist; Hayek was an economist, psychologist, philosopher, and jurist; Taleb himself was a trader, statistician, philosopher, and writer. These individuals possess multiple skills; if one path fails, others do. More importantly, knowledge from different fields can be cross-
fertilized, generating unique insights. But why do modern enterprises promote extreme specialization? "
Asymmetric Risk" provides the answer: because
companies
need replaceable parts, not indispensable talent. Replaceable parts are cheap, easy to manage, and can be laid off easily.
Irreplaceable talent, on the other hand, has bargaining power, is difficult to manage, and is costly. Therefore, HR and management consultants advocate specialization because specialization makes you vulnerable, dependent, and easily controlled. Your vulnerability is their management convenience. This logic of
specialization leading to "component-like" skills
has an even more extreme manifestation in
China: the separation of arts and
sciences in education. On the surface... This is a product of limited educational resources, but it has gradually become fully institutionalized, even forming a culture. Those who study science look down on those who study humanities, and vice versa. This is like the ruling art of slave
owners: those who are literate are not allowed to carry swords, and those who carry swords are not allowed to be literate. The result is that those who carry swords look down on those who are literate, and vice versa. Both sides feel superior, while the slave owners remain unperturbed. In
reality, true elites should receive a general education. Those who only receive
specialized education, or even only skills training, are precisely the advanced components. Modernity also has a tenet: economies of scale and
centralized management. From small workshops to large factories, from local banks to multinational banks, from decentralized production to global supply chains, the larger the scale, the lower the marginal cost and the higher the
efficiency.
This certainly makes sense from a technical perspective. But Taleb asks what the cost is. The cost is vulnerability. Hayek pointed out long ago that decentralized systems are more stable. The closure of a small restaurant does not affect the overall health of other restaurant industries. The closure of a large bank impacts the entire financial system. Why? Because centralization
creates systemic interconnectedness. In 2008,
Lehman Brothers declared bankruptcy. With assets of $600 billion and a leverage ratio exceeding 30, the collapse of Lehman Brothers
would normally be a normal market shakeout.
However, Lehman was
too large, with complex business relationships with all major financial institutions. Its collapse caused widespread suffering, freezing global credit, causing stock market crashes, and plunging the
economy into recession. Governments were forced to intervene and
bail out other large banks: AIG, Citigroup, Bank of America, and Goldman Sachs, using taxpayer money totaling $700 billion. This is the "too big to fail" phenomenon. On the surface, it appears to be rescuing the market, but in reality, it's creating moral hazard. What is moral hazard? If you don't bear the consequences of losses, you'll take excessive risks.
Bankers
knew that as long as their banks were large enough, the government wouldn't dare let them fail. So what did they do? They leveraged wildly, 30 or 40 times, using $1 billion of their own capital to leverage $30 or $40 billion in assets. Why did
they dare do this? Because it was a free option. If things went up, they made money and received
huge bonuses; if things went down, they lost money, and the government bailed them out.
This is the core critique of "Asymmetric Risk": socializing risk, privatizing returns,
taxpayers bearing losses, and bankers receiving bonuses.
Scott, from a state perspective, points out
that high modernism favors centralization. Centralization is easier to control and easier to read. A large factory is easier to manage than a thousand small workshops; a central bank is easier to regulate than 100 local banks; a standardized supply chain is easier to coordinate than countless local suppliers. But what are the costs of centralization? First, it eliminates diversity; second, it eliminates the trial-and-error mechanism; and finally, it
creates the risk of single points of failure. Taleb's
diagnosis is that small restaurants like this will go bankrupt. This is because they are fragile, but precisely because they are individually fragile, the entire catering industry is antifragile. Inferior restaurants are eliminated, and high-quality restaurants survive. The industry continues to evolve. Big banks cannot fail, which seems stable, but
this destroys the system's learning mechanism. Mistakes are not punished, risks accumulate, and eventually, a larger crisis erupts. Individual fragility is a prerequisite for system antifragility, but "too big to fail" destroys this mechanism.
Individuals are protected, the system cannot learn from the accumulation of risks, and eventually, the entire system collapses. What's worse, who designed this system? Bankers, regulators, and politicians. They have jointly created a system where risk is socialized and returns are privatized. They reap the benefits of upward movement, while taxpayers, depositors, and ordinary people
bear the risks of downward
movement. The four lesions are: expert rule equals the
separation of decision-making and consequences. Modernity has a deep-seated belief that complex problems require experts. We should listen to the experts. Economic policies are designed by economists, war decisions are discussed by think tank experts, financial products are priced by PhDs in mathematics, and urban planning is done by architects.
This seems reasonable—leave professional matters to professionals.
But Taleb asked a crucial question: do these experts bear the consequences? The
answer is no. That's the problem.
Before the subprime crisis, what were economists saying? "Housing prices wo
n't fall nationwide. This has never happened in the past 70 years. Our models show the risk is manageable." What were rating agencies doing? Giving CDOs AAA ratings, the highest credit rating on par with US Treasury bonds. What were
investment banks saying? "These structured products are
safe and suitable for pension funds and insurance companies." In 2008,
housing prices crashed, and the financial system collapsed. What happened to those experts?
Economists continued to serve as
consultants, publishing books and giving speeches,
earning hundreds of thousands of dollars per session. Rating agencies continued to rate and charge fees. Some investment bank executives were fired, but they left with hefty severance packages—tens of millions of dollars in severance pay. No one bore any
substantial consequences for wrong predictions, wrong ratings, or wrong product design. This is the greatest paradox of modernity: a complete separation of decision-making power and risk-bearing. In modern society, experts sit in their offices, making decisions using models, data, and jargon, decisions that affect the lives of millions.
However,
experts bear no consequences.
If they're wrong, they can just move to another organization and continue being experts. Taleb calls these experts "knowledgeable idiots." They have PhDs, can use technical terms, and understand complex models, but they live in a world of egalitarianism and don't understand extremistism. Their models work in normal times but collapse in extreme times. Worse still, they don't know they don't know.
This is what Hayek called fatal arrogance. What is the essence of expert rule? People with techne but no mediocre skills are making decisions for
people with mediocre skills but no techne, and the former don't bear the consequences. This is the greatest irony of modernity. The lesion is that
institutional
design equals systemic
risk transfer. Here, I won't talk about the US CDO; I'll give you a more relevant case: China's real estate. This is a textbook
example of a risk transfer system. Let's see clearly how the money flows and how the risk is transferred. First, let
's look at how the money flows. A homebuyer buys a house for 3 million yuan, with a down payment of 900,000 yuan. The remaining 2.1 million yuan is a 30-year mortgage. Where does this money end up? After the homebuyer signs the contract, the bank directly transfers the 2.1 million yuan loan to the developer. At
this point, the house may have only just started construction, but the
developer has already received 3 million yuan in cash. Of this 3 million yuan, half, or 1.5 million yuan, is land transfer fees. Adding hundreds of thousands more in various
taxes and fees, 2 million yuan flows into local government finances. The remaining 600,000 yuan is construction costs. The developer's actual gross profit is only 400,000 yuan, and the net profit is even lower. However, years of
propaganda have focused on how greedy developers are, demanding they have a moral compass. And look at how ineffective the oversight is! According
to regulations, pre-sale
funds should be used for designated purposes, deposited into a escrow account, and allocated according to project progress. But in reality, the local government is the land seller, the pre-sale fund supervisor, and the tax collector. They and the developers are a community of interest. The government wants land sales revenue, tax revenue, and GDP; the
developers want land, pre-sale permits, and approvals. Both sides are tied together, so oversight becomes a mere formality. Developers submit false project progress reports, and the regulatory departments turn a blind eye and approve them. Even more directly, developers
don't deposit the pre-sale funds into the escrow account at all; instead, they use them to pay off old debts
and acquire new land, like a Ponzi scheme. As long as housing prices rise and new projects sell, the cash flow continues; once
housing prices fall, the
chain breaks. The inability to ensure funds are used for their intended purpose is not a technical issue, but rather a problem with the profit structure. Then consider how the risks are transferred. Once
homebuyers
sign the contract, they enter a 30-year
risk trap. First, there's the risk of
unfinished projects.
The developer uses the money to acquire new land, and if the project's funding chain breaks, it becomes unfinished. Your 900,000 yuan down payment is lost, and you still have to repay the 2.1 million yuan loan. Why? Because the purchase contract is with the developer, and the
mortgage contract is with the bank.
If the developer absconds, your debt remains, and defaulting on the loan has serious consequences. Second, there's the risk of poor quality upon delivery. Pre-sale funds
may be misappropriated, leading to
shoddy workmanship, wall cracks, leaks, and elevator malfunctions. These problems only become apparent after delivery,
and you
cannot refuse to accept the property, otherwise it's considered a breach of contract. If you accept the property and go to the developer,
after the warranty period, you might have to fight a two- or three-year lawsuit. Even if you win, the
developer is just a project company with
no assets, so the
judgment
cannot be enforced. You're still paying a 30-year mortgage and living in a leaky, cracked house. Third, there's the risk of
falling
property prices. The largest land suppliers are often large speculators, much like high-priced private placements in the stock market. First, they use scarcity marketing, releasing only a small amount of land each year, driving up land prices.
Buying a house at a high price means taking over when the government is cashing out at a high price. Your land transfer
fees go directly into the government's treasury. After successfully raising funds at a high price, the government can't sell land and has to lower prices to sell it off. As long as the land cost is low enough, they
can keep lowering prices to sell off. Meanwhile, the big players who cashed out at the high price
have already received their
land transfer fees into the treasury, gained their political achievements, and may have already been promoted. If house prices fall, that's the next administration's problem, your problem. In the end, who will bail them out? In 2021, Evergrande and Country Garden went bankrupt,
leaving millions of houses unfinished. The government guaranteed delivery,
but where did the money come from? Local governments couldn't come up with it, so the
central government issued bonds and set up a special fund. In the end, all taxpayers
footed the bill. What's even more ironic is that the guarantee of delivery only guarantees completion, not quality. Many projects lack water and electricity, elevators, and exterior walls that haven't been plastered or painted. Buyers
receive half-finished houses and have to spend their own money on renovations, but the 30-year mortgage cannot be reduced by a penny. The
logic of the whole system is that
homebuyers pay the down payment plus a 30-year mortgage, and the bulk of the money flows
into the government's pre-sale funds. Regulation is ineffective because the interests of the government, developers, and banks are intertwined. Unfinished
projects and declining quality result in all
liquidity risks being transferred to homebuyers. Mortgage defaults have extremely serious consequences, leading to credit blacklisting, asset seizures, and even price gouging. Ultimately, the entire taxpayer foots the bill to ensure delivery. This is not a market economy; it's a systemic risk transfer mechanism. Taleb argues that elites design the system to gain profits and transfer risk, while ordinary
people bear the consequences. Local governments
sell land for political achievements, officials get promoted, and the debt is left to the next administration. Banks lend money to earn interest, and the state
bails out bad debts.
Developers expand with high leverage, becoming "
too big to fail," and when they collapse, the government bails them out. Only homebuyers are locked in for 30 years, bearing all the risks with no way out. Before 2021, the problem of rising
housing prices
was masked;
after 2021, the problem of falling housing prices was fully exposed,
but it was too late. The
wealth of tens of millions of families has
evaporated, and millions of houses have become unfinished projects. This is the core of asymmetric
risk. The criticism is that decision-
makers don't bear the consequences, and those who bear the risk have no decision-making power. Now, let me summarize the common characteristics of these five ailments. From an antifragile perspective, they are all concave structures:
over-optimization leads to small profits in normal times. 5% cost reduction leads to massive losses during crises and 50% losses from production stoppages. Extreme specialization results in stable wages during normal times, but skills
depreciate after unemployment. Centralization is efficient during normal times,
but carries systemic risk during collapse. Expert rule appears scientific during normal times, but models fail during extremes. Financialization
collects fees and interest during normal times, but
shifts losses during crises. From the perspective of asymmetric risk, all of these are risk transfers. Over-optimization results in CEOs receiving short-term bonuses, while the next CEO bears the supply chain risk. Extremely specialized companies gain management convenience, but employees bear the risk of unemployment.
Centralized banks receive bonuses, while taxpayers bear the bailout costs. Expert rule results in
experts receiving consulting fees, and the public bears the burden of failed decisions. Financialization turns financial institutions into reapers. The core insight is that modernity doesn't make the world safer, but rather makes the elite safer, making you more vulnerable. The essence of
constructing rationalism
is doing these things in the name of rationality, science, and professionalism. First, it deprives you of your choice; second, it destroys your
honor;
third, it increases your dependence; and finally, it
transfers the risk to you. The more you optimize, the more vulnerable you become; the more specialized you are, the more dependent you are on the system; the more centralized you are, the more passive you become; the more you listen to experts, the
more likely you are to be scammed; the more financialized you are, the more the
risk is transferred to you. Understanding the root cause... The question now is, what do you do? Ideally, you would change the system, but that's difficult, requires generations of effort, and success isn't guaranteed. We'll discuss this more realistic choice later: protect yourself first. Taleb's strategy can be divided into two levels. The first level is "voting with your feet"—choosing those with skin in the game. The second level is self-transformation—changing yourself
from concave to convex. The core principle of the first level, "voting with your feet," is to
take responsibility for yourself as much as possible. If you must rely on others, choose agents who share your risks. The first strategy is to make your own investment decisions. Don't entrust your money to mutual funds. Why? Because the business model of mutual
funds is to achieve scale and collect management fees. Whether you make a profit or loss, they still collect their management fees. This is a typical example of
concave risk; they gain
upside returns, while you bear
downside risks. So what do you do? Learn to invest and make your own decisions. Buffett's advice is not to invest in things you don't understand. This isn't about avoiding investment, but about learning until you understand. A more
extreme example is
cryptocurrency. You put your coins on an exchange thinking it's safe, but
you're actually transferring the risk to the exchange. What happens if the exchange goes bankrupt? Haven't the lessons from
Mt. Gox and FTX been enough? Keep your private keys safe using a hardware wallet. Although it's inconvenient, the risk is in your hands. What if you lose your private keys? That's your responsibility, but at least no one can run away with your money. The
old adage in the crypto world is "Not your keys, not your coins." The third strategy is to make your professional skills transferable. Don't rely on a single employer,
and don't let your skills only apply to one company. Why are mid-level managers at large
companies laid off at 35? Because their skills are specific to a particular company's system. What happens when those skills depreciate outside that system? Learn more
transferable skills. English is globally applicable, programming is cross-industry, writing is cross-domain, and data analysis is needed everywhere. These skills are yours, not dependent on an employer.
Even if you change jobs, industries, or countries, these
skills remain. The fourth strategy
is to maintain
geographical mobility. Don't lock yourself into one country. Get a passport, visa, learn a foreign language, and understand immigration policies. These are things you can do now. Don't wait until a crisis hits to try and escape; by then, it
will be too late. Look at history: how many European Jews in the 1930s couldn't escape because they weren't prepared? Those who obtained visas in advance, learned English, and had overseas connections survived. Many who thought things wouldn't be so bad didn't survive. I'm not saying a crisis will definitely come; I'm saying keep your
options open and take control of your destiny. The
fifth strategy is to verify information yourself. Don't just rely on one media outlet.
Don't just listen to one voice. Find original sources and verify them
yourself. When you see news, find how different media outlets report on it. When you see research, find the original papers.
Don't just look at media interpretations. It's tiring, but it's the only way to maintain independent judgment. Modern media and social media are creating information, feeding you what you want to see, not what you should see, like a cocoon. If you don't actively break free, you'll be trapped inside. The sixth strategy is not to
outsource education. Do
n't completely hand over your child's education to schools. Schools teach standardized things suitable for the industrial age. The future needs creativity, independent thinking, and problem-solving skills. Schools can't teach these; you have to teach them yourself. Broaden
your child's horizons, discuss issues with them, teach them critical thinking, and encourage them to question authority. These are your responsibilities as parents and cannot be outsourced. The
core of the
first level is to keep control, decision-making power, and risk in your own hands. Is it troublesome? Yes, it is, but it's the only way to be antifragile.
Because as long as there are intermediaries, there's a possibility of risk
transfer; as long as there are agents, there's a problem of conflicting interests. The reality is, we
can't do everything ourselves. We can't open our own bank, manufacture our own
mobile phones, or run our own schools. So the second principle is to choose agents who share your risks. Here, we'll only use investment as an example. A simple yet effective criterion is to prioritize companies where the founder is the CEO. Why? Because the "skin in the game" for founders and professional managers is completely different. How do professional managers make money? High salaries, bonuses, stock options. When the company's stock price rises, they
exercise their options, cash out, and leave. If the company runs into problems, they jump ship to another company for a higher salary because their resume now includes the
title of CEO of a large company. Their downside risk is limited; the worst-case scenario is being fired and receiving a large severance package to find another job. Their upside potential is also limited.
No matter how well they perform, they are still just employees and can't truly share in the company's growth. So what are their incentives? Short-term performance to make the stock price look good during their tenure, then cash out and leave.
What about founders and CEOs? Most of their wealth is tied to company stock, which usually has a lock-
up period and cannot be cashed out
easily. More importantly, this is their "child," their "career," their "reputation." If the company fails, they not only lose wealth, but their entire life
is ruined. If Musk messes up Tesla, where can he go? If Bezos messes up Amazon, what can he do? If Zuckerberg's Facebook collapses, what is the meaning of his life? They are tied to their companies; the success or failure of the company is their success or failure. This binding creates perfect incentive alignment.
Founders are more responsible for the company's long-
term value because that is their
own value. They will avoid the trap of short-termism because they can't escape it. They will be
more cautious in taking risks
because if they lose, they lose everything. Data also proves this: in the S&P 500, companies led by founders have significantly higher long-term
returns than companies led
by professional managers. Companies that continue to thrive after founders leave management are generally because they leave behind an excellent corporate culture and good governance structure, forcing subsequent
professional managers to continue the original development path. The second level is self-antifragility. Identifying people with "skin in the game" is
only the first step. More importantly, it's about transforming yourself from concave to convex. Taleb
gives several core principles. The first principle is the barbell strategy, the core of which is extreme differentiation. Clear out the middle ground. Don't aim for medium risk and medium return; aim for 90% extreme safety and 10% extreme risk. Why is the
middle ground dangerous? The mathematics of "Antifragile" tells you that medium-risk assets are often concave. They usually yield small
profits of 8% to 12% annualized, but suffer huge losses during crises, with principal losses of 50% to 80%. "Asymmetric Risk" explains why there are so many medium-risk products. Because this is designed by financial institutions, they receive fixed income from management fees while you bear the risk. The complex, concave nature of the product masks the
true risk,
thus eliminating the middle ground. Let me explain in detail how Taleb's Black Swan Fund operates. This is a perfect example of a barbell strategy. 90% to 95% of the funds are placed in
short-term US Treasury
bonds, which have good liquidity,
almost zero risk, and can be
readily converted to cash. 5% to 10% of the funds are used to buy deep out-of-the-money put options. Profits are only made when the
market crashes; they are cheap normally because everyone thinks it's impossible. The key
characteristic of this strategy is that it loses a little each year, with
option premiums going
down the drain, resulting in an annualized cost of 1% to 5%. During crises, like the 2008 financial crisis when the S&P 500 fell 40%, the Black Swan Fund doubled. During the 2020 pandemic, when the
S&P 500 fell more than 30% in one quarter, the Black Swan
Fund earned 36 times its initial investment. During the bull market from 2009 to 2019, the fund lost a little each year, causing distress for investors. However, when a crisis hits, while others suffer huge losses, the Black Swan Fund makes a
massive profit, compensating for several years' worth of costs
and generating substantial profits. The key insight is... Taleb doesn't need to predict when a crisis will come; he only needs to know that a crisis will definitely come. His barbell strategy
allows him to
not only avoid losses during crises but also make huge profits. How can ordinary people apply this? It doesn't necessarily mean buying options. You can learn his core
logic: place most of your
assets in
extremely safe places to ensure your life is unaffected by market fluctuations; place a small portion of your assets in extremely risky
places. Even if you lose everything in the worst-case scenario, that's only a small portion, and your life remains unaffected. In the best-case scenario, you can
multiply your assets tenfold or a hundredfold. How to implement a business barbell strategy? Have a relatively low-stress job as the stable end, and then do side hustles, entrepreneurial projects, or content creation as the risk end. There are
many success stories. For example, Dangnian Mingyue, a
customs officer, is the stable end; writing "Those Things of the Ming Dynasty" is the risk end. The book eventually sold millions of copies, and his royalties far exceeded his salary. Liu Shen Leilei, a Xinhua News Agency reporter, is the stable end; writing for a public account is the risk end. He only became a full-time self-media creator after gaining millions of followers. Liu Cixin, a
power station engineer at Niangziguan, is the stable end; writing novels while working is the risk end. He only
resigned after writing "The Three-Body Problem." There's also Aunt Liu Zhongjing. Self-media websites and book royalties are stable income sources, which already surpasses his income as a forensic doctor or university professor in China. The "President of the Republic of China" is the risky side.
Although you might find it laughable, the returns on this risky side are astronomical.
Taleb himself is an example: a New York University professor and Wall Street
trader is a stable side; writing books, giving speeches, and being an online celebrity is a risky side. I've seen too many bosses in China go all in, only to have their financing fail, their companies collapse, and they go bankrupt. There's no way out;
one failure equals game over. My lesson is:
never put all your eggs in one basket. My income sources include investment returns as a stable side, consulting services as a stable side, and content creation as a risky side. Content creation is a typical option: limited downside—at worst, nobody reads it; limited time investment;
unlimited upside—if it goes viral, its influence grows
exponentially, bringing more consulting opportunities and commercialization possibilities. Putting myself in the shoes of today's young people, I'd give some advice. If I were only in my twenties, I would finish my PhD at Peking University, then be selected for a government position, or go abroad to study and immigrate, aiming for a government public utility industry.
After securing a stable job, I'd then seek growth opportunities in other areas outside of work. The second principle is subtraction thinking: don't pursue the best, but avoid the worst.
Munger
said, "I only want to know where I'm going to die, and then I'll never go there." This is subtraction thinking. Knowing what not to do is more important than knowing what to do. What is subtraction thinking in investing? What is foolish investing? High leverage—you can't afford to lose. Not understanding the risks of things you don't understand. Needing constant
upward movement to make money. Moral hazard on the other side—gambling with your money. If you avoid these
four types, you've already
won against most people. What is subtraction thinking in life? Taleb's health strategy isn't eating superfoods, taking supplements, or complex nutrition plans, but rather eating less processed food, less sugar, and intermittent fasting. Why? Because our bodies have evolved over millions of years, adapted to irregular eating habits, natural foods, and plenty of movement. Modern life is the opposite: eating processed food every meal and sitting all day. So returning to a natural state and doing subtraction is itself healthy. What is
subtraction thinking in this channel? Why is this channel high-barrier? Videos over 30 minutes require thought; we talk about frameworks,
not code. This will lose many viewers who want quick answers, specific stock recommendations, or chasing trends. But this is precisely subtraction thinking—
by setting a high barrier to entry. By filtering out these viewers, I avoid satisfying unrealistic desires. The third principle is maintaining selectivity. People's nostalgia for youth
is essentially nostalgia for
infinite possibilities. At
20, you can be anyone, go anywhere, and do anything. By 40, most people are locked in—locked in by their
careers, their identities, and their past choices. How do we maintain selectivity? First, maintain the ability to learn. Not what you learn, but the ability to
learn. Most people stop learning
after leaving school; their brains become rigid, they only do familiar things, and they panic when faced with new things. This
is why people are eliminated at 35—
not because of age,
but because they stopped learning at 25. Maintaining the ability to learn means always being exposed to new things, always stepping
out of your comfort zone, and always challenging your understanding. Second, learn
transferable knowledge.
What is transferable? English is
useful in any country. Writing is useful in any industry because clear expression is useful. Programming thinking breaks down problems, and logical reasoning is useful
everywhere. Data analysis is needed for business and research. This knowledge is not dependent on a specific job or industry; it is
your own. Third, learn basic subjects because they are meta-knowledge. Mathematics teaches you abstract thinking, and physics teaches you causal reasoning. History teaches you pattern recognition, philosophy teaches you concept analysis.
These abilities are fundamental; once mastered, learning anything concrete becomes incredibly fast. In contrast, those who only
learn applied skills—like Excel, a
particular software program,
or a specific operation—have very short half-lives, becoming obsolete in two or
three years. The half-life of fundamental disciplines, however, can be decades or even centuries. Finally, it's about maintaining physical and mental plasticity. A rigid body cannot adapt to new environments, and a rigid mind cannot accept new perspectives. Consider those who successfully immigrate: they maintain an open mind, are willing to learn new cultures, and are willing to change themselves. Those who fail often cling to old habits, refuse to learn, and complain about their environment. Taleb's
concept of antifragility, at the individual level, is this kind of
adaptive plasticity. Individuals can save themselves, but what about systems? If the problem of modernity is constructive rationalism and experts overstepping centralized power, what is the solution? The right-wing critique of modernity provides a clear answer: the
core principle is mandatory skin-in-the-game, making decision-makers equal to risk-takers. This is
n't Taleb's invention; it's the wisdom of humanity accumulated over thousands of years. How did ancient Rome do it? Architects designed bridges, and the architects stood beneath them.
Generals led troops into battle alongside their soldiers. Sons of senators were required to serve in the military.
How did the Code of Hammurabi stipulate this? If a house collapsed and killed someone, the architect's son was executed. If an eye surgery failed, the doctor's hand was cut off. What
is business ethics? Reputation equals the greatest asset; one act of deception equals a lifetime of dishonesty. The Mediterranean trade network operated on reputation for centuries. Why was it effective? Because decision-makers knew they would bear the consequences of their mistakes, so they were cautious, conservative, and respected tradition. What should we do in modern times? In the
financial system, bankers trade with their
own money,
returning to a partnership model. If hedge funds underperform, fund managers lose money along with them. Eliminate the "too
big to fail" mentality, allowing banks to go bankrupt. CEO compensation should be
linked to 10-year long-term performance, not quarterly performance. In the political system, failed decisions lead to the resignation of officials and legal liability. Politicians who advocate war should send their children to war first. Debts incurred during their term are personally attributed; there are no golden parachutes. In the expert system, consultants are paid based on results, not time. Economists who make incorrect
predictions
face license revocation, mandatory portfolio disclosure, and public
disclosure of
conflicts of interest. The second principle is localism: small-scale equals automatic risk sharing. Hayek, Scott, and
Jacobs agree
that small-scale is superior to large-scale. Why? First, small-scale enforces risk sharing. If a mayor's policies fail, he encounters voters daily and
cannot escape them. Brussels'
bureaucratic policies affected Greece, while he remained comfortable in Belgium without consequences. Second, small-scale diversifies risk. A policy failure in one state does not affect other states, making the system antifragile. A policy failure in the
central government affects the entire country, making the system fragile. Third, small-scale allows for trial and error. A centralized system leaves no room for error; if one fails, everyone perishes.
Historical comparisons show the impact on Europe. In contrast to East Asia, where Europe remained unified for
centuries over the past two millennia, with hundreds of small states,
city-states, and principalities competing, learning through trial and error, and giving rise to modern science,
democracy, and the
Industrial Revolution, East Asia pursued unification. The Qin Dynasty's prefecture-county system and centralized power led to overexpansion, collapse, fragmentation, and reunification—a cycle repeated for 2,000 years.
Why was Europe more successful?
Because decentralization allowed for trial and error. One country's failure didn't affect others; one country innovated,
and others learned. With unification, the emperor's mistakes were implemented nationwide; errors resulted in national catastrophe. Talebhayek advocated decentralization, local autonomy, and federalism over centralization; small states were superior to large states, and city-states to empires. Liu Zhongjing's theory of the various Xia states is a right-wing critique of modernity applied in the Chinese context. A unified empire is fragile; a collapse means total
collapse. The small states of the various Xia states are anti-fragile, diversifying risk
and allowing for individual trial and error.
You may disagree with his political views, but theoretically, a fragmented system of small states is indeed more stable than unification. However, in reality, the system is difficult to change in the short
term. Why? Because the current system favors the elite, who reap upward
benefits. The risk is being shifted to you.
Why would they want to change? The inertia of the system is enormous. There are too-to-fail banks, a powerful central government, and a financialized economy—all of which have huge vested
interest groups. So what can you do? It depends on where you are. If you are
in the free world, then congratulations, you have the potential to drive change. But don't misunderstand, I'm not saying you have to convince the majority, or that you have to wait for
51% to agree before you can change anything. In *Asymmetric Risk*, Taleb offers a counterintuitive insight: changing the world doesn't require a majority, only a
determined minority. He cites Kosher as an example. American Jews make up only 2% of the population, and those who strictly adhere to Kosher laws are even fewer. But if you go to the supermarket, you'll see many food products with Kosher certification.
Why?
Because Jews are an uncompromising minority; they absolutely refuse to eat non-Kosher food.
Others, however, are
indifferent to whether it's Kosher or non-Kosher. So how do food companies choose? They
make everything Kosher, so that Jews can eat it, and others can eat it too, maximizing the market. The result is that the 2% of determined minorities changed the standards of the entire
food industry. The key to this is that the silent majority always loses to the determined minority because the majority is flexible, while the minority is uncompromising. When one side has to compromise and the other
refuses to compromise, the side that refuses to compromise will ultimately win. What does this mean for you?
You don't need to convince 51% of voters; you just need to find that 3% to 5% of staunch minorities and take consistent action in your community, your city, your state. Attend city
council hearings—every time, speak every time. Vote for a mayor who is truly
accountable to the community. Mobilize your friends to vote too. Push for transparency in local budgets—watch every
expenditure. Support school district
reform. Participate in
parent committees. These may seem small, but the key is consistency and persistence. Most people are too lazy to attend city council meetings, too lazy to examine budgets, too lazy to vote. As long as you and a small group persist,
you can change decisions because these things are
irrelevant to others,
but essential to you. The
final equilibrium will be based on your standards. History is full of examples. The abolitionist movement in the United States initially had only a small number of radicals supporting abolition, but their unwavering and persistent action ultimately changed the entire
country. The civil
rights movement started with only a minority of Black and white leftists, but their refusal to compromise ultimately led to the
enactment of civil rights legislation. The environmental movement, the women's rights movement, and the legalization of same-sex marriage—which of these started by convincing the majority? It's always the case that a small, determined
minority acts first, and then the more flexible majority gradually accepts. This insight is especially important for local politics. Why? Because local political participation is extremely low. In city council elections, voter turnout is often only in the teens.
This means that if you can organize just 2% to 3% of the committed voters, you can determine the composition of the city council. And the city council controls budgets, zoning, education, and law enforcement—things that directly affect your quality of life. So
if you're in the free world, don't think, "I'm just one person, I can't change anything."
You don't need to change everyone;
you just need to find that 3% of like-minded people and act decisively. At the local level, that's enough. But if you're not in the free world, the possibility of institutional change is extremely slim. So my
advice is simple:
abandon the idea of ​​change. Don't be like those selfless officials who take the world as their responsibility. Don't waste your energy on things you can't change. Adults should only filter, not change. What you need to do is manage yourself and
your family, invest your time and resources in things
you can control: improve your skills, accumulate wealth, maintain your health, educate your children, build connections, and most importantly, gain the right to choose as soon as possible: get a passport and visa, learn a foreign language, understand immigration policies, accumulate transferable skills and assets,
so that you have the ability to leave when necessary and the ability to choose a better institutional environment. Voting with your feet is your most practical choice. Remember Taleb
's core insight: Don't try to
change a system you can't change; instead, empower yourself to exit it.
Antifragility isn't about fighting a boulder; it's about ensuring you're not underneath it when it falls. Now let's return to the initial question: What's wrong with modernity? The left says the problem is capitalist private ownership and market chaos; the solution is more state intervention, central planning, and expert governance. The right says the problem is constructive rationalism, experts overstepping
central authority; the solution is traditional wisdom,
local autonomy, and spontaneous order. Taleb stands on the right side.
He is the latest representative of the intellectual lineage of Burke, Hayek, Scott, and Jacobs. He uses *Antifragile* to tell you about the structural fragility created by modernity. He uses *Asymmetric Risk* to tell you about the risk transfer mechanism behind modernity. What is the complete four-part logic? *Fooled by Randomness* talks about humility; success may be luck, don't be overconfident. *The Black Swan* talks about accepting uncertainty; extreme events are unpredictable, but they determine history. *Antifragile*
talks about transforming structures not by predicting the
future, but by enabling yourself to
benefit from chaos. *Asymmetric Risk* talks about identifying risk transfer; understanding who is transferring risk to you. Why is this relevant to our
generation? Global geopolitical risks are surging, supply chain restructuring, financial decoupling, and inflation eroding wealth. The 2008 financial crisis, the 2020 pandemic, and the 2022 Russia-Ukraine war have all proven that what you thought was impossible can happen. Most people are unprepared, or even unaware, that everything they're used to can be destroyed in an instant. What
can you do? Vote with your
feet. Choose
people and institutions with skin in the game.
Stay away from experts who gamble with your money.
Vote with your money. Use a barbell strategy: mostly extremely safe, plus a small amount of extremely risky. Maintain liquidity. Don't lock yourself into a path. Adopt an antifragile, subtractive mindset to avoid foolishness. Maintain a diverse range of skills and income.
Remember Taleb's words: Fragile people seek prediction; antifragile people seek choice. The wind
can extinguish a candle, but it can make a
fire burn brighter.
What we need is not more planning, but more humility; not more expert
rule, but more risk-sharing; not greater centralization, but more
decentralized local autonomy.
Taleb's ideas are not academic luxuries, but survival necessities. When poor, cultivate your own virtue and protect yourself. Make yourself
antifragile. When successful, export order and understand the world. Vote with your money. Push for reform when the opportunity arises. But whatever you do, never believe in the absence of skin. Those in the game, don't leave your fate in the hands of
others.
Maintain your options and
wait for your opportunity.
Thanks for watching, see
you next time!