Today we're going to talk about a country that
can be considered one of the biggest economic disasters in modern human history:
Venezuela.
As the country with the world's largest oil reserves, it started with a
hand of
"two kings and four twos,"
yet its GDP plummeted by 80% in less than a decade.
According to UN estimates, by
2024, 82% of the population will
live below the poverty line. The
capital, Caracas, has a poverty line, an entire mountain of slums, and one of the
highest murder rates in the world.
In this country where gas is practically free, even basic necessities like
toilet paper, food, and medicine are in
extreme shortage.
Supermarkets are so crowded that you have to be queuing to buy groceries,
checking the last digit of your ID card, and they have
very strict armed security. For over a decade, Venezuela has been mired in hyperinflation, where
money is weighed by the kilogram. How absurd is
this rate of currency
devaluation?
If you stacked
100-bolivar bills from 20 years ago one by
one, and
physically filled the entire Bird's Nest stadium—
or even
40 Bird's Nest stadiums—how
much would that be worth? It's only enough to
buy a McDonald's hamburger,
and you can't even get fries and a soda,
etc.—these are some of the most horrific concepts. It turns out that all these factors have manifested in this
one country. So don't think we're talking about Venezuela today just because it's a political hotspot. Let's take a look at how it managed to turn such a promising situation around. Venezuela is a country on the northern coast of South America, with a
land area of ​​910,000 square kilometers, slightly larger than the three northeastern provinces of China combined. It currently has a population of
approximately 28 million. Originally inhabited by indigenous Native Americans, it was ruled by the Spanish for nearly
300 years, starting in the 16th century. Therefore, it still speaks Spanish. It gained independence in 1830,
becoming one of the first countries in South America to break free from Spanish rule. However, the key factor truly influencing its development wasn't independence or colonization, but something else entirely. In 1914, Venezuela drilled its first commercial oil well, discovering oil. In the following 21 years, it transformed from an unknown country into the world's second-largest oil producer,
second only to the United States.
We often say oil is black gold, and this windfall became a boon for Venezuela's then-dictator, Gómez. He became the richest person in all of Latin America. We've discussed this before regarding oil. In the early days,
global oil resources were monopolized by
seven British and American oil companies, known as the "Seven Sisters,"
forming a cartel.
Venezuela's share was distributed among three of these: Gulf Oil, Standard Oil, and Shell. Initially, these three had considerable influence, as oil extraction and transportation technology was relatively scarce. Venezuela,
being a small, inland country, only
received a small share of the oil profits. However, after World War II, these
oil-producing nations began to realize
something was amiss. "So many companies can
extract oil, but only I possess this resource. This is the scarcest and most valuable resource. I am the landlord! What are
you Seven Sisters doing, arguing with me?" So, Venezuela joined forces with the Seven Sisters to negotiate, signing the famous 50/50 revenue-sharing agreement. Simply put, "I let you extract oil here, and we'll split the profits 50/50." Later, Venezuela
also joined forces with four Middle Eastern countries to
establish OPEC, which significantly
boosted the Venezuelan government's revenue.
This gold mine grew even larger. In
just five years,
government revenue increased sixfold.
But the real golden age was
yet to come.
The wealth accumulated before was merely
small-scale. In
1973, the Yom Kippur War broke out, also
known as the "Fourth Middle East War."
Arab countries in the Middle East joined hands and collectively
imposed an oil embargo on the West,
plunging the world into an oil shortage. Oil
prices quadrupled in a short period,
from $3 per
barrel to $12, known as the First Oil Crisis. A few years later, in 1979, the
Second Oil Crisis broke out, with oil prices soaring further to $35 per barrel—ten times the price of ten years earlier! This led to global inflation and economic stagnation. But for Venezuela, it was like a windfall. A huge windfall!
Venezuela was probably the biggest beneficiary of these two consecutive oil crises. Venezuela,
you see, is an oil-exporting country, has
little connection to the Middle East, and is
so close to the United States.
In 1976, the Venezuelan government
fully nationalized its oil industry,
establishing its own state-owned oil company, PDVSA.
If the previous high oil prices were
a goldmine,
this time it was an unimaginable windfall. In
10 years,
Venezuela's GDP increased sixfold.
The capital, Caracas,
saw the construction of South America's most modern highways,
skyscrapers, and university towns. State-owned
enterprises
expanded rapidly, employing 300,000 people. You'd find a waiter standing
in an elevator,
in a public bathroom, or outside an
office –
that's a job. The
government had plenty of money. Meanwhile, private
enterprises shrank as they moved into the city.
But that didn't matter;
even if large companies weren't profitable, they
were supported by government subsidies. The
Venezuelan bolivar
became one of the world's strongest currencies
because of its extremely strong exchange rate.
At that time, Venezuela's middle class
would even go shopping in Miami on weekends. As long as
oil prices remained high, the
Venezuelan government had a continuous supply of oil.
As long as oil prices remain high, every citizen can relax and enjoy a life of high wages and high welfare. High oil prices provide
enough
incentive for the entire economy to stand at the top of the world; no
economic problem is a problem.
However, this didn't last long. In the
1980s, international oil prices began to plummet. The
Venezuelan government initially hoped
this was just a temporary setback.
So, although government revenue began to decline,
it didn't cut back on
previous redundant government spending. Instead, it
chose to issue
large amounts of debt, thinking that when oil prices rose, it would immediately recover. But this was clearly naive; it was just the beginning of a nightmare. To cope with high inflation,
the US announced interest rate hikes, and
capital began to withdraw from the Latin American market. In
1982, Mexico couldn't hold on any longer and
announced it couldn't repay its foreign debt,
officially triggering the Latin American
debt crisis. Venezuela was also greatly affected. Venezuela couldn't hold on any longer.
On February 18, 1983, the president announced that the bolivar's exchange rate had depreciated from 4.3 bolivars to 7.5 bolivars to the US dollar,
and foreign exchange controls were implemented. And, as you can imagine, a large portion of its capital was imported. This entire period is known as Venezuela's "Black Friday." Venezuela quickly plunged into an economic crisis, and
oil prices further collapsed in 1986, falling from $27 to less than $10. What
Venezuela didn't expect was that oil prices would remain at this low level for nearly 20 years. Inflation began to rise in Venezuela, and
the government tried various policies, but none were effective. In fact, many of these policies were counterproductive,
further pushing up prices in Venezuela. We'll analyze this in more detail when the situation worsens. The government realized that various control policies were ineffective, and in 1989, a new president named Perez was elected. He went to the other extreme, completely deregulating everything—
foreign exchange, interest
rates,
costs, and
privatizing state-owned enterprises. This period is also known as the "Great Adjustment Period."
Those who frequently read our content should be familiar with
this concept of extreme
market liberalization, which was extremely
popular in the 1990s, mainly promoted by the United States. At that
time, it wasn't just in Latin America, but also in Southeast Asia, and later in Russia and Poland, shock therapy followed this style. It believed that the
market would solve all problems. In fact, the liberalization
reforms themselves weren't inherently problematic, but the issue was that these policies were too radical. Suddenly abandoning all
control had a huge short-term impact on the
economy.
More importantly, this laissez-faire approach to market competition has a prerequisite: the market needs a basic business environment and a basic rule of law. But what was Venezuela's situation at the time? Market rules were nonexistent, many laws were ineffective, and public subsidies for food and energy were
gone. The minimum wage was
completely eliminated, which inevitably worsened the domestic economy, leading to numerous protests and riots. The bolivar began to plummet. As we just mentioned, on Black Friday in 1983, one dollar was worth
7.5 bolivars; by 1993, it had fallen to 1 dollar to 100 bolivars. In 1994,
banks collapsed one after another, and corruption in the
government and financial sector was completely exposed. President Perez, for embezzling 250 million bolivars from the National Liberty Fund, became the first president to be impeached by the
Supreme Court, and the Finance Minister was also forced to
resign. This also signaled the complete failure of the "Great Adjustment" era. As the tide receded, it became clear that almost everyone in the financial world was talking about it. This financial world may have glossed over many things, but
I think its impact on the Venezuelan economy was more direct than the problems we just discussed. It was like a heavy punch to Venezuela's jaw, causing it to collapse on the
spot. Speaking of which, I guess you can sense from our previous words that Venezuelan politics is quite chaotic. Just look at how frequently its name has
changed. When it gained independence in 1830, it was called the States
of Venezuela. Later, it was renamed the Republic of Venezuela. Less than 10 years later, seeing that the Americans to the north had a better system, they fought a war and changed the name to the United States of Venezuela. Then,
after World War II, it was changed back to the
Republic of Venezuela. And then, you see, it has to be changed again. Although its
system has been basically democratic
elections, these elections are often invalid or heavily manipulated. There are also many different forces vying for power within the government. So, every president's position is precarious. They have to balance the interests of various interest groups, constantly worry about being overthrown or impeached, and find ways to attract votes. Of course, they also have to think about how to benefit themselves. This inevitably
leads to many problems.
But I believe that in the long run,
a very fundamental problem
is that its leadership is incapable of long-term investment and
long-term planning. Let me
give you a simple example. Do you think the Venezuelan leader doesn't understand that
oil prices will continue to fluctuate and
won't rise forever? The
simplest way to prevent this is to establish
a national fund, like Norway, to save money
when oil prices are high and
buy gold or foreign bonds—making
long-term investments. Is that
so difficult? Didn't the
Venezuelan government think of this?
Actually, it's not that
they haven't tried, but these presidents gradually realized that
every time they tried to save money, it only
became a cash cow for the next few presidents. The
dramatic changes in power, coupled
with rampant corruption, made
any long-term investment almost impossible. Note that I'm referring to
long-term investment
not only in the form of
investments with
returns, but also in institutional investments, such as investments in... The idea that a quick and effective presidential election can win over public support is a good analogy. From
this
perspective, look at Middle Eastern countries like Saudi Arabia, Qatar, and the UAE –
these are relatively centralized monarchies. While they have many problems stemming from their strong power, they can indeed take a longer-term view and make many long-term investments. After all, this isn't just for the country, but also for their own future and their descendants. Look at their visionary plans, right?
They might even be a bit too willing to
invest long-term. In short, Venezuelan politics is quite chaotic. Let's go back to the
timeline. In the 1980s and 1990s, with low oil prices, Venezuela's GDP didn't grow for 15 years. The economy stagnated, struggling in a high-inflation environment. The
people increasingly hoped for a major reform. Against this historical
backdrop, in 1999, Venezuela's most famous president, and also its most controversial leader, came to power: Hugo Chávez. Chávez himself had a military background and
a very strong-arm government.
His advocacy of "socialism" led to the founding of the "United Socialist Party of Venezuela." He was very close to Cuba and had a very close relationship with Castro. Several
times, he flew to Cuba to celebrate Castro's birthday with him for several days. In fact,
Chavez had attempted to overthrow the existing regime in 1992, though unsuccessfully, but he gained significant public support. Later, in the
1997 election, he advocated for
large-scale reforms to address the status quo and eliminate corruption.
Imagine, the people, utterly disillusioned with the corrupt government, certainly hoped for a strong leader to change the situation. Thus, Chavez came to power forcefully and remained president of Venezuela until his death from cancer in 2013. And what did Chavez do first upon taking office? He changed the country's name to the "Bolivarian Revolution." You see, they seem to really like "
Bolivarian," right? It's the country's name, and even the currency. The Bolivar is actually a name associated with a great general who helped South America gain independence from Spanish rule in the 19th century. Therefore, it carries a certain symbolic weight of independence, chaos, and patriotism. Chavez
believed that the main reason Venezuela was previously in such chaos was the erosion of capitalism. They're trying to turn the wealth we've gained from our oil resources into their own profits.
Inflation?
This isn't a
natural economic phenomenon! This is the evil of capitalism! Hostile forces are behind this! This is their conspiracy! So he drastically implemented a series of public ownership reforms. All the key industries, like banking, infrastructure, transportation, electricity, and
communications, were nationalized, while taxes on foreign companies were increased. This scared away most foreign investment. In 2001, he passed the Land Law, allowing the state to expropriate land and encouraging grassroots communities to establish small cooperatives, providing them with funding and technical support
as an alternative to a market economy. Chavez also
successfully brought the previously independent central bank under
complete government control through several legislations. The
government had the final
say.
This actually foreshadowed his later run into hyperinflation. And of all
Chavez's
nationalization efforts, the most important one I haven't mentioned yet is oil. Are you wondering why? Didn't we just say that the oil industry was already nationalized in 1976 and had
considerable influence,
even being called a
"state within a state"?
Chávez felt it was a disgrace that
the nation's lifeline, the
oil company, was controlled by Americans and British, and that they had to share so much money with it. So, in 2002, he placed trusted individuals on the board of directors of the national oil company in an
attempt to control him.
He appeared on a weekly television program
called "
April 7th," where he would
hold a whistle in his mouth and read out the
names of the oil company executives who opposed him. Each
whistle signaled their dismissal.
This escalated,
even leading to a brief military coup
attempt to remove Chávez, which
he suppressed. At the end of
2002,
employees of Venezuela's national oil company
staged a massive strike,
virtually halting oil production. Output plummeted
from 3 million barrels
per day to less than 300,000 barrels per day,
essentially
shutting down the country's engine.
This strike,
conservatively estimated, cost
Venezuela $10 billion in economic losses,
causing a 27% decline in its GDP in the first quarter of 2003.
However, these short-term economic losses were relatively minor. Even
more devastating was the long-term damage it caused.
Chavez's response was extremely harsh: "
You're on strike? You're
not working?
Then you don't need to come anymore. Fire
everyone!" This resulted in the dismissal of nearly 20,000 employees. You might not think that many now, but for the Venezuelan state-owned oil company at the time, it meant almost half its workforce was laid off. And think about it, this was different from typical layoffs. Normally, layoffs are selective, choosing those who are
easy to lay
off. But back then, they targeted those who took to the streets. No matter who
you were, if you
held key technologies or
held a critical position,
if you took to
the streets, you were out. This resulted in the layoff of many core
technical personnel. After this upheaval, Chavez did indeed successfully control the state-owned oil company, but he paid a very heavy price. Not only did external technology withdraw, but he also laid off a large portion of his technical staff, causing Venezuela's oil technology to regress by more than a decade. Both management and technical capabilities have
declined drastically.
With aging equipment and
technology loss, more than
20 years later,
its extraction capacity is less than
half of its peak before the strike.
The oil was simply left there for you to extract. It just ca
n't get anything out. After only a couple of digs, it starts panting and
can't keep up, so it has to sit and rest for half a day. And many American oil giants, including ExxonMobil, either had their assets forcibly seized or were forced to accept new contracts in the period that followed.
You see, the
vast area of ​​refineries in the Gulf of Mexico is designed for
Venezuelan heavy oil. This disruption is
n't just about losing a few barrels of oil in the short term; it means these newly invested refineries will face a "famine" for decades. They won't have oil to refine and will have to rely on Canadian heavy
oil as a substitute. So, as we analyzed before, this US attack on Venezuela definitely has a significant reason: it's not just because of its abundance of oil, but because it's all heavy oil suitable for US refineries. The situation is starting to get complicated.
Let's
lay out some
background information.
Oil-rich countries like Venezuela are
hard-pressed to
escape this so-called "oil curse." It's not simply a matter of money leading to corruption.
You see, having abundant natural resources leads to exports, generating large amounts of US dollars. And then...
It converts large amounts of US dollars into the local
bolivar, leading to a continuous appreciation of the bolivar. When your currency appreciates, your domestically produced goods become more expensive for other countries, losing competitiveness. Goods from other countries become cheaper, leading you to favor goods from other nations. This significantly weakens Venezuela's domestic agriculture and manufacturing,
causing them to gradually decline.
So, over time,
from a national perspective, its economic model
becomes
frantically exporting oil
and buying other goods.
You see,
over 95% of its exports are oil, while
over 80% of its domestic industry and food
are imported.
Its domestic manufacturing and agriculture decline, and the service
sector becomes the main industry.
It's like a rich kid who,
because God has given them so much, ca
n't help but become decadent.
This phenomenon has a specific term in economics:
"Dutch disease," named after a similar phenomenon that occurred
in the Netherlands in the 1960s.
However, I think it should actually be called "
Dutch disease.
" If this so-called disease
continues indefinitely, it
's not a big problem;
I'll just keep selling oil to make money
and buying other things. The
key issue is that
this country's industrial capacity has deteriorated, and it
can't produce anything of its own.
This means its economy has lost its immunity; any slight disturbance could cause it to collapse. This is why, in the 1980s, when
oil prices fell,
Venezuelan oil companies might seem to think, "So what if oil prices fall? You'll just earn less, it won't cause a collapse." The reason is that its non-oil sectors had lost their capacity and completely deteriorated. And the crux of all this is the exchange rate. Look at how Chavez messed with the oil companies;
foreign investors
avoided the country like the plague, and
domestic citizens lost confidence
in the
economy and went abroad to
exchange their money for US dollars.
This led to a
continuous decline in the exchange rate of its currency, the bolivar, and a continuous
rise in prices.
Faced with these two classic economic difficulties, Chavez's
response was
very simple and brutal: "The
exchange rate is falling?
No way!
I'll
set an official exchange rate.
Prices are rising? No way! I'll set a cap on the purchasing power of the bolivar." But the cost was further degradation of domestic productivity, further distortion of the economic structure, and further growth of corruption and the black market. With further capital flight and increased shortages of supplies, Venezuela was terminally ill. However, things didn't deteriorate rapidly; instead, life in Venezuela gradually improved. Why? Because oil prices rebounded,
and moreover, at the beginning
of the year, the
global economy experienced a surge, leading to a dramatic increase in oil demand. Oil prices increased sixfold in
seven years, and Venezuela's goldmine returned. With
this influx of abundant US dollars, the entire economy returned to the prosperous state it had been in the 1970s. Instead of using this respite to build a reserve fund, Chavez heavily subsidized the public, providing them with almost free electricity, almost free
water, and almost free oil. Very cheap food and generous housing subsidies. He also established thousands of
free medical clinics for the poor. At the time, gasoline in Venezuela was even cheaper than bottled water. $100 worth of gasoline was enough to drive around the world several times over. The government became increasingly large and bloated. About a quarter of Venezuela's working population worked in government. Although the economic structure was unbalanced and basic necessities had to be imported, it didn't matter, because
oil prices were rising
and
people had more money. People's lives improved under Chavez's leadership. The country's GDP quadrupled in just ten years. Venezuela was gradually eliminating poverty, and its
urbanization rate reached
90%, the highest in South America. At this
rate, it could soon become
one of the world's richest countries again. To encourage borrowing, Chavez even set a cap on interest rates. The idea was to borrow more, spend more, invest more, and not save. The highest interest rate for credit cards at the time was 29%. This might sound very high, but you have to know that
Venezuela's
inflation rate at the time was 30%-50%. Its
loan interest rates are lower than the inflation rate; the real
interest rate has always been negative. After you
borrow money, the
amount you actually have to repay decreases, so saving money results in increasingly lower returns. Naturally, everyone borrows money instead of saving. This led to a consumer frenzy in
Venezuela, where people bought cars without hesitation, all for the sake of financial management. The
real estate bubble was even more pronounced. This negative real interest rate caused the entire economy to accelerate rapidly, with capital turnover becoming faster and faster. A very interesting consumer trend emerged: cosmetic surgery.
Venezuela became
one of the countries in the Americas most fond of cosmetic surgery. Many women considered
it an essential step in their coming-of-age ceremony. Families with the means would prepare money for their daughters' cosmetic surgery. Now, there's a social consensus that cosmetic surgery is a "necessary path" to better career opportunities and higher social status. After all, with such high inflation,
saving
money is impossible, but cosmetic surgery is a long-term
investment in one's life. You should know that Venezuela is a global beauty pageant powerhouse, arguably the
strongest in the world. It has won the most titles in the four major
global beauty pageants. Venezuela, also known as the "Land of Beauties," has a very complete beauty pageant system. Not only does it have the highest-level "Miss Venezuela" pageant, but every city, community, and even school has its own
beauty pageant, forming a
complete beauty selection mechanism. Naturally, this has also led to the rise of a related industry chain: beauty pageant training and cosmetic surgery. Okay, let's lighten things up a bit. Now back to the main topic. In 2013, Chávez died of cancer. During his 14 years in power, oil prices initially rose steadily and then fluctuated at high levels. He used the wealth generated by oil to directly improve the lives of Venezuelans. However,
some fundamental economic problems, such as structural issues, corruption, and government inefficiency, continued to worsen under the nourishment of the oil boom. His successor,
Nicolás Maduro, also from the United Socialist Party, was not so lucky. Almost as soon as
he took office, before he even had a chance to settle in, oil
prices began to plummet. Venezuela's good days are over. The crisis of the 1980s is essentially repeating itself, only this time with even greater intensity. Its
economic structure and
inefficient
state-owned enterprises simply cannot support domestic demand. Most necessities rely on imports, a constant stream of overseas purchases. But with
oil
prices falling, Venezuela has run out of money and can no longer afford these
goods. In five years, Venezuela's imports have plummeted to one-sixth of previous levels, plunging the country into severe
shortages. By 2015, due to severe shortages and
government price controls to prevent price increases,
many food items, including toilet paper, were snapped up as soon as they hit the shelves. Many cities had to be fenced off with iron bars, and armed security personnel had to patrol
supermarkets to prevent excessive riots or "zero-dollar purchases." You'd think there were some treasures inside! Eventually, the
lines in front of supermarkets
became so long and chaotic that
the government mandated that people go to the supermarket on a per-item
basis. For example, those with birthdates ending in 0 or 1 could go on Mondays, and those with birthdates ending in 2 or 3 on Tuesdays. And so on.
To prevent people from potentially stealing others' identities, he also installed fingerprint recognition machines at
supermarket entrances. During the peak of the shortage in 2017, many people survived by scavenging food from garbage. Out of humanitarian considerations, Colombia
opened its borders to Venezuelans, providing them with some supplies and food. But even with such a shortage of supplies and soaring prices, there was one thing that Venezuela had always kept very cheap, even the cheapest in the
world: gasoline. Note that it's not oil, but gasoline for cars. Why? It's not that
Venezuela has low oil production costs. As we just mentioned, its equipment is outdated, it lacks skilled workers, and it has almost no capacity to refine gasoline. It has to import all its gasoline. The reason it's so cheap is because the government has continuously invested heavily in subsidies, making it practically free. You can fill up your tank for just one dollar. But there's no such thing as a free lunch. Gasoline is
practically free, so everyone rushes to fill up. The cost is transformed from money into waiting time. So many people just sit there waiting in line every day. Let me tell you, if you go to Venezuela—but I do
n't recommend it—you'll see a long line of cars on the roadside, queuing up all day long, almost without moving. This isn't just traffic; they're queuing for
gas. Even in Caracas, the capital, the
wait is relatively short, averaging 5-6 hours. In many places, the wait can be several days, even a week. People basically sit in their cars queuing during the day, then lock their cars and go home to sleep when the gas stations close at night,
only to return the next day to queue again. Of course, there are market-
based gas stations that charge international fuel prices, so there aren't queues there. But most Venezuelans have become accustomed to this free gasoline, so they still queue. Think about it, this isn't just a single gas
station or a few cities; it's a nationwide phenomenon. What a huge waste of resources! Queues at supermarkets, queues at gas stations—
countless people are queuing every moment across the country. And what's even more problematic is that such a large subsidy leads to smuggling. Many people smuggle
this cheap gasoline to neighboring Brazil or Colombia to sell. It's estimated that the value exceeds $10 billion
annually, exacerbating the already severe gasoline shortage. Hearing this, you might be thinking, "When fuel prices were high, the government had so much money it was overflowing, so you wanted to subsidize it. That's understandable. But now the economy is like this..." With
such a severe government fiscal deficit, why bother with subsidies? Just stop subsidizing!
The Maduro government isn't unwilling, it's afraid. People have become accustomed to this near-free gasoline. If you liberalize it, the price could increase hundreds or thousands of times, triggering strong public discontent, anger, and
protests. The Maduro
regime is already unstable, so they have no choice but to continue subsidies. But the increased discontent is a problem, and now there's another layer of pressure: US
sanctions. Since 2006, the US has imposed limited sanctions on some Venezuelan individuals, including Chavez himself. Starting in 2014, the US stated that the Venezuelan
government had human rights abuses, undermined democracy, manipulated elections, etc., and
therefore imposed increased sanctions. Gradually, the sanctions evolved from targeting
individuals to sanctioning the entire country. Especially after Trump took office in his first term, he refused to recognize Maduro as president or the regime. The US, along with dozens of other countries,
imposed very strong and comprehensive economic sanctions on Venezuela. The biggest blows
came from sanctions on the oil industry and financing transactions, freezing the assets of the national oil company, prohibiting the US from buying its oil, and restricting the Venezuelan government. All
financing activities of oil companies were affected. Sanctions on the oil industry prevented the Venezuelan government from earning money, and restrictions on
financing
prevented them from borrowing. In short, Venezuela was deprived of funds. On one hand, there were US sanctions; on the other hand, its extraction capacity had severely declined after the major strike. As a result, Venezuelan oil production plummeted by 90% after 2015. At this time,
Venezuela's government debt was increasing, and the deficit was growing larger. In 2017, the
government selectively defaulted on its foreign debt. Maduro had to activate his backup plan, the last thing economists wanted to see:
he started printing money. We've discussed before how
Zimbabwe's currency
depreciated too quickly, adding
zeros too rapidly, forcing the continuous introduction of new currencies. Venezuela was similar. Its previous currency was called the Bolivar. Due to severe depreciation, in 2008, three zeros were removed, and a new currency called the
"Strong Bolivar" was
introduced. It was said that 1 Strong
Bolivar = 1000 Bolivars. Initially, one US dollar was equal to 2.15 bolivars. Later, it gradually depreciated to 10 bolivars per dollar. You might think this
rate of depreciation is acceptable, but let me tell you, this is just the official exchange rate. The black market rate had already reached
10,000 bolivars per dollar. Because the black market was so rampant, the official exchange rate had to follow suit, falling to 4 million bolivars per dollar by August 2018. What to do? They rounded down five zeros and introduced a new currency unit called the "Sovereign Bolivar," with one
Sovereign Bolivar equal to 100,000 bolivars. By 2019, Venezuela's
inflation
had exceeded 300,000%, meaning 30,000 yuan today would be equivalent to one yuan next year. So in 2020, they introduced a new currency called the "Digital Bolivar," rounding down six zeros from the Sovereign Bolivar. Does
n't that sound like a tongue twister? The current exchange rate is approximately
325 digital bolivars per dollar. If we use 2000... The original version of the bolivar, if you add
14 zeros after the
325, becomes 3.25 trillion bolivars. You don't need much economic knowledge to imagine that when prices rise to this level, the
economy is essentially paralyzed. Everyone's money is burning their hands; they just want to spend it as quickly as possible. You
don't care about price; you buy toilet paper whenever you see it, hoarding it if you can. Forget about investment and production. Historically, once a country falls into this vortex of hyperinflation, it's very difficult to stop or escape. But look at Venezuela's hyperinflation; it miraculously came down in
2020. Why? I'll tell you, it's not miraculous at all. Venezuelans completely abandoned their own currency. Strong bolivar, sovereign bolivar—even if you gave me a
"super invincible bolivar," I would
n't
believe it. The entire country began using the US dollar for transactions on a large
scale, becoming dollarized. Now, when you
walk into a restaurant, a roadside stall, or a supermarket, most prices are in US dollars. The numerical bolivar
hardly circulates at all. And you should know that the US dollar is not even the official currency in Venezuela. Therefore,
US dollar bills are extremely rare; you simply can't withdraw them from ATMs, especially small change. This leads to a rather amusing phenomenon: for example, if you go to a restaurant and spend $13,
don't expect the
restaurant to give you the two dollars in change. You just order a few more things to make it $15, and everyone's happy. So now, US dollar payment apps like Zelle and PayPal are very common in Venezuela. In other words, a large number of transactions in
Venezuela are actually
completed between US banks.
You see, the Venezuelan
banks and government are
quite helpless. In the last decade, over 8 million people have fled Venezuela—more than a quarter of its population. They all left in just a few years, including many talented people, wealthy individuals, and students. Everyone who could leave did. Originally, the problems of corruption and economic structure were
n't entirely unsolvable,
but
now that people are gone, it's an irreversible loss. The long-term impact
on Venezuela is devastating. Many people earn less than $10 a month, which is simply not enough to make ends meet. Most of them rely on relatives abroad. Sending money to make a living:
Many of these people are
descendants of people who immigrated to Venezuela in the 1950s and 60s, full of hope. Who knew that after so many
years of ups and downs, their
children would now be forced to flee the country? This wave of immigration has also led to hundreds of thousands of
Venezuelan immigrants being accepted by South American countries like Colombia, Brazil, Peru, and Argentina in the past two years. This has indeed taken away many jobs in the short term, causing considerable instability throughout South America. Therefore, this wave of immigration
can be considered one of the most significant crises South America has faced recently. In 2020, the country's GDP fell to
only 15% of what it was ten years ago, even lower than the level
in 1980. However, after our analysis,
you can probably see that the high GDP a decade ago didn't mean the economy was booming. The recent economic collapse isn't just a problem of the last ten years, nor is it solely the fault of the Maduro-Chávez government; it's a concentrated eruption of
various deep-seated problems accumulated
over the past century. In fact, if you look at Venezuelan urban development, it's not like many African countries where people are simply
poor; you
can see that it was wealthy before. But in the last
10 years, the government has indeed run out of money. Basically, the management of public order and public welfare is in a semi-hands-off, semi-laissez-faire state. The overall public security is very bad. So, starting a few years ago, many countries' officials advised their citizens not to travel to Venezuela because it's dangerous. There's an area called
Petare in the Venezuelan capital. You see the walls painted in beautiful, colorful colors, but in reality, it's one of the largest slums in
Latin America, housing over 2 million people. The houses on several hills are extremely densely packed, one next to another. There isn't
even a stable supply of water, electricity, or sewage systems. It looks peaceful during the day because everyone is either sleeping or working in the city. But at night, it becomes a haven for gangsters and one of the regions with the highest crime and murder rates in the world. I think even the most daring social media
bloggers would need several experienced guides,
travel in groups, and stay in their cars before daring to go there. And even after
you leave
this slum, the security situation in the capital, Caracas, isn't very good either. If you're not careful and wander around in places you shouldn't be, Oops, you'll be broke. If you're
driving in its capital... You'll find that at
night, the traffic lights are basically just for show; nobody cares. Everyone just
runs across the red light. Why? It's not that everyone
in Venezuela is a thug or wants to break the law. It's mainly because the security situation there is so
bad. A couple of years ago, there was a shooting incident where people were moving forward to turn off the
light. People were too afraid to even look at the train until it disappeared from view. When the light turned off,
people just ignored it.
The whole city, the whole country, is basically in a state of complete traffic freedom. Take the subway, for example. At first glance, it seems much better than the New York subway. It was
built in the early 2000s when Venezuela was particularly wealthy. But now, the government has neither the ability nor the resources to operate the subway. The entire Caracas subway is free. It does
n't have
automatic ticket checking; it's all about skill. If you can squeeze on, you sit down. There's no air conditioning.
Venezuela relies on hydroelectric power stations
built more than half a century ago to support the electricity needs of the entire nation. However, due to a lack of
talent, poor maintenance, and a
lack of alternative energy
sources... Power outages occur almost every two or three days, especially in 2019 when a
nationwide mega-scale blackout lasted for a week, costing over $
10 billion. More than $100 million was discovered during a congressional investigation, and over 14 thermal power plants were found to be inoperable. You can imagine the extent of corruption involved. Having made so many videos analyzing national economies, I've
found that you can't just look at
research reports and economic data. If we only focus on economic analysis, we might develop some misconceptions about the
lives of people in that country. Actually,
you can look at videos of people living their lives at that time, from the perspective of happiness indexes and their expressed emotions. It might not be as dire or unfortunate as people imagine based on
economic data. The many
economic problems we just mentioned do exist; Venezuela
's economy is indeed a
mess. But South Americans are incredibly
optimistic, easygoing, and know how to enjoy life. They complain about wages, the capital, and the
government in a chaotic manner, and their communication rate is high. However, it's not that everyone is tense and afraid
to go out. Everyone
should just go about their business,
work or go to school. If you see a gang doing business somewhere, just avoid it. Don't stop at
red lights. In recent years, with Venezuela's complete dollar-backed economy, the inflation problem has gradually improved. The extreme economic phenomenon has forced Venezuela to abandon its "economic package" approach. Supermarket shelves are overflowing, but market prices mean Venezuelan goods are more expensive than those in Miami. Real wages are still lower than
50 years ago. Gangs demand protection money, and police frequently collect "tolls." The whole country has fallen into a jungle law mentality, somewhat like a semi-anarchy.
After Maduro's arrest, the US is likely more focused on
Venezuela's oil and economic stability, and less likely on developing its overall economy. Its
overall economic structure is
essentially in
shock therapy. An
economy that failed to utilize its oil resources when it was resource-rich and had sufficient income is a prime example of this. Instead, it fostered government corruption, allowed domestic productivity to decline, and exacerbated economic imbalances. Meanwhile, government policies such as price
controls,
foreign exchange controls, and interest
rate controls were like drinking poison to quench thirst, leading to hyperinflation. It's like a child who isn't fully mature; they make mistakes. But if they start with astronomical wealth, the corrective mechanism is
likely to fail. Small economic imbalances, minor corruption, and small price distortions,
without timely feedback in an environment of continuous wealth inflow, will stray further and further from the right path. By the time they are critically ill, a sudden drop in oil prices will
trigger a vicious cycle, making it difficult to recover. Therefore, sometimes having
too much money and spending it in the wrong places can be more
fatal than
having no money at all. As the former Venezuelan Energy Minister, also known as the father of OPEC,
said,
oil will bring us destruction;
it is the devil's excrement,
perhaps a kind of
Venezuelan excrement.