Today we're going to talk about a country that
can be considered one of the biggest economic disasters in modern human history:
Venezuela.
As the country with the world's largest oil reserves, it started with a hand of
"two kings and four twos,"
yet its GDP plummeted by 80% in less than a decade.
According to UN estimates, by
2024, 82% of the population will
live below the poverty line. The
capital, Caracas, has an entire mountain of slums, and it boasts one of the
highest murder rates in the world.
In this country where gas is practically free,
even basic necessities like toilet paper, food, and medicine are in
extreme shortage.
Supermarkets are so crowded that you have to be queuing to buy groceries, checking the
last digit of your ID card, and they
have very strict armed security. For over a
decade, Venezuela has been mired in hyperinflation, where
money is weighed by the pound. The
rate of currency devaluation is
outrageous!
If you stacked 100-bolivar bills from 20 years ago one by
one and
physically filled the entire Bird's Nest stadium—
or even
40 Bird's Nest stadiums—how much would that be
worth? It's only enough to
buy a McDonald's hamburger, and
you can't even get fries and a soda,
etc.—these are some of the most horrific concepts.  It
turns out that all these factors have manifested in this one country.
So don't think
we're talking about Venezuela today just
because it's a political hotspot.
Let's take a look at
how it managed to turn such a promising situation into this.
Venezuela
is a country on the northern coast of South America, with a
land area of ​​approximately 910,000 square kilometers, slightly
larger than the three northeastern provinces of China combined. It
currently has a population of about 28 million. Originally, the population was
mainly composed of indigenous Indians.
From the 16th century onwards, it was
ruled by the Spanish for nearly 300 years,
so it still speaks Spanish.
It gained independence in 1830, becoming one of the first countries in
South America to break free from Spanish rule. However, the
key factor that truly influenced its development wasn't
independence or
colonization,
but something else entirely. In
1914,
Venezuela drilled its first commercial oil well and
discovered oil.
In the following 21 years,
it transformed from an unknown country
into the world's second-largest oil producer, second
only to the United States.
We often say that oil is black gold.
This windfall made
Venezuela's then-dictator,
Gómez, the
richest man in all of Latin America.  In
our previous episode on oil, we discussed how, in the
early days, global oil resources were
monopolized by seven British and American oil companies,
known as the "Seven Sisters,"
forming a cartel.
Venezuela's share was distributed among
three of these:
Gulf Oil,
Standard Oil,
and Shell.
Initially,
these three had considerable influence,
as the technology for extracting and transporting oil was relatively scarce.
Venezuela,
being a small, inland country,
could only receive a small share of the oil profits.
However, after World War II,
these oil-producing nations
began to realize something was
amiss. "
So many companies can extract oil,
but only I possess
this resource. This is the
scarcest and most valuable resource.
I am the rightful owner!
What are you Seven Sisters doing, acting so arrogantly?"
Thus,
Venezuela rallied other Middle Eastern oil-producing nations to
negotiate with the Seven Sisters,
signing the famous 50/50 revenue-sharing agreement.
Simply put, "
I let you extract oil here, and we'll split the profits 50/50."
Later, Venezuela, along with four other Middle Eastern countries,
established OPEC.
This significantly boosted Venezuela's government revenue, making
its goldmine even larger.  In
just five years,
government revenue increased sixfold.
But the real golden age was yet to
come; the
previous wealth was
merely a drop in the ocean. In
1973, the Yom Kippur War broke out,
also known as the "Fourth Middle East War."
Arab countries in the Middle East joined forces to
impose an oil embargo on the West,
plunging the world into an oil shortage. Oil
prices quadrupled in a short period,
from $3 to $12 per barrel—the
first oil crisis. A
few years later, in 1979, the
second oil crisis erupted, with
oil prices soaring to $35 per barrel—ten times higher than
ten years earlier! This
led to global inflation and
economic stagnation.
But for Venezuela, it was a
windfall—a
huge windfall! Venezuela was likely the biggest beneficiary of
these two consecutive oil crises.
It's an oil-exporting country, has
little connection to the Middle East, and is very close
to the United States. Furthermore, in
1976, the Venezuelan government
fully nationalized its oil industry,
establishing its own state-owned oil company, PDVSA.
If the previous oil prices
were a gold mine for it,
this one was a...  In a
mere 10 years,
Venezuela's GDP increased sixfold.
The capital, Caracas,
saw the construction of South America's most modern highways,
skyscrapers, and university towns. State-owned
enterprises
expanded rapidly, employing 300,000 people. Waiters were everywhere – in
elevators,
public bathrooms,
office doors – a
single job. The
government had plenty of money. Meanwhile,
private enterprises shrank further.
But that didn't matter;
even if large companies weren't profitable,
government subsidies sustained them. The
Venezuelan bolivar
became one of the world's strongest currencies
due to its extremely strong exchange rate.
At the time, Venezuela's middle class
would even travel to Miami on weekends to shop. As long as
oil prices remained high, the
Venezuelan government had a continuous supply of resources.
As long as oil prices remained high,
every citizen could relax and
enjoy high wages and welfare.
As long as oil prices remained high, there was
enough incentive to keep the
entire economy at the top of the world.
No economic problem seemed insignificant. However, this golden age didn't last. In the
1980s, international oil prices began to plummet. Initially, the
Venezuelan government hoped
this was just a temporary setback,
so although government revenue began to decline...
Instead of cutting back on redundant government spending, Venezuela
opted for massive debt issuance,
hoping that a rise in oil prices would allow it to recover quickly.
However, this was naive;
it was merely the beginning of a nightmare.
To combat high inflation,
the US announced interest rate hikes, and
capital began to flee Latin American markets. In
1982, Mexico couldn't hold on any longer and
declared it unable to repay its foreign debt,
officially triggering the Latin American debt crisis.
Venezuela was also severely affected. On
February 18, 1983,
the president announced a devaluation
of the bolivar
from 4.3
to 7.5 US dollars
and implemented foreign exchange controls.
Given that Venezuela relied heavily on imports, the price of almost everything
it bought
nearly doubled in an instant.
This day
became known as Venezuela's
"Black Friday."
Venezuela quickly plunged into an economic crisis,
and oil prices further collapsed in 1986,
plummeting from $27 to less than $10.
What Venezuela never expected was that
oil prices would fall from this low level...  After
nearly 20 years of continuous turmoil,
Venezuela's inflation began to rise.
The government tried price controls and foreign exchange controls,
but they were ineffective.
Corruption was too rampant, and
many policies simply could not be effectively implemented.
Moreover, many of these policies were counterproductive,
further pushing up prices in Venezuela.
We will analyze this in more detail when the situation worsens.
The government realized that various control policies were not working, and
in 1989, a new president
named Perez was elected. He
went to the other extreme,
completely deregulating the market. Foreign
exchange, interest rates, and prices were allowed to
fluctuate as they pleased.
The government stopped subsidies, and state-owned
enterprises were privatized.
This period is also known as the "Great Adjustment Period." Those who
frequently read our content should be familiar with this kind of
extreme market liberalization ideology, which was extremely popular in the 1990s,
mainly promoted by the United States.
At that time, it wasn't just in Latin America, but also in
Southeast Asia,
and later in Russia and Poland with shock therapy.
It believed that the market could solve all problems on its own.
From an economic theory perspective,
market-oriented and liberalized reforms are
not inherently problematic. The
problem is that these policies were a bit
too radical.  The
sudden abandonment of all control had a
devastating short-term impact on the economy.
More importantly,
this laissez-faire approach to market competition
has a prerequisite: a
basic business environment and a sound
legal framework. But
what was Venezuela's situation at the time?
Market rules were vague,
regulation was virtually nonexistent,
many laws were ineffective,
and then the government suddenly stopped intervening.
Food price subsidies, energy subsidies, and the
minimum wage all disappeared.
This inevitably worsened the domestic economy, leading to
numerous protests and riots. The
bolivar began to plummet. As
we just mentioned, on Black Friday in 1983,
one dollar was worth 7.5 bolivars;
by 1993, it
had fallen to 100 bolivars. In
1994, a
major banking crisis occurred, with more than half of the banks,
including its second-largest,
collapsing. The
corruption within the government and financial sector was
now fully exposed.
President Perez,
for embezzling 250 million bolivars from the National Liberty Fund,
became the first president to be impeached by the Supreme Court. The
Finance Minister was also forced to resign.
This marked the complete failure of the "Great Adjustment" era.  When
the tide went out,
everyone suddenly realized that
almost everyone was swimming naked.
This financial crisis, which
many people might have glossed over,
actually had a more direct
impact on Venezuela's economy
than the problems we just discussed. It was like a
heavy punch to Venezuela's jaw, causing it to collapse instantly.
Speaking of which,
I guess you've probably sensed from our conversation that
Venezuelan politics is quite chaotic. Just
look at how frequently its name has changed.
When it gained independence in 1830, it was
called the
States of Venezuela.
Later, it was renamed the Republic
of Venezuela.
Less than ten years
later, seeing the Americans to the north with a better
system, they
fought a war and
changed the name to the
United States of Venezuela.
Then, after World War II, it changed back to the
Republic of Venezuela. And
then, you see, it
has to change again.
Although its system has been basically democratic elections, these
elections are
often invalid or heavily manipulated. There
are also many different forces vying for power within the government,
so every president's
position is far from secure.  They
have to balance the interests of various interest groups, constantly worry about being
overthrown in a coup,
attract votes, and of
course, gain personal benefits.
This inevitably leads to many problems.
But I believe that in the long run,
a fundamental problem
is that its leadership is incapable of long-term investment and
long-term planning. Let me give you
a simple example: do you think
Venezuelan leaders
don't understand that oil prices will fluctuate and
won't rise forever? The
simplest way to prevent this is to
establish a national fund, like Norway, to save money
when oil prices are high and buy
gold or
foreign bonds—is that
so difficult? Didn't the
Venezuelan government think of this?
Actually, it's not that they haven't tried,
but these presidents gradually realized that
every time they tried to save money, it only
became a cash cow for the next few presidents. The
dramatic changes in power, coupled
with rampant corruption, made
any long-term investment
almost impossible. Note that
I'm referring to long-term investment
not only investments with returns, but
also institutional investments,
such as investing in anti-corruption
efforts and establishing transparent and fair mechanisms.
This is very difficult in Venezuela,
so generally, successive presidents...  The most direct and
effective policy he could implement was
subsidies.
This kind of short-term, quick-return approach
garnered public support.
From this perspective,
look at the Middle East—
Saudi Arabia, Qatar, the UAE—these
are centralized monarchies.
While they have many problems stemming from their power,
they can indeed take a longer-term view and
make many long-term investments.
After all, this isn't just for the country, but also
for their own future
and their descendants.
Look at their visionary plans, right? They
might even be a bit too willing to invest long-term. In short,
Venezuelan politics is quite chaotic. Let's go back to the
timeline. In the
1980s and 1990s, with
low oil prices,
Venezuela's GDP
didn't grow for 15 years. The
economy stagnated, struggling with
high inflation.
The people increasingly hoped for
a major reform. Against
this historical backdrop, in
1999,
Venezuela's most famous president
and most controversial leader came to power:
Hugo Chávez.
Chávez himself had a military background and led
a very authoritarian government.
He advocated so-called "21st-century socialism," which
later became...  The
"United Socialist Party of Venezuela" had
very close ties with Cuba and a
very close relationship with Castro.
On several occasions,
he would fly over to celebrate Castro's birthday with him for several days.
In fact, Chavez
had attempted to overthrow the existing regime in 1992,
though unsuccessfully,
but he gained significant public support.
Later, in the 1997 election,
he advocated for large-scale reforms to
change the status quo and
eliminate corruption.
Imagine, the people, utterly disillusioned with the corrupt government,
certainly hoped for a strong leader
to change the status quo.
Thus, Chavez came to power forcefully and remained president of Venezuela
until his death from cancer in 2013. What did
Chavez do
first upon taking office? He
changed the country's name
from "Republic of Venezuela" to
"Bolivarian Republic of Venezuela."
He said he would carry out a thorough reform,
calling it the "Bolivarian Revolution."
You see, they seem to really like "Bolivarian," right? It's the
country's name, and even the
currency. The
Bolivar is
actually a name associated with a great general who
helped South America gain independence
from Spanish rule in the 19th century,
so he has a symbolic meaning of independence and
patriotism.
Chávez believed that
Venezuela's previous chaos was
mainly due to the
encroachment of evil foreign capitalism.
They were trying to turn the wealth earned from Venezuela's oil resources into
their own profits.
Inflation was
not a natural economic phenomenon;
it was the work of evil capitalism, the machinations of
hostile forces, their conspiracy.
Therefore, he
implemented a series of sweeping reforms to public ownership. All
key industries,
such as banking, infrastructure, transportation, electricity, and communications, were
nationalized,
while taxes on foreign companies were increased.
This scared away most foreign investment.
In 2001, he passed the Land Law,
allowing the state to expropriate land and
encouraging the establishment of small cooperatives at the grassroots level,
providing them with financial and technical support
as an alternative to a market economy.
Chávez also
successfully brought the previously independent central bank under
government control through several legislations.
From then on, the government could decide how much money to print.
This actually foreshadowed the subsequent hyperinflation.
And of all Chávez's nationalization efforts, the
most important one, which I haven't mentioned yet,
is oil.
Are you wondering why? Did
n't we just mention...?
The oil industry
was nationalized in 1976, and the
National Oil Company (PDC) was established.
Although theoretically state-owned,
Venezuela
was heavily reliant on foreign technology and capital, giving the
West considerable influence; it was
even considered a
"state within a state."
Chávez felt it was a disgrace that the
nation's lifeline, the oil company,
was controlled by the Americans and British, who were also taking a large
cut of the profits.
So, in 2002,
he placed trusted individuals on the
PDC's board of directors
to control him.
He appeared weekly on a television program
called "Hello, Mr. President."
On April 7th,
he used a whistle to
read out the
names of high-ranking PDC executives who opposed him, firing them each time he blew the
whistle.
This escalated,
leading to a brief military coup
attempt to depose Chávez, which he
suppressed. In late
2002,
PDC employees
staged a massive strike, bringing
oil production to a near standstill, dropping
from 3 million barrels per day.  The
daily output of oil fell to less than 300,000 barrels,
which was equivalent to the
entire country's engine stopping.
This strike,
conservatively estimated,
brought Venezuela an economic loss of $10 billion,
causing its GDP to decline by 27% in the first quarter of 2003.
But these short-term economic losses were relatively minor; the
more fatal were the long-term losses.
Chavez's response was very tough: "
You're on strike? You're not
working?
Fine, you don't need to come anymore. Fire everyone!" He
laid off nearly 20,000 employees at once.
You might not think that many now,
but for the Venezuelan state oil company at the time, it meant
almost half of its workforce was laid off. And
think about it, this
was different from typical layoffs. Usually, layoffs
are selective, targeting those who can be laid off
easily.
But at that time, they targeted those who took to the streets. No matter
what you were, if you
held key technologies or were in a
key position,
if you took to the streets, you were out. This
resulted in the layoff of many very core technical personnel.
After this turmoil,
Chavez did indeed successfully
control the state oil company,
but he also paid a very heavy price.
Not only did external technology withdraw...  The strike
also resulted in the dismissal of a large portion of
Venezuela's technical backbone, causing Venezuela's oil technology to
regress by more than a decade. Both
management and technical capabilities have
declined drastically.
With aging equipment and
technology loss, more than
20 years later,
its extraction capacity is less than
half of its peak before the strike. The
oil is simply sitting there, ready to be extracted, but it just can't be extracted. After only a
couple of digs,
it starts to tire and has to
rest for half a day.
Many American oil giants, including ExxonMobil,
either had their assets forcibly seized
or were forced to accept new contracts in the period that followed. It's important to
understand that the
vast area of ​​refineries in the Gulf of Mexico were
designed specifically for Venezuelan heavy oil.
This disruption is
n't just about a few barrels of oil lost in the short term; it means that for
decades to come,
these newly heavily invested refineries
will face a "famine"—they
won't have oil to refine and will
have to rely on Canadian heavy oil as a substitute.
Therefore, as we analyzed before, the
US's sudden attack on Venezuela
must have had a significant reason: it's not just
because Venezuela has a large quantity of oil,
but because it's all heavy oil that meets the standards for US refineries.
Well, things are starting to get complicated.
Let's lay some groundwork first.
I'll give you some basic information to
explain
why oil-rich countries like Venezuela
struggle to escape the so-called "oil curse."
It's not as
simple as money leading to corruption.
You see,
abundant natural resources
lead to exports,
generating huge amounts of US dollars.
Then, these
dollars are converted into the Bolivar,
causing its currency to appreciate continuously. With
currency appreciation,
domestically produced goods
become more expensive and less competitive compared to other countries.
Meanwhile,
goods from other countries become cheaper, leading Venezuela to
favor imports.
This significantly weakens
Venezuela's domestic agriculture and manufacturing sectors,
causing them to gradually decline.
So, over time, from a
national perspective,
its economic model becomes a
relentless pursuit of oil exports
and the purchase of other goods.
You see,
over 95% of its exports are oil, while
over 80% of its industrial raw materials and
over 60% of its food
are imported.
Its domestic manufacturing and agriculture decline, and the service
sector becomes the dominant industry.
It's like a rich kid who,
because God has given them so much, ca
n't help but become corrupt.
This phenomenon has a specific term in economics:
"Dutch Disease," named after a similar situation that occurred in the
Netherlands in the 1960s.
However, I think it should actually be called
"Venezuelan Disease."
In reality, if this so-called disease
could continue indefinitely, it would
n't be a major problem;
I could just keep selling oil to make money
and buy other things. The
key issue is that
the country's industrial capacity has deteriorated; it
can't produce anything of its own, meaning the
economy has lost its immunity.
A slight disturbance can cause it to collapse.
This is why the
drop in oil prices in the 1980s
had such a severe impact on Venezuela's economy.
You might normally think, "If oil prices
drop,
you'll just earn less, it won't
cause a collapse."
Why?
Because its non-oil sectors
have lost their capacity and
completely deteriorated.
And the key to all this
is the exchange rate.
Look at how Chavez messed with the oil companies;
foreign investors
naturally avoided the country and
withdrew completely. The
domestic population also lacked confidence
in the country's economy and
currency.
They would try to exchange their money for
US dollars, leading to a
continuous depreciation of the Bolivar and a
continuous rise in prices.
Faced with these two classic economic difficulties,
Chavez's response was
remarkably simple and brutal. The
exchange rate was falling?
No way!
I set an official exchange rate.
Prices were rising? No way!
I set a price ceiling.
This method of distorting supply and demand did
maintain Venezuela's purchasing power to some extent,
but at the cost of further deterioration of its productivity, further distortion of its
economic structure, further
growth of corruption and the black market, increased capital
flight, and greater shortages of
goods.
At this point, Venezuela was terminally
ill.
However,
things didn't deteriorate rapidly; instead,
life in Venezuela gradually improved.
Why?
Because oil prices rebounded,
and this time the rise was even more dramatic. In early
2000, the
global economy experienced a boom,
oil demand surged, and
oil prices increased sixfold in seven years.
Venezuela's goldmine returned.
With this influx of abundant dollars, the entire economy
returned to the prosperous state of the 1970s.
Chavez,
instead of using this respite
to build a reserve fund, spent
heavily on subsidies,
providing almost free electricity and water to the public.
Almost free oil,
very cheap food, and generous housing subsidies.
He also
established thousands of free medical clinics for the poor.
At the time, gasoline in Venezuela was
even cheaper than bottled water;
$100 worth of gasoline was
enough to drive around the world several times over. The
government became increasingly large and
bloated, with about a quarter of
Venezuela's working population
employed in government.
Although the economic structure was unbalanced and
basic necessities had to be imported, it
didn't matter, as
oil prices continued to rise, and
people had more money.
Under Chavez's leadership, people's lives
improved again. The
country's GDP
quadrupled in just ten years.
Venezuela was gradually eliminating poverty, and its
urbanization rate reached 90%, the
highest in South America.
At this rate, it
could soon once again become one of the
world's richest countries.
To encourage borrowing,
Chavez even set a cap on interest rates. The message was:
borrow more,
spend more,
invest more,
don't save. The
highest interest rate for credit cards at the time
was 29%, which
may sound very high,
but you have to know that
Venezuela's inflation rate at the time
was 30%.  50%
means that
its loan interest rate is lower than the inflation rate; the
real interest rate has always been negative.
After you borrow money, the
amount you actually have to repay decreases,
so saving money results in increasingly lower returns.
Naturally, everyone borrows money
instead of saving. This
led to a consumer frenzy in Venezuela.
People used their wages to buy
cars, appliances, luxury goods, and travel
abroad.
Many people bought cars not to drive, but as an
investment;
as long as they could get a car loan, they would
buy one without hesitation. The real
estate bubble was even worse.
This negative real interest rate
accelerated the entire economy, making
capital turnover faster
and faster.
A very interesting consumer trend emerged:
cosmetic surgery. Venezuela
became one of the countries in the Americas most fond of cosmetic surgery.
Many women considered it an essential step in their
coming-of-age ceremony.
Families with the means
would prepare money for their daughters' cosmetic surgery.
Now, there's a social consensus
that cosmetic surgery is a
"necessary path" to better career opportunities and higher social status. After all, with
such high inflation, saving
money is impossible,
but cosmetic surgery is a
long-term investment in one's life.
You should know that!
Venezuela is a global beauty pageant powerhouse,
arguably even the strongest in the world. It boasts the most wins in the
four major global beauty pageants,
earning it the nickname "Land of Beauties."
It has a very comprehensive beauty pageant system.
Not only does it have the highest-level "Miss Venezuela" title, but
every city, community,
and even school
has its own beauty pageant,
forming a
complete beauty selection mechanism. This has
naturally led to the rise of
a related industry chain including beauty pageant training and cosmetic surgery.
Okay, let's lighten the mood a bit and get back to the
main point. In
2013, Hugo Chávez died of cancer.
During his 14 years in power,
oil prices initially climbed steadily,
then fluctuated at high levels.
He used the wealth generated by oil to directly improve the
lives of Venezuelans. However,
some fundamental economic problems,
such as structural issues,
corruption, and
government inefficiency, continued to worsen
under the nourishment of the oil boom.
His successor, Nicolás Maduro,
also from the United Socialist Party, was
not so lucky.
Almost immediately after taking office, before he even had a chance to settle in,
oil prices began to plummet.
Venezuela's good days are
over. The
crisis of the 1980s is
essentially repeating itself,
only this time with even greater intensity.
Its economic structure and inefficient state-owned enterprises
simply cannot support domestic demand.
Most necessities rely on imports, a constant stream of
overseas purchases.
But with oil prices falling, Venezuela has run
out of money and can no longer afford these goods. In
five years,
Venezuela's imports have
plummeted to one-sixth of their previous levels,
plunging the country into severe shortages.
By 2015,
due to severe shortages
and government price controls to
prevent price increases,
many food items,
including toilet paper, were
snapped up as soon as they hit the shelves.
Many supermarkets had to be fenced off with iron bars and patrolled with
armed security personnel to
prevent excessive riots
or "zero-dollar purchases."
You'd think there were some treasures inside!
Eventually, the lines in front of supermarkets
became so long and chaotic that
the government implemented a quota system for supermarket visits, based on the
last digit of your ID card.
For example, those with IDs ending in 0 or 1
could go to the supermarket on Mondays.
2 and 3 are Tuesdays, and
so on.
To prevent
identity theft,
they also installed fingerprint recognition machines at supermarket entrances.
During the peak of the shortage in 2017,
many people survived by scavenging food from garbage.
Out of humanitarian concern,
Colombia opened its borders
to Venezuelans, providing some supplies
and food.
But even with such shortages and
soaring prices, there's one thing that
Venezuela has always had very low prices,
even the lowest in the world:
gasoline.
Note, not oil, but
gasoline for cars.
Why? It's
not that Venezuela has
low oil production costs. As
we just mentioned,
its equipment is outdated, and it
lacks skilled workers, so it has
almost no gasoline refining capacity and
has to import gasoline. It's
so cheap
because the government continuously subsidizes it heavily,
practically making it free.
A dollar can fill up a tank.
But there's no such thing as a free lunch.
Gasoline is practically free, so
everyone rushes to fill up. The
cost
shifts from money to waiting time—
queueing.
So many people just sit there all day.
I'm telling you,
if you go to Venezuela—
but I don't recommend it—
you'll see
a long line of cars queuing all day
long.
Almost motionless.
This isn't a traffic jam;
they're just queuing for gas.
In Caracas, the capital, it's considered relatively mild, with an
average wait of 5-6 hours. In
many places, the wait can be several days,
even a week.
People basically sit in their cars queuing during the day,
then lock their cars and go home to sleep when the gas stations close at night, only to return
the next day to queue again.
Of course, there are market-based gas
stations that charge international fuel prices, and there are
n't queues there,
but the vast majority of Venezuelans have become
accustomed to this free gasoline,
so they still queue.
Think about it,
this isn't just a single gas station
or a few cities;
it's a nationwide phenomenon. What a
huge waste of resources! Queues at
supermarkets, queues at gas stations—
countless people are queuing every moment across the country.
And what's even more problematic is that
such a large subsidy leads to
smuggling.
Many people smuggle this cheap gasoline
to neighboring Brazil
or Colombia to
sell.
It's estimated that the
value exceeds $10 billion annually,
exacerbating the already severe gasoline shortage.
Hearing this, you might be thinking, "
When fuel prices were high, the
government had so much money it was overflowing, so
you could easily subsidize it.
That's understandable. But
now the economy is like this..."  With
such a severe government fiscal deficit, why bother with
subsidies?
Just stop subsidizing! The
Maduro government is
n't unwilling, it's afraid.
People have become accustomed to
this near-free gasoline.
If you liberalize it,
the price could increase hundreds or thousands of times,
triggering strong public discontent, anger, and protests. The
Maduro regime is already unstable,
so they have no choice but to continue subsidies.
And what's more troublesome is the
added layer of pressure:
US sanctions.
Since 2006, the
US has imposed some small-scale sanctions on Venezuelan individuals,
including Chavez himself.
But since 2014,
the US has stated that the
Venezuelan government
has human rights abuses,
undermined democracy,
manipulated elections, etc., and will increase
sanctions.
Gradually, it has evolved from targeting individuals to
sanctioning the entire country.
Especially after Trump took office in his first term,
he refused to recognize Maduro as president or the regime. The
US, along with dozens of other countries,
imposed
very strong and comprehensive economic sanctions on Venezuela. The
biggest blows were
against the oil industry and financing transactions,
freezing the assets of the national oil company,
prohibiting the US from buying its oil,
and restricting the Venezuelan government.
All financing activities of oil companies were
affected. Sanctions on the oil industry
prevented the Venezuelan government from earning money, and
restrictions on financing prevented
them from borrowing. In short,
Venezuela was deprived of funds. On
one hand, there were US sanctions; on
the other hand,
its extraction capacity had severely declined after the major strike. As a result,
Venezuelan oil production
plummeted by 90% after 2015. At
this time, Venezuela's
government debt was increasing, and the deficit was growing
larger. In
2017, the
government selectively defaulted on its foreign debt.
Maduro had to activate his backup plan, the
last thing economists wanted to see:
he started the printing press.
We've discussed before how
Zimbabwe's
currency depreciated too quickly,
requiring the continuous introduction of new currencies.
Venezuela was similar.
Its previous currency
was called the Bolivar.
Due to severe depreciation,
in 2008, three zeros were removed, and
a new currency
called the "Strong Bolivar" was introduced.
That is, 1 Strong Bolivar = 1000 Bolivars.
Initially, one US dollar was equal to 2.15 bolivars.
Later, it gradually depreciated
to 10 bolivars per dollar.
You might think
this rate of depreciation is acceptable,
but let me tell you,
this is just the official exchange rate. The
black market rate
had already reached 10,000 bolivars per dollar.
Because the black market was so rampant, the
official exchange rate had to follow suit, falling to
4 million bolivars per dollar by August 2018.
What to do?
They rounded down five zeros and
introduced a new currency unit
called the "Sovereign Bolivar."
One Sovereign Bolivar equals 100,000 bolivars.
By 2019,
Venezuela's inflation
had exceeded 300,000%, meaning 30,000
yuan today would be
equivalent to one yuan next year.
So in 2020, they introduced a new currency
called the "Digital Bolivar,"
rounding down six zeros from the Sovereign Bolivar. Does
n't that sound like a tongue twister? The
current exchange rate is approximately
325 digital bolivars per dollar.
If we use 2000...  The
original version of the bolivar,
if you add 14 zeros after the 325,
becomes 3.25 trillion bolivars.
You don't need much economic knowledge to
imagine that
when prices rise to this level, the
economy is essentially paralyzed.
Everyone's money is burning their hands; they just want to
spend it as quickly as possible.
You don't care about prices;
you buy toilet paper if you see it,
hoard it if you can, and
forget about investment and production.
Historically, once a country falls into this vortex of hyperinflation, it
's very difficult to stop or escape.
But look at Venezuela's hyperinflation; it
miraculously dropped in 2020.
Why? Well, it's
not miraculous at all.
Venezuelans
completely abandoned their own currency.
Strong bolivar,
sovereign bolivar—
even if you gave me a "super invincible bolivar,"
I wouldn't believe it. The
entire country began
using the US dollar for transactions on a large scale,
becoming dollarized.
Now, when you walk into a restaurant, a
roadside stall, or a supermarket,
most prices are in US dollars. The
numerical bolivar
hardly circulates at all.
And you should know that the US
dollar is
not even the official currency in Venezuela.
Therefore, US dollar bills
are extremely rare;
you simply can't withdraw them from ATMs,
especially small change.
This leads to a rather amusing phenomenon:
for example, if you go to a restaurant and
spend $13,
don't expect the restaurant to give you the two dollars in change.
You just order a few more things to make it
$15, and
everyone's happy.
So now,
US dollar payment apps like Zelle and PayPal
are very common in Venezuela.
In other words, a
large number of transactions in Venezuela
are actually completed between US banks.
You see, the Venezuelan banks and
government are quite helpless.
In the last ten years,
over 8 million people have fled Venezuela—
more than a quarter of its population. They all
left in just a few years,
including many
talented people, wealthy individuals, and students. Everyone who could leave did.
Originally, the
problems of corruption and economic structure
weren't entirely unsolvable,
but now that people are gone, it's an
irreversible loss. The
long-term impact on Venezuela is
devastating.
Many people earn less than $10 a month;
less than $10 a month
is simply not enough to make ends meet.
Most of them
rely on relatives abroad.
Sending money to make a living:
Many of these people are descendants of immigrants who came to Venezuela in the 1950s and 60s
full of hope.
Who knew that after so many years of
ups and downs,
their children would now be
forced to flee the country?
This wave of
immigration has
led to hundreds of thousands of Venezuelan immigrants being accepted by
South American countries like Colombia,
Brazil, Peru, and Argentina in the past two years. This has
indeed taken away many jobs in the short term,
causing considerable instability throughout South America.
Therefore, this wave of immigration
can be considered one of the most significant crises South America has faced recently. In
2020, the
country's GDP
fell to only 15% of what it was ten years ago,
even lower than in 1980.
However, after our analysis,
you can probably see that the
high GDP a decade ago
didn't mean the economy was booming. The
recent economic collapse is
not just a problem of the last decade or so, nor is it solely the
fault of the Maduro and Chavez governments. It's a
concentrated eruption of various deep-seated problems accumulated over the past century.
In fact, if you look at Venezuelan urban development, it's
not like many African countries where poverty is the norm;
you can see that it was once wealthy.
But in the last 10 years, the
government has indeed run out of money.
Basically, the management of public order and
public welfare has become largely laissez-faire. Overall, public
security is terrible.
So, starting a few years ago,
many countries' officials
advised their citizens
not to travel to Venezuela, saying
it was too dangerous. There
's an area in the Venezuelan capital called Petare.
You see the walls painted in vibrant colors,
quite beautiful,
but in reality,
it's one of the largest slums in Latin America,
housing over 2 million people. The
houses on several hills are extremely densely packed, one
next to another. There's
no stable water or electricity supply,
and no sewage system. It
looks peaceful during the day
because everyone is either sleeping
or working in the city.
But at night,
it becomes a haven for gangs,
and one of the
areas with the highest crime and murder rates in the world. Even the
most daring social media bloggers
would need several experienced guides,
traveling in groups, and only dare to go there in a car. And
even after leaving the slum, the security situation
in the capital, Caracas, is
n't good either.
If you're not careful, you might
wander around in places you shouldn't be.
Oops
You'll be out of money. If you drive in its capital, you'll
find that at
night, the
traffic lights are basically useless;
nobody cares.
Everyone just runs red lights.
Why? It's
not that all Venezuelans are thugs or want to break the law. It's
mainly because the security situation is so bad. A
couple of years ago, there were
incidents of people being robbed or even shot while waiting at red lights. This has
led to people being afraid to linger and speeding through
red lights.
And the traffic police
simply don't care. The
whole city, the
whole country, is
basically in
a state of complete traffic freedom. Take the
subway, for example. At
first glance, it seems
much better than the New York subway.
It was
built in the early 2000s when Venezuela was particularly wealthy.
But now, the
government doesn't have the ability
or resources to operate the subway. The
entire Caracas subway is free. The
automatic ticket machines and fare gates are just for show, and the escalators are out of service. The
subway is still running,
but not frequently. Since it's
free,
people rely on their own
ability to squeeze on and sit down. There's
no air conditioning inside.
Venezuela
relies on hydroelectric power plants built over half a century ago
to power its entire population.
However, due to a lack of skilled workers,
poor maintenance, and a
lack of alternative energy sources, power
outages
occur frequently. In 2019, a massive nationwide blackout
lasted over a week, resulting in
at least 43 deaths.
Subsequent investigations revealed that over
$80 billion of the $100 billion invested in the power system by Congress had been
misappropriated, rendering over 14 thermal power plants inoperable.
This illustrates the extent of corruption involved. Having
made numerous videos analyzing national economies,
I've found that
you can't just rely on research reports and
economic data.
If we only focus on economic analysis, we
might develop misconceptions about the lives of the people in that country.
Instead, you should watch videos and vlogs made by people living there.
I've watched many of these,
observing how people there describe their lives.
I've come to a deep impression
that their lives,
from the
perspective of their happiness index and their expressed emotions, are
not as dire or unfortunate as people imagine based on economic data. While the
economic problems we've discussed
certainly exist,
Venezuela's economy is indeed in a mess.
But South Americans are
truly optimistic,
easygoing, and know how to
enjoy life. They complain
about wages,
prices,
and the government,
but they also laugh at the drop of a hat,
dance to music, and watch
baseball on weekends.
Caracas, the capital, is indeed chaotic with a
high crime rate,
but it's not like everyone is on edge or
afraid to go out. Everyone goes about their business as
usual—
working, going to school. If
you see a gang doing business somewhere, just avoid it.
Don't stop at red lights.
In recent years,
with Venezuela's full dollarization,
inflation has largely disappeared. The
government's finances are extremely strained,
forcing them to abandon
the old, all-encompassing welfare system. The
"magical economic phenomenon" of long queues at gas stations and supermarket rationing is
gradually disappearing.
Although supermarket shelves are once again full of goods,
market prices
mean that Venezuelan goods are more expensive
than those in Miami across the border.
Real wages are still less than they were 50 years ago.
Gangs demand protection money,
and police frequently collect "tolls." The
whole country has fallen into a jungle law mentality,
feeling somewhat like a state of semi-anarchy.
After detaining Maduro,
the US is likely more focused on
Venezuela's oil and politics, and
less likely to invest significant effort
in reversing its economic structure and
social order.
Overall,
its economic development faces extremely high uncertainty,
essentially entering a shock therapy phase.
An economy that, when resource-rich and with
ample income,
failed to utilize its oil resources effectively,
instead fostering government corruption and allowing its
productivity to decline,
exacerbating economic imbalances,
coupled with government price controls,
foreign exchange controls, and
interest rate controls—a
short-sighted approach leading to hyperinflation—is like a child whose mind is still developing. They make mistakes and experience confusion. Normally, harsh reality would immediately teach them a lesson—this is an automatic error-correction mechanism. However, if someone starts with astronomical wealth,
this mechanism
may fail.
Small economic imbalances,
minor corruption, and
small price distortions, without timely feedback
in an environment of continuous wealth inflow,
will stray further and further from the right
path.
When the economy is already terminally ill, a
sudden drop in oil prices
could trigger a vicious cycle.
After that, it would be difficult for him to climb out again.
So sometimes, having
too much money and spending it in the wrong places can be
more fatal than having no money at all.
As Venezuela's former energy minister,
also known as the father of OPEC, said,
oil will bring us destruction;
it is the devil's excrement.
Perhaps for Venezuela,
oil truly is a curse.