Hi~
January 2026
can be described as the
craziest month in precious metals history,
reaching the highest volatility ever.
Just look at the silver price
chart; it's truly a rollercoaster ride.
First, it climbed steadily,
surging 68% to
over $120, then plummeted back to square one
in just two days.
If you stretch the timeline a bit, you can
see how crazy this month was.
Gold,
while not as "crazy" as silver,
"only" rose nearly 30% in a month,
breaking through $5,500,
before also crashing. So
many friends have left messages asking me to talk about it,
so today let's take a look at this
massive shock in the precious metals market and see what's going on. Oh, by the way, let
me interject here.
Recently, some friends have left messages saying that
Xiao Lin's channel has switched to English.
Well,
this isn't my setting; it
's because YouTube recently added a new feature, and
some people are automatically playing AI English by default.
So, you can go to the settings,
there's an Audio Track option, and
change it to Chinese to
hear Xiao Lin's original voice.
Today,
I want to take a slightly different approach than usual.
I think...
Let's analyze this together.
I'm not going to give you a direct answer,
but rather we'll
dissect the problem layer by layer.
So, the logical chain in this video
might be a bit long.
You can follow along if you want, or just
get the general idea if you don't feel like thinking too much.
I mainly want to discuss
three questions:
First,
why did gold and silver surge before?
Second, why did
silver rise so much more sharply than gold? And third, why did it plummet
afterwards?
Interested?
First, why did it surge before? Actually, if
you understand why it rose before and
why it fell afterwards, it becomes much more
logical. Let's take
a look. The most basic starting point for
analyzing these price fluctuations
is to clarify whether we're discussing a
long-term
or short-term logic.
We need to clarify the time frame first.
If we're analyzing
why gold jumped in the last 5 minutes,
we naturally need to see
what happened in those 5 minutes.
For example, which major client increased their holdings,
or what news broke in the market? If
you say that the 5-minute gold rise
was due to a lack of confidence in the US dollar...
This is a bit of a stretch.
It's definitely not the main reason.
But conversely, if
you want to analyze
why gold has risen in the past two years,
you have to look at the longer-term,
more fundamental narrative.
For example, what everyone often hears about is
the market's distrust
of the US dollar and US Treasury bonds, the hedging value of
gold and silver, central
bank purchases, etc.
We discussed this quite clearly in our previous video about gold. What
we want to talk about today
is why it has experienced such a sharp rise and fall within a one-month timeframe.
This is still a very short-term phenomenon,
so we mainly want to find the short-term reasons.
As for
why precious metals have risen so sharply in the short term,
you can always
explain it with two reasons:
one is safe-haven demand, and the other is
speculation.
The key is what kind of safe-haven demand,
who is seeking safe-haven demand,
and who is speculating.
First,
what kind of safe-haven demand?
I've summarized it into
two main factors that have
come together. The
most important one
is the market's concern about the new Federal Reserve Chairman.
Note that the new chairman hasn't been appointed yet,
because the term of the previous Federal Reserve Chairman, Powell, is about to expire. The
new chairman
will be nominated by Trump,
and Trump has been criticizing Powell for a year,
wanting him to cut interest rates quickly.
Finally, an opportunity arose to change leadership,
so the market speculated that,
given Trump's style, he would inevitably
find a very obedient,
dovish, and accommodating chairman.
Consider the
Federal Reserve, the de facto leader of the dollar, is
incredibly important,
and this chairmanship typically lasts at least four years.
This would be a huge blow to the dollar's value, the
Fed's independence, and the
dollar's credibility.
Therefore, many fund managers said, "Let
's quickly buy some gold and silver to hedge!"
Another reason
is the concern about geopolitical risks.
Look at 2026;
Trump has been very active again.
Besides arresting Maduro, there have been
a series of
potential actions surrounding Iran, Cuba, and Greenland.
Think about all these keywords
appearing frequently in the past month.
Although some are just verbal expressions
without actual action, they still
cause market anxiety.
These two reasons combined
became a fundamental support for the previous surge.
But this is far from over.
This is only the
initial driving force behind the surge. The
real reason for such a crazy
price increase
is
speculation.
Okay, let's analyze this further.
Actually, analyzing speculation
mainly involves looking at two things:
who is buying and how they are buying.
Who is buying?
According to data from the Gold Association,
gold buyers fall into a few categories:
central banks,
industrial and technological users,
jewelry consumers,
and investors. Central
banks may not buy much silver, but the
others are similar. So,
what's causing the rollercoaster ride in
gold and silver prices?
First, it's definitely not the needs of jewelry and industrial/technological users.
Their price lag is significant,
so it's unlikely to cause
such wild price swings. Do
n't underestimate this part;
gold production is 5,000 tons per year, and
about half of that is for these purposes.
Secondly, central banks
can be largely ruled out.
In the last two years, their
purchases have indeed doubled compared to before, buying around 1,000 tons a year
to hedge against the risks of de-dollarization.
Although I don't have their January data, it's
highly probable
they won't chase the market up or down;
instead, they'll buy counter-cyclically,
buying less as prices rise. That
explains why 2025 is supposedly the riskiest and
hottest time for gold.
Central bank purchases actually decreased.
Part of the reason is that central banks
felt gold prices were too high at the time,
so they reduced their purchases. In short, it's
unlikely that central banks caused this rollercoaster ride.
So the answer is obvious:
it's the remaining 2,000 tons or so of investors.
But "investors" is
too broad,
right?
Let's break it down. The
main buyers are
long-term funds like mutual funds and insurance funds.
They are huge in size
and consider long-term capital allocation.
We've been analyzing what kind of hedging is being done, right?
These long-term funds
are mainly for hedging,
driving hedging funds,
but they're not speculating.
Ah, we're finally getting to the point. Who were the
people who truly pushed this surge to its peak through speculation? After
some screening and evaluation, I've identified
roughly three groups. The
"first and foremost" is hedge funds,
and their frantic buying was for
short squeeze.
Actually, let me tell you,
if you see a price chart like this,
especially after a series of sharp drops,
especially when it's linked to the futures market...
Your first guess should be a short squeeze.
What is a short squeeze? Take
silver, for example.
Simply put, it's when a
large number of long positions in silver futures are held and
not closed out by the expiration date,
exceeding the amount of silver available for settlement in the
physical market. This attempts to squeeze out the short sellers. When the short sellers are pushed to the limit, they have no choice but to frantically raise prices to close their positions, causing a sharp price increase. If you didn't quite understand, that's okay. In short, when is a short squeeze likely to occur? When there's a severe shortage of physical silver. For example, in the silver market, there was a short squeeze just
last October. At that
time, Indians
bought a large amount of physical silver,
and China, one of the main silver suppliers, was on holiday for the
National Day Golden Week. This
created a significant gap in the market.
London experienced an extreme shortage of silver, and interbank
lending rates soared
from almost zero
to 30%. Thousands of tons of silver
even needed to be airlifted from the US to
London. Do
you know what that means? The
entire Shanghai Gold Exchange's
total inventory was less than 1,000 tons.
Such a large-scale airlift would have been
unthinkable in the past.
So you can see how scarce silver was at the time. In
January of this year, the
silver shortage wasn't as dramatic as last year,
but global geopolitical tensions tightened.
China
implemented strict controls on silver exports starting in January,
and there were increasing rumors in the US about
imposing tariffs on silver,
causing extremely disrupted international silver flows. The Shanghai Gold Exchange's
silver inventory
dropped to a record low, and the
US COMEX silver inventory
could only meet 14% of open positions,
leading to a very high risk of a run on silver.
In short, the main purpose of
these hedge funds rushing into the silver market,
frantically buying or going long on silver, was to
squeeze short positions. The
second group
was
retail investors.
What do retail investors like? Chasing highs and
selling lows.
You see, when
you want to hoard gold or
buy silver, have
n't you already
heard that
gold and silver have risen sharply recently, and
everyone is rushing to buy them?
Then TikTok starts pushing viral videos
saying silver has gone crazy. When
you see these kinds of videos, don't
you feel a little itchy too?
Retail investors are indeed
one of the main driving forces behind this surge.
This demand
mainly comes from the fact that
silver prices in Shanghai
are mostly lower than global prices,
but at the beginning of this year there was a 6%-8% premium,
indicating a severe shortage of silver in mainland China. Let me
tell you,
whether you look at the gold or silver market
globally, you'll find
a very interesting phenomenon: the
two main consumer battlegrounds are
China and India,
but their
preferences differ.
Chinese people
like to hoard gold and silver at
home,
while Indians
prefer to wear them.
This is reflected in the data:
China is the world's leading market in sales of gold and silver bars, while India is the world's leading market in
jewelry sales,
both gold and silver,
accounting for almost half.
So,
if you use your clever little brain and
carefully consider the timing of these two price surges,
you'll make a surprising discovery.
Last October,
silver was extremely scarce, leading to a short squeeze.
That was
right before Diwali in India, the peak time for
gold and silver buying.
And this January,
gold and silver prices surged.
That was right
before the Chinese New Year,
also the peak time for Chinese gold and silver buying.
This is not a coincidence.
The market generally believes that
retail demand from China and India was the main reason for the surge in precious metal prices
in October last year and January this year. The
third group that caused the surge is
a bit different,
and it is also
a rapidly growing emerging driving force in the past year:
cryptocurrency capital.
This force
is not large in terms of size now,
but it is extremely active
and is likely to grow exponentially in the future.
So let's talk about it.
You see, we're talking about quite a variety of things today.
Many platforms
launch silver tokens on the blockchain. The
issuing company
actually buys silver bars in physical form
and then issues such tokens on the blockchain
for everyone to trade. It's
somewhat similar to a silver ETF on the blockchain.
This market is growing very rapidly,
but its size is not large, only about
$400 million in total.
What is the truly active market? It
's the silver derivatives market
on the blockchain.
You can think of it as a silver futures contract on the
blockchain that never expires.
People do not physically take delivery of silver; it
's purely a price bet.
Of course, the platform has some mechanisms to ensure that
the price is linked to physical silver. The
leverage ratio of this type of contract can reach 20 times.
Some platforms even offer leverage up to 200 times.
I suspect this
might be a bit confusing for those unfamiliar with cryptocurrencies,
but don't worry, just get the
gist.
Basically,
silver also has spot and futures trading in the crypto world.
These silver contracts,
or "futures," have
existed for a while,
but only suddenly became incredibly popular at the beginning of this year.
Why?
Think about it: many people in the crypto world have a
completely different investment goal than traditional funds.
They want higher volatility.
To put it bluntly,
they're playing for excitement;
they're playing for short-term surges and crashes.
Bitcoin, on the other hand, has been
very weak in recent months, and
its volatility is far less exciting than silver.
Look at how sharply silver rose last year;
its contracts even offered 20x leverage.
So, when this was discussed in the community,
players immediately flocked in, creating
a frenzy. The
daily trading volume reached billions of dollars, which is a huge amount for the
silver market.
And while this market
is in the crypto world
and involves derivatives, it
seems unrelated to physical silver,
but it's actually connected through arbitrageurs.
Just as silver futures affect spot prices, and
silver tokens affect spot prices,
these silver token derivatives
also affect spot prices.
The entire market is interconnected.
These cryptocurrency players constitute the
third driving force behind the short-term surge in silver prices.
I'd like to mention that there's
an even larger group of buyers
in the cryptocurrency market who have become a
force to be reckoned with:
stablecoin issuers,
like Tether. On
one hand,
the stablecoin market is growing rapidly; on
the other hand,
they issue gold and silver tokens. All of this
leads these issuers
to continuously hoard gold.
For example, Tether is
estimated to have
bought 140 tons of gold in a year and is still
buying at a rate of about one ton every three to four days.
This exceeds the
buying speed of most central banks, including China and the United States.
Of course, this doesn't mean they're betting on gold; it's just that the
development of stablecoins is too fast. They
're buying both long-term and short-term government bonds and
gold.
I estimate that in the
next few years, they may become an
increasingly significant force influencing global financial markets.
Okay, so
we've basically finished analyzing the reasons for the surge in gold and silver prices. Let me
summarize:
two short-term safe-haven factors, the
Federal Reserve Chairman and
geopolitical factors,
plus the influx of speculators,
including hedge funds and retail investors.  The rush of cryptocurrency capital
led to an epic surge in gold and silver prices.
Okay,
let's move on to the next question:
why does silver rise more sharply than gold, and
fall even more drastically? Actually, it's
not just recently. Let's
look at a slightly longer timeframe. Historically, the price movements of gold and silver
are highly correlated,
but silver's volatility is significantly higher.
In fact,
I did a simple calculation, and
silver's volatility over the past few years
is roughly twice that of gold.
So you see, this month isn't anything special;
its rise is
twice that of gold, and its fall is twice that of gold. It
perfectly matches historical patterns.
So why is silver more volatile?
Simply put, its market size is smaller.
Globally,
in terms of mining volume,
silver is an order of magnitude larger than gold,
about 26,000 tons per year.
But because it's cheaper—
gold is 50-100 times more expensive than silver for the same weight—silver's
market size
is an order of magnitude smaller than gold's.
And if we disregard that,
whether it's gold or silver, the
short-term volatility is
mainly determined by the portion used for investment.
But for silver, the
portion used for investment is even smaller;
60% of its use is in industry.
Furthermore, the demand for photovoltaic products has exploded in the past two years, and for five consecutive
years, the total
silver production has been less than the total demand. If
you exclude jewelry and silverware
used for investment purposes, that's only about 1/5, roughly
5,000 tons. The
silver market is much smaller, which
leads to what?
Greater volatility.
It's like in the ocean:
gold is like an aircraft carrier; when a
big wave hits it,
it only sways slightly.
Silver, on the other hand, is
like a small boat.
Although it rises and falls with the carrier, the
fluctuations are much greater. Okay, let's
look at why
silver rose even more sharply in January.
Actually, if
you look at the three types of people we just analyzed who fueled the price surge,
you'll understand.
Hedge funds want to squeeze the
gold market, but it's obviously too large;
they can't do it. Silver is much easier.
For retail investors,
many feel gold is too expensive, while
silver is much more attractive—it's
rising sharply and is cheaper, so
why not give it a try?
And for cryptocurrency capital, they
go where the volatility is;
silver is definitely more exciting than gold.
These three types of people all tend to
favor silver,
leading to...
Central banks and other central banks generally don't pay attention to silver,
but the silver market is small,
and speculators are pouring in, causing
prices to rise even more sharply.
Let's look at
why precious metals have plummeted. It's
actually quite logical.
This plunge began on January 30th.
Two things happened that day:
one was a major event in the financial markets,
and the other might
seem trivial to the average person.
The major event was the news about the
new Federal Reserve Chairman.
Trump unexpectedly announced his nomination of
Kevin Warsh as the next Fed Chairman. As
we just mentioned, the
market expected Trump to
choose someone very compliant,
very dovish, and strongly advocating for
printing money and lowering interest rates.
Kevin Warsh,
well,
his relationship with Trump is indeed not ordinary.
His father-in-law
is the heir to the Estée Lauder Companies. He
and Trump have been
good friends for decades.
However,
at least based on his previous policy stances, he is
very hawkish, strongly advocating for
tight monetary policy.
He previously opposed quantitative easing and
forward guidance;
it seems he opposed everything the Fed had done in the past 20 years. Now,
after being elected,
he has to balance Trump's position.  The
relationship with the market...
well, let me tell you,
this guy is pretty cunning.
He proposed something called
"interest rate cuts and balance sheet reduction." He cuts
interest rates,
satisfying Trump and
boosting the economy.
At the same time,
he wants "aggressive balance sheet reduction,"
which means reducing the assets the Fed bought with printed money,
selling the Fed's holdings of Treasury bonds and MBS—
somewhat like withdrawing all the money previously printed.
Why do I say he's cunning? It's like
a car stuck in mud. Normally, the
people inside need to step on the gas,
while someone else helps push.
Now,
the car is almost out of the mud, but
Trump wants to accelerate it.
What to do?
Kevin Warsh said, "
How about this?
We'll keep pushing from the outside,
we'll get a few strong men to help push.
But the people inside,
you step on the brake,
I'll do a double whammy:
push from the left, brake from the right; cut interest rates
on the left, reduce balance sheet on the right." Hehe.
As for the exact speed the car needs,
you can guess.
Of course, in reality, it's definitely not just a
simple double whammy of braking and pushing.
There's yield curve control,
balance sheet restructuring, and so on.  The
overall message is that
the market realized
this guy wasn't as
blindly obedient to Trump as previously expected;
he was still trying to balance the
US government and the market. Hence the
surge in the dollar and the
decline in gold and silver prices—that
's the initial reason,
the "big event." There's
also a "small matter," which,
coincidentally, also on January 30th, saw the
world's largest futures exchange, CME, announce an
increase in trading margins for gold and silver. The
margin for gold was raised from 6% to 8%, and for
silver from 11% to 15%.
Simply put, the
cost of leverage when going long or short on gold and silver has increased. If
you were going long on 100 units of silver, you used to
only need to pay 11 units of margin;
now you need to pay 15.
Don't think it's just 4 units;
that's equivalent to a 36% increase in margin. To
give a more realistic example,
maybe you previously invested 11 million
to go long on 100 million units of silver. With this
change in margin policy,
you're suddenly required to pay an additional 4 million.
Many people might not be able to raise that 4 million.
What happens if you can't make up the difference?  The
only option was to sell. This
combination triggered a drop in gold and silver prices. By
the way,
some people might think that the CME
deliberately timed its margin increase,
believing that the "market maker" couldn't afford to lose,
and even suggesting it could escalate to a US-China conflict.
I don't have any inside information on this.
First of all, the CME's margin increase is
reasonable. The
more volatile the silver price, the
higher the margin should be.
This is indeed a reasonable risk control measure by the exchange.
It didn't just increase
it on the 30th; since December 2025, as
silver price volatility has increased, it
has increased four or five times consecutively.
And it's not just the CME; the
Shanghai Futures Exchange is also increasing it.
Of course, it's
possible it was instructed by someone else;
we don't know.
Okay, let's get back to the point. The
new chairman and the margin increase were just the
initial driving force behind the market decline.
Then who came in?
Well, it's the three forces we mentioned before that
pushed the market up.
Hedge funds and cryptocurrency capital share
a common characteristic:
they all used very high leverage.
So it's simple: they all got
liquidated.
High leverage...
Once the market starts to fall,
many people
will be forced to liquidate their positions due to insufficient margin, leading to
further selling of silver. This causes
silver prices to fall further,
creating a chain reaction – a
familiar formula.
We've told this story too many times. Just
look at the cryptocurrency market those two days; the most frequently
liquidated products were
n't Bitcoin
or Ethereum,
but silver token derivatives.
Keep in mind that its market size is
less than a fraction of Bitcoin's,
yet it was the most liquidated. In
three days,
silver fell by more than a third,
from nearly $120 per ounce to below
$80. Gold, along with all other metals, was
dragged down in those two days,
but quickly stabilized.
Cryptocurrencies fared much worse.
You can see that Bitcoin and Ethereum
's decline was slightly slower than silver's.
As the market became risk-averse and
liquidity dried up,
both began to fall.
Conversely, the US dollar rose.
Just look at the past month; the US
dollar and gold and silver have completely
reversed course,
perfectly matching what we learned in textbooks.
So, which is a risk asset and
which is a safe-haven asset is
relative.
When the US dollar is risky, gold and silver
become safe-haven assets;
when gold and silver are risky, the US
dollar becomes a safe-haven asset.
Einstein said over 100 years ago that
everything is relative
except for the speed of light. (Just
kidding,
Einstein never said that.)
On the surface,
it looks like a rollercoaster ride for precious metals,
but a closer look reveals something interesting. It
connects to
a whole host of current hot topics:
cryptocurrencies,
the Federal Reserve,
geopolitics, etc.,
while simultaneously experiencing leveraged short squeezes and margin calls in the financial markets. It's quite a
spectacle. In
our previous episode about gold, we summarized that the
huge noise in gold prices in the short term
is due to speculation and hype. In my
opinion,
from a long-term perspective,
we may indeed be in
a period of turbulence and transformation in the monetary and trust systems,
with various major trends.
However, the recent surge and plunge within a month is mainly
driven by speculation. The
capital market is either in conflict
or has collapsed.
That's the general logic. Just
watch the show;
it's only a short-term fluctuation.
I personally believe it won't affect the
long-term fundamentals of gold and silver.
I've also put
some gold investment tips from our previous gold episode on the screen for your
reference. The
same applies to silver. Have
you noticed that
this recent surge and plunge in precious metals
happened precisely during...
Before the Spring Festival,
if you remember two years ago,
the Xueqiu product's margin call
also happened before the Spring Festival. It makes
me seem like a spoilsport, since
everyone was celebrating the New Year while
I was talking about a market crash and margin calls, right?
I felt helpless. It's probably because
before the Spring Festival,
liquidity from institutions and banks tightens, and
people are
more restless because of the upcoming holiday. This makes the
market prone to volatility.
So everyone, be careful
before future holidays.
Okay,
that's all for today.
Finally, I
wish everyone a happy Year of the Horse! Goodbye!