Hello everyone, this is Brain Master.
Today we're going to talk about
cycles. Sima Qian wrote in *Records of the Grand Historian: Biographies of the Wealthy*: "Those
without wealth rely on strength; those with little wealth rely on
wisdom; those with abundant wealth rely on
timing." What does this mean? The poor rely on physical strength, the moderately wealthy rely on wisdom, and the extremely wealthy rely on opportunity.
This "timing" refers to cycles. The
real big money is all about
cycles.
Look at those who made a fortune: those who
bought oil stocks before the 1970s oil crisis, those who bought
Japanese real estate before the Plaza Accord in the
1980s, those who bought Microsoft and Cisco before the dot-com bubble in the 1990s, those who
bought gold after 9/11 in the
2000s, those who bought Amazon and Apple before the mobile internet boom in the 2010s, and those who
bought lithium mines and electric vehicles after the pandemic in the 2020s. Were they
smarter than others?
Not necessarily. But they all had one thing in common: they
rode the crest of the cycle. When you're in the right place at the right time, even a pig can fly. But when the tide goes out, you see who's been swimming naked. Conversely, even the smartest person will stumble if they ride the wrong cycle. If you happen to buy at the peak of the cycle's boom, you're missing out on the big picture.
Buying Tokyo real estate in 1990 and
PetroChina in 2007 are famous examples, each a case study spanning
decades. When
the cycle reaches a downturn, no matter how
smart you are, it's useless. Your knowledge, your expertise, your models only have meaning if you time the cycle correctly. Going against the cycle is worthless. Therefore, investing isn't necessarily about who's smarter,
but about who can see the timing clearly.
Today, we'll thoroughly discuss the concept of cycles.
Many people find cycles mysterious,
like some profound economic theory,
but it's actually very simple.
There's a very simple model in physics
: a pendulum. If
you pull it to one side and release it, it will swing back and
forth. Why? Because two factors are at play: gravity pulls it towards its equilibrium position—this is the constraint force. But a moving object has the tendency to continue moving—this is inertia. When you pull the pendulum away, gravity pulls it back. In the process of pulling it back, it gains velocity. When it reaches the
equilibrium position, the effect of gravity cancels out,
but the velocity remains,
so it will rush past the equilibrium point. After rushing past,
gravity acts in the opposite direction, pulling it back again. This cycle repeats, and that's the cycle. The essence of all cycles is this mechanism: constraint
plus inertia.
Why do we have the four seasons of spring, summer,
autumn, and
winter? Because the Earth revolves around the Sun, the Sun's gravity is a constraint, and the Earth's speed is inertia. If there were only gravity and no inertia, the Earth would fall directly into the Sun; if there were only
inertia and no gravity, the Earth would fly away. The balance between constraint and inertia results in periodic orbital motion. Combined with the Earth's axial tilt, the point of direct sunlight oscillates between the Tropic of Cancer and the Tropic of Capricorn throughout the year, thus forming the four seasons. The cycles of nature are essentially constrained movements created by certain conservation laws and boundary conditions. The same principle applies to economic and social cycles. What are the constraints? Limited
resources, limited production capacity,
limited credit,
limited market capacity. What is the inertia? The inertia of human expectations, the momentum of investment, and the inertia of institutional
mechanisms. When the economy is good, people believe it will continue to be good—this is the inertia of expectations. Entrepreneurs believe demand will continue to grow, so they invest heavily; banks believe loans are safe, so they lend heavily; consumers believe income will continue to rise, so they consume heavily,
even borrowing money to consume. Everyone's behavior reinforces this trend, thus forming a positive
feedback loop. But
can this loop continue indefinitely? No, because there are constraints, such as limited
resources like iron ore, copper ore, and oil. Reserves are finite, extraction speed has an upper limit, and production capacity is also limited. Factory equipment and
labor can't be added at will, and credit is finite; people can't borrow indefinitely. When investment exceeds resource constraints, it overheats, inflation rises, raw material prices soar, wages increase, and
all costs rise. Businesses find they can't
make money and
begin to contract.
During contraction,
everyone thinks things will continue to worsen, so
entrepreneurs frantically cut investment,
banks frantically collect loans, and
consumers frantically save money.
Everyone's behavior reinforces this trend, creating a
negative feedback loop.
But when contraction reaches a certain point,
assets become cheaper,
opportunities arise, and
people dare to invest again,
starting a new cycle. In short, it's
an over-correction cycle. It
overshoots during rises and overshoots during falls.
Why does it overshoot?
Because people's expectations have inertia, and
adjustments are delayed.
In mathematical terms,
it's the oscillating solution of a second-order differential equation.
Any system whose
rate of change
depends on its deviation from equilibrium has an
oscillating solution. This applies to a simple
pendulum and the
economy.
Philosophically speaking,
cycles are the movement of contradictions.
Hegel spoke of the negation of negation, and the
Chinese say that things
reach their extremes and then reverse. Lao Tzu said, "Reversal is the movement of the Tao," which speaks to this very point. Contradictions, when pushed to their limits, will transform. However, this
transformation is not instantaneous
but rather a spiraling, cyclical process.
Because systems have inertia, delays, and memories,
cycles are not mysterious;
they are a
common characteristic of any constrained dynamic system. Everything has its time—
this is the theoretical basis of cycles.
Economists have studied this for over a century and have
indeed discovered some patterns.
They have
discovered cycles of different lengths from different perspectives.
Let me systematically explain it to you. The
Kitchin cycle, 3-4 years, is an inventory cycle.
Discovered in 1932 by the British economist Kitchin,
he studied economic data from Britain and the United States and
found that there is roughly a small cycle every 3-4 years.
How does this cycle occur? It's the
time lag in companies adjusting their inventory. When
companies see good demand and
sales growth, they
feel the need to increase inventory. Increasing inventory requires
production, which in turn requires purchasing raw materials and
hiring workers.
This process itself creates new demand.
Upstream suppliers receive more orders,
workers receive wages, and
can consume, leading to a
better economy.
But once the inventory is sufficient,
companies find that they can't sell their goods;
demand suddenly disappears.
Why?
Because some of the demand in the previous period
was for replenishing inventory,
not genuine end-consumer demand.
Now that the inventory is replenished... When the demand for restocking disappears,
aggregate demand decreases, forcing
companies to reduce inventory. This leads to production cuts, which in turn leads to layoffs.
Reduced orders from upstream suppliers result in
unemployment, decreased
consumption, and a weakening
economy. Once inventory levels
reach a certain point and become
very low,
companies find that even a slight increase in demand is
insufficient, necessitating inventory replenishment and the
start of a new cycle.
This cycle typically lasts 3-4 years
because the time lag between companies assessing demand, replenishing inventory, and reducing inventory
adds up to
roughly this timeframe. The constraints are the company's cash
flow capacity and warehousing costs. Inventory
cannot be increased indefinitely; cash needs to circulate, warehouses incur rent, and there are losses. Replenishment
reaches a certain level, increasing
financial pressure and necessitating a halt. The Juglar cycle, a 7-11 year equipment investment cycle, was discovered by the
French economist Juglar in 1862, more than 60 years before Kitchin. He studied economic data from France, Britain, and the United
States and found a cycle
roughly every 7-11 years. This cycle arises from fixed asset investment. When companies see a favorable industry with high profit margins, they expand production capacity.
Expanding production capacity requires investment in new equipment and factories. Investment itself creates demand; equipment manufacturers get more orders, construction workers'
wages increase, and the economy prospers. However, once all the equipment is invested in and the factories are built, investment demand
disappears.
Equipment manufacturers lose their orders,
construction workers lose their jobs, and the
economy declines. Then, a new round of investment demand only arises when the equipment has depreciated, the
technology becomes obsolete,
or it breaks down. Why is this cycle 7-11 years? Because the average lifespan of industrial equipment is this long. Machines need to be replaced after seven or eight years, but companies certainly won't replace them every day; they will concentrate on replacing them at a certain time.
What are the constraints? The
lifespan of fixed assets and the company's investment capacity. Equipment
cannot break down immediately; under normal circumstances, it can be used for seven or eight to ten years. Companies also have limited funds; they
cannot invest on a large scale every year. Investments have
cycles. They dare to invest only when they make money; they
dare not invest when they lose money. The Kuznets cycle, a
15-25 year construction cycle, was discovered by
Kuznets in 1930 when studying the US economy. It is also called the housing cycle. He was the 1971 Nobel Prize laureate in
economics and a master of studying long-term economic growth. How does this cycle occur? The real estate investment cycle is longer because houses are used for longer periods; a single building can last for decades or even centuries. Therefore, the investment
cycle in the construction industry is also
longer. Furthermore, real estate investment is closely related to population cycles. When there are many young people buying houses, the demand for marriage is high, leading to robust real estate investment. Once this generation has bought their homes, the next generation hasn't yet grown up, causing real estate investment to shrink. What are the constraints? Population growth, urbanization,
and land supply. When urbanization is rapid, a large influx of
people from rural areas into cities creates
strong demand for
housing. When urbanization slows down, those who should have moved to the city have already moved, leading to a shrinking demand for housing.
Population structure is also a constraint. When there are many
young people, the proportion of the 20-35 age group is high, resulting in strong demand for housing. As the population ages, the proportion of this age group declines,
weakening demand for housing.
Land is also a constraint. There's only so much land in the city center; once developed, it's gone. Expansion must either extend to the suburbs or increase the floor area ratio. However, there are limits to suburban expansion and floor area ratio increases. The Kondratiev cycle, a
50-60 year innovation cycle, is the longest cycle. This is what we often call the Kondratiev wave, proposed by the Soviet economist Kondratiev in 1926. He studied economic data from Britain, France, the United States, and Germany from 1780 to
1920 and found that there was a major cycle roughly every 50 to 60 years. Unfortunately, after proposing this
theory, he was arrested by the Soviet government on charges of counter-revolution and executed in 1938. The charges were that he promoted the theory of capitalist cycles and undermined the legitimacy of the Soviet planned economy. However, his theory has survived and been verified countless times. He
discovered that each major cycle corresponds to a technological revolution: the first from 1780 to 1850 – steam engines and textiles; the second from 1850 to 1900 – railways and steel; the third from 1900 to 1950 –
electricity and chemicals; the fourth from
1950 to 2000 – automobiles and electronics; and the fifth from 2000 to the present – ​​information technology and the internet. Schumpeter later further developed this theory, proposing the concept of creative destruction. He said that the essence of capitalism is creative destruction; with the emergence of new technologies, old
industries are eliminated. Horse-drawn carriages were replaced by automobiles, gasoline lamps by
electric lights, telegraphs by telephones, and
telephones by
the internet. Each technological revolution brings decades of
prosperity. However, when this technological paradigm reaches its limit, growth stagnates, and a new cycle begins only after the next
revolutionary
technology emerges. What are the constraints? The limits of technological paradigm diffusion. No matter how much you improve the steam engine, its efficiency is limited. No matter how many railways are built, there are only
a few main lines. No matter how widespread automobiles become, a family will only have two or three. No matter how much the internet is promoted, the number of users is only a few billion globally. Every
technological paradigm has its ceiling. When penetration approaches 100%, there is no more incremental
growth, only replacement of existing stock. At this point, economic growth slows down. What happens then? Overinvestment, overcapacity, price crashes, bankruptcies, financial crises, and a prolonged economic recession. Economic prosperity only resumes when the next
revolutionary technology emerges and
new investment opportunities arise. However, technological breakthroughs
are accidental;
you
can't have
them just because you want them. It might take 10 years, or it might take 20 years.
This is the recession phase of the Kondratiev
wave. Let's use an abstract, nested structure to explain how the complexity of real-world cycles occurs. This nested structure has three layers. The first layer, at its core, is the cycle of human fear and greed. Traditional
economics assumes that people are
rational,
but in reality, people are fundamentally irrational. Imagine a perfect world with unlimited resources, unchanged credit, unchanged policies, and unchanged technology.
Would there still be cycles? Of course, because people experience fear and greed. The stock market is the best example. The same company, with unchanged fundamentals and profits, can see its stock price rise from $10 to $100, then fall back to $10. Why? Because the
market is pricing in expectations, and expectations are self-reinforcing. When prices rise, people think they will rise further, so they buy, pushing up prices. The rising prices validate the expectations, making them even stronger. The media also fuels the fire, and FOMO (Fear of Missing Out) begins to spread. This is positive feedback.
However, positive feedback loops have limits. Once
prices rise to a certain level, the rate of new capital
entering the market can no longer keep up with the greed of existing capital, so a reversal begins. As soon as selling begins, the upward trend stops.
Those who chased the high panic and start selling. The more people sell, the faster prices fall, and the
greater the panic. Stop-loss orders are triggered, leverage is liquidated, and a stampede
begins. This
cycle is entirely a pendulum swing of human nature, unrelated to external constraints. Keynes's beauty contest theory illustrates this point: you're not choosing the most beautiful person, but rather guessing who others will choose. This game generates spontaneous fluctuations, even if beauty itself is constant. Soros's theory of reflexivity goes a step further: participants' perceptions influence reality, and reality, in turn, influences perceptions. A rising stock price makes it easier for a
company to raise funds, which allows for expansion. Expansion leads to better performance, which in turn drives up the stock price—a positive feedback loop. The reverse is also true. Therefore, financial markets are inherently unstable, naturally prone to bubbles and crashes. The second
layer, the intermediate layer, involves the cyclical changes of specific constraints. In the real world, constraints are
not constant
but cyclical.
These changes don't arise out of thin air but are driven by larger, higher-level constraints, such as the credit cycle. Why does the
government sometimes loosen credit and sometimes tighten it? Because there's a larger constraint behind it: fiscal sustainability. When the economy is weak, the government
stimulates growth by loosening credit, lowering interest rates, and expanding the fiscal deficit. This stimulates the
economy, but at the cost of rising debt and inflation. When the debt ratio becomes too high or inflation becomes too severe, fiscal constraints come into play. A high debt ratio
means… A large portion of fiscal revenue goes towards debt repayment, leaving no money for construction. Inflation becomes too high, unbearable for ordinary people, leading to social instability. The
government realizes that if this continues, fiscal collapse and social instability will ensue, so it must tighten credit, raise interest
rates, and
reduce the fiscal deficit.
This controls
debt and inflation, but at the cost of economic recession. Businesses can't borrow money, investment decreases, employment decreases, and consumption decreases, creating a vicious cycle. When the economic recession reaches a certain point,
unemployment becomes too high, businesses collapse en
masse, and
social instability returns.
The government can't withstand the pressure, so it has to loosen restrictions again. This is a nested hierarchy of constraints: economic growth requires credit;
credit
expansion is constrained by inflation and debt; inflation and debt are constrained by fiscal sustainability and social stability. Each cycle is driven by the constraints of the layer above. The third and outermost layer, the fundamental constraint, is a slow-moving variable:
fiscal sustainability. What constrains it? It's the political system. In democratic countries, the election cycle is four years. Politicians
wanting re-election must produce results during their term. How to achieve results quickly? Monetary stimulus,
lowering
unemployment, increasing GDP, and boosting the stock market, making voters
happy. As for the risk of inflation
due to debt accumulation, that's a matter for the next administration. China's situation is slightly different. China doesn't have an electoral system, but it has another constraint: growth targets. To maintain growth, local governments rely on land revenue and urban investment bonds, leading to excessively high debt levels. The
central
government then has to deleverage. However, once deleveraging reaches a certain point,
economic
growth slows, employment pressure increases, and the central government may have to loosen monetary policy again to stabilize growth. The 2020 pandemic led to further monetary easing, and in 2021, growth picked up,
so tightening began again.
This is why
China's credit cycle is particularly pronounced and shorter than that of the US. Behind each tightening or loosening is a struggle between growth targets and debt sustainability. Looking further ahead, there
are also constraints from technological
paradigms.
Fiscal sustainability is constrained by
economic growth potential, which in turn is
constrained by technological
progress. The mobile internet paradigm experienced rapid expansion from
2010 to 2020, with the widespread adoption of 4G, smartphones, and apps, creating numerous jobs and tax revenues. Rapid government tax revenue growth and low fiscal pressure allowed for a higher debt ratio. However, by 2020, this paradigm had essentially matured. 5G arrived, but it didn't bring new application scenarios. The
maturity of a technological paradigm means that growth has peaked. Peak
growth leads to greater fiscal pressure, which in turn necessitates tighter credit. The Federal Reserve began
aggressively raising interest rates in
2022, from 0% to over 5%, precisely because inflation had risen and debt had become
too high. Therefore, a complete cycle consists of these three overlapping layers. When these three layers resonate, it presents a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity. The 2008 financial crisis exemplifies this. At the time, there was extreme panic, with volatility indices soaring above 80. Central banks around the world began to inject liquidity, and the
Federal
Reserve drastically reduced interest rates to zero, initiating quantitative easing. The eve of the mobile internet technology revolution saw the release of the iPhone, the establishment of the App Store, and the initial widespread adoption of 3G networks. When these three cycles resonate simultaneously, a bull market lasting over a decade ensues. The Nasdaq
rose
from less than 1,300 points to 24,000 points, an increase of nearly 20 times. Apple, Amazon, and Google all
saw increases of several dozen times. Many people believe that consumer technology
industries have no cycles, which is a grave mistake. Let's first discuss consumption. Many say that food is the most important thing for people, and consumption is an eternal need, so how can it have cycles? There are too many constraints on consumption. The first constraint is income. During periods of rapid economic growth in developed countries, consumption appears robust. Wages
rise by 10%, housing prices by 20%, and stocks are profitable. The wealth effect is at play; you
feel increasingly wealthy and are willing to
spend, even borrow money. However, when economic growth slows, assets stop appreciating, the wealth effect disappears, housing
prices stagnate or even fall, and stock accounts
stop generating profits. Although wages may still be rising, the rate of increase slows. You find yourself not becoming richer, and may even be becoming poorer. At this point, consumption immediately shrinks. The
second constraint is debt.
Developed countries generally have high household leverage ratios. A large portion of people's monthly income goes towards debt repayment: mortgages, car loans, credit card debt, student loans. Only after repaying these loans can they consume. Before 2008, the US engaged in rampant leverage.
After the bubble burst,
housing prices fell, but debt remained. For many, the value of their homes was now lower than their loan amounts. The
pressure of
debt
repayment crushed their consumption capacity. It took US households 10 years to deleverage before consumption finally picked up. The third constraint is demographic constraints.
Young people aged 20-35 are buying
houses, cars, getting married, and having children, resulting in extremely strong consumption demand. Meanwhile, older people over 60 have already bought houses... With children and increased independence, consumer desires have declined significantly. Developed countries are generally entering an aging society, meaning a necessary shift in consumption patterns.
Japan experienced sluggish consumption after the 1990s, and Europe followed suit after the 2010s. This wasn't a
sudden decrease in consumer spending, but rather a change in the constraint of population structure. The
fourth constraint is the expectation constraint: consumption depends not only on current income but also on expectations of future income. After the 2008 financial crisis, massive unemployment, plummeting housing prices, and shrinking
401(k) retirement accounts led to widespread pessimism about the
future. Even those with jobs and unchanged wages dared not spend. This
explains why the US household savings rate surged from 2% to over 8%
after 2009, and this is happening in China today. Regarding the technology industry, many believe it experiences exponential growth without cycles. We can only say that innovation is endless, but specific technology sectors always have cycles. The dot-com bubble of 2000 saw the
Nasdaq plummet from 5,000 points to
1,000 points, an 80% drop. In the
1990s,
Japan's electronics industry collapsed, destroying former global giants like Sony, Panasonic, Sharp, and Toshiba. The tech industry is struggling, and its cycles may be more drastic than those of traditional industries because technological iteration is too rapid, making it easier for competitive advantages to be overturned. The first constraint is the expansion limit of technological paradigms. Every technological paradigm has its diffusion curve. Initially, it experiences exponential growth, with penetration rates increasing rapidly from 1% to 5%, and from
5% to 20%. However, once penetration approaches saturation, growth slows from 50% to
80%. PC internet, from 1995 to 2007, saw penetration rates rise from a few percentage points to over 70%, a golden age. But by 2007, everyone who needed internet access was already online. Mobile internet, from 2007 to 2020, represents another new paradigm. But by 2020, everyone who needed a smartphone had already bought one. With only about 8 billion people globally, excluding children and the elderly, almost
every adult owns a phone.
Growth has plateaued. 5G hasn't brought new application scenarios. What will be the next paradigm? Perhaps AI, perhaps Web 3, but it's still unclear. Before a new paradigm emerges, mobile internet will enter a period of competition for existing users, and
growth will slow.
The second constraint is the cycle of capital expenditure. The technology industry requires massive capital investment. Data centers, chip manufacturing, and fiber optic network R&D all require significant investment. When everyone is investing, overcapacity occurs, leading to a price crash. The semiconductor industry is a prime
example. During boom times,
chip supply falls short of demand, prices soar, and all
companies expand. New factories are built, increasing production capacity. However, demand does
n't necessarily grow at the same pace, resulting in overcapacity, a price crash, and losses for companies. Those with severe losses go bankrupt or are acquired. The third
constraint is regulatory oversight. As technology companies grow large, they
inevitably face antitrust scrutiny.
Microsoft faced antitrust investigations in the 1990s and nearly broke up; Google was
fined billions of euros by the EU. Once regulatory constraints tighten, the expansion of technology companies is limited, and growth slows. Therefore, the technology industry also has cycles. No
industry is without cycles; as long as there are constraints, there are cycles. Understanding the essence of cycles allows us to understand the investment logic of cyclical stocks. Cyclical stocks experience three phases during boom periods, corresponding to the first, third, and fifth waves in Elliott Wave Theory. The first phase, the capacity clearing phase (wave one), is crucial not for product prices
but for the supply-demand inflection point. Many people wait until product
prices start to rise... It might be too late to
buy cyclical
stocks now. The real buying opportunity is when the supply-demand inflection point appears. What is the supply-demand inflection point? It's when supply has contracted to a relatively low level, and demand has begun to pick up. The two lines are
about to intersect. At this time, product prices may still be falling, even hitting new lows. The
industry is in a bleak state,
companies are suffering huge losses, and the media is
predicting a downturn. However, stock prices have already
started to rise because stock prices are priced in the future, not the present. The lithium mining market from 2019 to 2020 is a typical example. In 2018, the price of lithium carbonate plummeted from 170,000 yuan per ton to just over 40,000 yuan at the beginning of 2020, a drop of 75%.
Everyone thought lithium was finished and that the overcapacity problem would never be solved. But those who understand cycles are looking at the supply side.
When lithium prices fell below 50,000 yuan, a large number of high-cost lithium mines shut down. A number of small mining companies in Australia went bankrupt. Salt lake projects in South America were delayed. Capital expenditures
plummeted. Supply was rapidly contracting. At
the same time, what was happening on the demand side? The penetration rate of
electric vehicles was accelerating. Tesla Model 3 was selling well globally, and Chinese companies like BYD and NIO were rising. Europe also began implementing carbon emission regulations, forcing automakers to produce electric vehicles. Governments around the world started subsidizing new energy vehicles, and demand was rising rapidly. Although
lithium prices were still at their bottom in early 2020, the inflection point between supply and demand had already appeared, and lithium mining stocks began to rise. By 2021,
lithium prices had really skyrocketed, and lithium mining stocks had multiplied several times over. So at this stage, you should
not look at product prices,
but at the hard data on the supply side. For
lithium mining, look at global
capital expenditure
and new capacity; for copper mining, look at mine capital expenditure and new project
commissioning plans; for iron ore, look at the production guidance of the four major
mining
companies. When capital expenditure falls to historical lows, when new capacity drops precipitously, and when no new mines come online, the
bottom of supply may be approaching. At this time, even if product prices are still falling, you should start to position yourself.
This stage is the most counterintuitive. The media is pessimistic, analysts are downgrading ratings, and financial statements are dismal, but
you should buy contrarian. Most people can't do it because they are looking at what has already happened, not what is about to happen. Remember, don't wait for product prices to rise before buying. By then, the first wave has already ended. The second stage is the stage of simultaneous
price and volume increases, which is the third wave. During this stage, product prices begin to rise, sales increase,
and profits explode.
This is the easiest stage to make money in, and also the stage with the most dramatic price increases. Why?
Because the continuous rise in product prices has a very direct and strong stimulus to the market. Prices rise from 50,000 to 100,000, and the media
starts reporting on the surge in lithium prices. From 100,000 to 200,000, lithium prices hit a new high. From 200,000 to 400,000, lithium is more expensive than gold; with lithium, you can go anywhere. Everyone is using
calculators to calculate
performance. The dynamic
PE ratio drops from 100 times to 20 times, from 20 times to 10 times, and from 10 times to
5 times, looking increasingly
cheaper. During this stage, fundamentals and stock prices resonate in the same direction: prices rise, sales rise, performance rises, and stock prices rise—a positive feedback loop. However, there is an exception. If the stock price rises too sharply in the first wave, prematurely exhausting the valuation, and the
product price increase is not dramatic enough, then the third wave may not follow.
The market is too optimistic in the first wave, prematurely incorporating the gains of several years into the valuation. When
performance truly explodes... Unless prices rise significantly more than expected,
stock prices may stagnate. A key indicator for
judging when the third wave ends is the supply-side reaction. When product prices rise to a certain level, new capacity will inevitably enter the market; this is a market law that no one can stop. This was the case with lithium mines
in 2021. Lithium carbonate
prices rose from 50,000 yuan per ton to 500,000 yuan, a tenfold increase. At this time, global lithium mine projects were accelerating production; new projects were being launched everywhere—Australia, Chile, Argentina, and Africa. Global lithium mine supply was expected to expand from
500,000 tons of LCE in 2020 to over
2 million tons by 2025. When you see a significant
increase in new capacity, a surge in industry capital expenditure, and capacity utilization returning to
over 90%, this is a signal that supply constraints are easing, and the price ceiling is approaching. The
third stage is the earnings release stage, also known as the fifth wave. This stage is the most complex and dangerous.
Product prices may still be high, or even slowly rising. Company performance may increase significantly quarter-on-quarter, and stock prices may continue to reach
new highs. However, this is precisely when the risk is greatest. Why? Because there are too many variables
affecting stock prices at
this stage: the pace of earnings release, changes in product prices, the speed of new capacity deployment, and changes in demand. Policy changes, market expectations—any one of these variables can cause a stock
price crash. Once the cycle reverses, the drop is often not just 10% or 20%, but a 50% or even 70% or 80% plunge. My operational principle for this
phase is: do not open new positions. If you've held your shares through the first and third
waves, your focus at
this stage
shouldn't be on buying more, but on when to sell. At this stage, the trend of product prices is far more important than valuation and performance. Many people are still using calculators to calculate valuations. They think a PE ratio of 10 is
cheap,
but that's useless. PE is a lagging indicator. What you need to watch is the trend of product prices. If product
prices are still rising and the economic climate is still improving, then you can continue to hold.
If product prices start to stagnate, trading sideways for several months
without rising further, then you need to be wary. If product prices start to fall slightly,
even by just a few points, but the trend has changed,
you must decisively reduce your holdings. A reversal of the economic cycle is only a matter of
time. Once prices start to fall, they will accelerate. This is exactly what happened with lithium prices
in the second half of 2022. Prices stagnated from a high of 600,000, rose for two months, and then fell slightly to 550,000, 500,000, and 450,000.
Many people are still using calculators to calculate PE ratios.
Look, the PE ratio is only 5 now, super
cheap. But lithium
prices continue to fall, from 400,000 to 350,000, then 200,000, all the way down to 100,000 in 2023. Stock prices have halved from their peak, and many lithium mining
stocks have fallen by more than 70%. Why? Because the supply side has reacted. When lithium prices rose to 600,000, all
lithium mining projects worldwide were frantically expanding production, resulting in an explosive increase in supply. Projects were concentrated in one phase, leading to a marginal reversal between supply and demand. Although demand is still growing, the growth rate has slowed. Battery manufacturers' lithium salt
inventories and car manufacturers' battery inventories are increasing. With the supply and demand reversal, prices collapsed. Another scenario: if you can't judge the trend of product prices, if you're not confident about the direction of the economic cycle, then just
sell everything. Because if you've been right all along, holding from wave one to wave five, from 10 yuan to 300 yuan, you've already made 30 times your initial investment. This stage has so many variables, and if you can't grasp it, why take the risk? Take profits when you can. More importantly, if you didn't participate in the previous stages, don't enter the third stage. Many people saw
lithium mining stocks repeatedly hitting new highs in 2022. Seeing
lithium mining
companies' quarterly profits in the billions or tens of billions, and witnessing the industry's boom, makes one unable to resist
chasing the market. This is typical of retail investors who get burned. What
you see as prosperity may be the peak of the cycle; what you think is the beginning may be the end. These people who chase the highs
haven't experienced the
first wave of capacity clearing, nor the third wave of price and volume
surges. They completely lack understanding of the cycle's rhythm. They only
see the prosperity, not the hidden dangers behind it. The most difficult part is switching cognitive frameworks between the three stages. In the first wave, ignore financial data and look for supply and demand inflection points. In the
third wave, focus on product prices and profit explosions. In the fifth wave, ignore valuations and only look at
product price trends and stock price
technical trends. Most people can't do this because they use a so-called value investing framework to view all stages. Using a financial framework, in the first wave, they see such severe losses that they dare not buy. In the fifth wave,
they see product prices still high and company performance
so good that
they are reluctant to
sell. As a result, they hold from the peak all the way to the crash, giving back all their profits. True cycle masters are those who can
switch freely between the three stages. More importantly, they know when to enter and when to exit.
Entering the market requires courage because it requires buying against the trend amidst
widespread pessimism. Leaving requires wisdom, because it means decisively withdrawing from a period of prosperity. Everything has a cycle, life has a cycle, and families have cycles. The cycle of life is also a combination of constraints and inertia. Constraints are your background, your resources, and your cognitive boundaries. Inertia is your habitual thinking, behavioral habits, and class inertia. But most people don't understand this cycle. They think their peak is forever and that there are no constraints on upward movement. Wrong!
True social class
isn't measured by your peak glory, but by what you have left when you're at your lowest point. Like a stock after the bubble has been removed, its true value lies in its market capitalization. Li Si, who rose to the position of Prime Minister in the Qin Dynasty, reaching the pinnacle of power, wept bitterly before his death in the marketplace of Xianyang, saying, "I wish we could go back to the days of hunting rabbits with our yellow dog outside the east gate of Shangcai! Is that possible?" He longed to return to the
past, to those
days of hunting rabbits with dogs in the countryside. Could he go back? No. Not only could he not go
back, but he was utterly wiped out, his entire family wiped out. The Jia family in *Dream of the Red Chamber*, with its halls of jade
and horses of gold, its extravagant lifestyle, even the Empress Dowager sent gifts for Grandmother Jia's birthday—they seemed to possess
boundless wealth and power, destined for generations to come. But in the end, it was like birds returning to their nests after their food was eaten, leaving behind a desolate, white expanse. After their property was confiscated, the Jia family was so poor they didn't even have decent clothes. The same is
true in modern times. At his peak,
Xu Jiayin's
net worth exceeded 200 billion. China's richest man, Evergrande's properties are all over the country, his football team has won numerous championships, he was always surrounded by entourages at banquets, a business leader—
and what happened? He's now imprisoned, his
overseas assets are frozen, and he faces global debt collection. After
decades of hard work, for whom did he toil and for whom did he reap the rewards? Then look at Pan Shiyi. At the peak of
SOHO China, he was also a real estate tycoon. But Pan Shiyi started selling
properties in 2014, and in 2021, he sold the entire
SOHO China to Blackstone. Now, Xu Jiayin is in jail,
sewing, while Pan Shiyi and his wife are laughing and joking in
the US. So, the truly smart people, the true aristocrats, are not those who are most glamorous at the peak, but those who can maintain their bottom line during every trough. What does it mean to maintain your bottom line? It means that in every downturn of your life, your trough is higher than the last. This is
true class advancement. It's not about how high your peak is, but how high your trough is. The peak might be due to luck, leverage, or the dividends of the times, but the trough reveals your true strength, your understanding, your resources, your network, and your risk
management ability. If you are a proletarian during your trough, then you are a proletarian. No matter how glorious your peak, if you remain aristocratic and bourgeois during your troughs, then you've truly become aristocratic and
bourgeois. What is class? I'm
not even talking about intergenerational inheritance; if you can't even secure your own future, how can you dare say you've elevated your class? So today, I'm talking about cycles, not just about investment,
but about life.
You need to understand the laws of cycles and even more so, respect their power. When
you're at the height of your power, remember that the rabbit caught in the East Gate can never be caught again. When you're enjoying the prosperity of life, remember the desolation of the past. In the high phase of each cycle, prepare for the trough of the next cycle, elevate your trough, and hold your bottom line. Each trough should be higher than the last; only then can
you create compound interest. Only then will your life and your family truly be on a
path of great fortune, truly on the road to defying fate. That's all for this video. See you next time.