Hello,
welcome to AI Senior's channel.
I'm Xiaolin.
During the Spring Festival,
I had an in-depth experience with OpenClaw, and it
's truly addictive!
It's like a 24/7 online personal assistant,
helping you accomplish various tasks,
such as writing code, researching information, managing files,
and even
controlling your browser to automatically complete tasks.
Many of you may have used Claude Code, which is
indeed very powerful,
but have you noticed that
it only runs on the terminal?
If you want to use it on your phone to
automatically organize to-do lists
or schedule specific tasks,
Claude Code ca
n't do that.
This is where OpenClaw's uniqueness lies.
It can connect to
various communication tools like Telegram, Lark, WhatsApp, and QQ,
allowing AI to truly integrate into our daily lives.
You can issue
automated commands and tasks anytime, anywhere,
and can also call upon
file system terminal commands, built-in tools,
skills, and various online services based on task requirements.
For example, it can automatically collect industry information, post on
Xiaohongshu, and publish
articles on WeChat official accounts.
If Claude Code
is a powerful individual programmer,
then OpenClaw is an
infinitely expandable AI team
with a wider range of application scenarios,
a truly integrated
intelligent hub into your entire digital life.
So, in today's video...
I will start with the installation and configuration of OpenClaw, then
introduce the main modules of setting up multi-agent systems, adding skills,
and practical application scenarios to help
you quickly get started using OpenClaw.
If you like today's topic,
please give my video a thumbs up.
Now, let's
introduce the concept of OpenClaw to those who are new to this intelligent agent.
Simply put,
you can think of it as
an AI command center.
We can send tasks to it directly through
various communication tools such as Telegram, Lark, Slack, and QQ on our mobile phones or computers.
OpenClaw comes
with a gateway, which
automatically assigns tasks to the
corresponding agents for processing.
These agents
can call skills,
operate browsers,
execute code,
manage files, etc.,
to automatically complete tasks for us.
Moreover,
it supports the ACP protocol,
which means we can summon multiple agents to
cooperate and
help us complete tasks.
Next,
let's look at
an OpenClaw learning roadmap,
from beginner to expert,
what we need to master in each step.
Then,
I will
explain the
key points of each section
and how to configure it in the order of this roadmap.
The first stage focuses on
basic introduction.
We'll learn the installation and deployment process,
including configuring files for initial use and choosing a communication terminal (
Telegram, Lark,
WhatsApp,
Discover, etc.).
Next, we'll
master its core tools.
This part covers the
tools built into the OpenClaw agent,
such as file
reading, writing, editing, and deletion. You
can
directly manipulate terminal commands on your computer,
configuring dependencies and
projects.
It
also allows access to online search tools like web
scraping and
complex tasks,
batch tasks, and parallel tasks.
OpenClaw supports
multi-agent collaboration,
and
multiple agents can create sub-agents.
For example, if you have a batch task
processing 10 files,
it can create 10 sub-agents to
complete the task simultaneously,
increasing efficiency. The
third part covers advanced automation,
such as
how to use scheduled automated tasks in OpenClaw.
For instance, if you want to
preview AI news at 9 AM daily...
So we can use
this scheduled task to complete the task
and make good use of the heartbeat monitoring mechanism.
For example, we can use it to
check the health status and
email.
This heartbeat monitoring can accomplish all of these tasks.
Then,
we can also use the
Webhook function
to trigger its automated tasks externally and perform
multi-agent collaboration. The
fourth part is skills expansion.
This is a
very core part of truly leveraging OpenClaw's capabilities.
Because if you only
rely on the capabilities of this model and
its basic toolkits,
its capabilities are still very limited.
Suppose you want to complete some
tasks that interoperate with external platforms and tools,
then we also need to utilize the skills section,
such as how to develop skills and
how to install existing skills.
This part is very important, and
I will talk about it in detail later. The
last part
is system architecture and operation and maintenance,
such as daily startup, shutdown, upgrades,
and some problem fixing.
Next,
we will proceed to the first step, which
is to install OpenClaw.
Regarding the installation,
I recommend running it on a local computer
for three main reasons.
First,
local operation is relatively more convenient,
and the installation process is also smoother.
If it is on a server,
you will need to connect remotely.
After installation,
you need to tunnel it to your local machine, which
can be quite troublesome for beginners.
If you're new to Openclaw,
I suggest finding a spare host and
configuring it locally.
Secondly,
in a local environment,
especially on a Mac,
you can use many built-in system tools
and skills, making the
functionality richer.
Thirdly, tasks
like calling external skills to
execute automated tasks
or collect data are
safer locally,
less likely to be detected or blocked by the platform.
Here,
I'll use my local Mac as an example to demonstrate the
installation. The
official documentation
recommends three installation methods:
macOS,
Windows,
and NPM (Node.js).
This is applicable to all platforms,
as long as you have the Node.js installer on your computer.
I personally
recommend installing via NPM
because its version management is clearer,
upgrades and maintenance are
more convenient,
and it integrates with the NPM ecosystem.
Before starting the installation...
Here's another tip,
especially for beginners.
Since the installation process
requires opening a local terminal,
this interface
might not be very user-friendly,
especially if you encounter errors.
Even though you can send the error message to AI,
switching back and forth is
inconvenient. So,
I recommend
opening an AI editor. This
also allows you to open a terminal window and input the
installation
commands there.
If you encounter errors or don't understand something,
you can always choose the terminal's response
and interact with it on the right.
This helps you
solve problems independently.
Whether you don't understand configuration files,
concepts,
or error messages,
AI can explain them directly on the right.
Okay,
let's install it.
First,
install Node.js locally.
Go to the Node.js website.
Here, you
can choose the Windows or macOS version.
Below are the installation commands.
Just execute the uncommented code (lines
2, 5, and 8)
in your terminal.
After that,
you can
see your local Node.js version using `node -v`.
Your version must
be 22 or higher. Mine is
version 24.11.1.
After installation,
we can
execute the installation command.
First,
copy this line of code: `
npn install -g openclaw@latest` (this
is a global installation).
Return to the terminal,
paste and execute. It will
indicate
successful installation.
Next,
we can run the installation wizard
to initialize and configure OpenClaw.
There are two options: the first
is a complete installation wizard,
including configuring the system service (
adding a daemon process so it will
automatically start the OpenClaw service upon restart). The
second option only
runs the configuration wizard.
I recommend the first option.
Copy this line of code,
return to the terminal,
paste and execute. This will
take you to the configuration interface. The
first option is for
a personal account;
select "Yes". The
second option is "
Quickstart".
Next
is configuring the model.
Most mainstream model vendors support this.
If you have an OpenAI membership...
Alternatively, if you're an Anthropic member,
you can directly
choose the first or second option for convenient
web-based
authorization and login.
Similarly,
if you don't have a membership,
you can use the API key.
Based on my experience,
I've used Openai,
Zhipu,
and Kimi 2.5 (the Dark Side of the Moon). Comparing them,
I think Kimi 2.5 offers the
best overall cost-effectiveness.
With Openai, a
few rounds of conversation could
cost several dollars.
If you used it intensively every day, it could cost
tens of dollars, or even
over $100.
Switching to Kimi 2.5,
I find its pricing reasonable. The
key reason for the cost savings is the
Kimi API
's exceptionally high hit rate per conversation, or cache
hit rate.
Here's an example:
with a 90% cache hit rate, for
1 million tokens, the
actual price is calculated as follows:
90% hit rate plus 10% miss rate...  The
input cost for 1 million is only 1 yuan, which is the same as
its standard price of 4 yuan.
That means a miss costs 4 yuan, and a hit costs 1 yuan.
This cost is only 1/4 or
25% of the standard price.
This is its cost advantage
and, after comprehensive comparison, I think it's the
most cost-effective method.
Okay, here
I'll choose Kimi 2.5.
Next
is filling in the API key.
There are three ways,
depending on where your account was registered.
For example, if I registered in .cn and
use it domestically,
then we choose .cn, which
is the second option.
If you registered overseas,
then choose .AI, which is the
first option. Also,
Kimi and
other model platforms
offer programming packages, and the
keys differ between them. You must
strictly follow the channel where your key was generated
to choose this option.
Here I choose the second
option, "Enter API key now," and
press Enter. Paste the
API key we generated on the Kimi platform
directly here and
press Enter to execute.
Then it will ask us to select a model;
we can just keep the default and
press Enter to execute.
Next
is the step of configuring the communication software.
You can choose Telegram.
In WhatsApp, you can
choose according to your actual needs.
Here's a demonstration using
Telegram as an example. It
asks us to enter a Telegram bot token. Creating a
Telegram bot token is
very convenient.
We open the software
and find the botfather (
parent bot).
If it's not in the list,
you can
search for "botfather" in the input box.
Enter the chat interface and
type `/newbot`.
The first step is to
enter the bot's name,
for example, "爬爬虾" (PaPaXia). The
second step
is to enter the bot's username,
which must end with "bot"
because we're creating a bot. The given
name is already taken, so we
changed it to "AilinclawdBOT".
After approval,
it sends
us the bot's token (
HTTP API).
This string is the Telegram bot's token.
Paste it here and
press Enter.
Next, it
asks if we want to configure the skill;
just click "Yes".
Here...  Here
are some pre-installed skills you
can briefly look at.
There's a password manager,
Apple's Notebook, and
some other functions.
We can skip these for now and
install them directly from the web interface in the management panel later.
We can select from the top and bottom menus. To
select a function,
press the spacebar. Then
press Enter to
skip.
Next,
we'll be asked to configure some basic key information.
We can skip this during the quick deployment
and configure it as needed later in the web version.
Click "Skip." Skip the
Notion API key, skip
OpenAI,
and skip Elevenlabs'
audio generation function for
now.
Next, we
'll select the hook, which is the
external trigger method.
If you're a beginner and
unfamiliar with this technology,
I suggest skipping this for now.
Next, it
will automatically configure the gateway
and complete the basic configuration. At
this point,
OpenClaw is installed. It
will then ask where to use it. If you're using it
in the web version, select the second
option and press Enter to execute.
This will open
a web-based gateway management interface.
Here,
we can directly initiate a chat.  It
can also manage some of its basic functions.
After that,
we can directly open this Telegram and
return to the bot we just created.
This is the bot I created.
Clicking it will jump to the
window where we can talk to it. After
sending the command "start",
it will ask us to reply, that is, to
allow the
interaction between the bot and OpenClaw. Let's
copy the last line of code
and go back to the terminal command to
execute the permission command.
Okay, it
's
allowed now. We can go back to this Telegram to have a conversation. Let it introduce itself. I just went online. To be honest, I haven't fully figured out who I am yet. I just woke up. My memory folder is almost empty
because we just completed the basic configuration,
such as some of its preset content
and its memory. It
is currently completely empty.
Next,
it will ask us,
for example, you can give it a name, and
what kind of reply you prefer,
whether it's formal, humorous,
or interesting, etc.
I will send it some basic information,
such as "Your name is PaPaXia.
As my AI assistant,
you help me complete some daily automated tasks.
My preferred reply
is simple and professional.
You can call me AI Senior.
My time zone
is Beijing."
Just click send.  The
reply is that the
profile has been updated.
The name is "Crawler Shrimp," and it
's my AI assistant. The reply then
asks the AI ​​senior
what needs to be automated or processed, suggesting that the
user directly tell them.
For example, the user could ask the senior AI to query the files on the
current desktop. The reply indicates there are
34 files and folders on the current desktop,
including 6 folders
containing
images, videos,
JSON files,
and other scripts and
formats. The user
then asks a simple question,
such as checking the weather in Beijing today.
This requires using its
built-in tools to connect to the internet and
retrieve network information. The
result is:
Beijing's weather today
is 4.4 degrees Celsius,
cloudy, with a southerly
wind. To fully
utilize
OpenClaw's capabilities, we need to
configure preset information, external skills,
and
different agents for different tasks, allowing
multiple agents to run in parallel.
This is how we
truly unleash its potential.
Next,
we'll examine the
backend management panel.
Let's familiarize ourselves with its functions
first. First, there
's a chat window.
If you've configured it on your local computer,
you can directly chat here. You
can also chat in a messaging app configured in Telegram; the
content is the same on both sides.
One advantage of chatting here is that the
information displayed on the webpage is more comprehensive
and faster.
In the messaging app,
all messages are pushed only after a reply is received.
On this webpage,
we can see the information in real-time;
it's a streaming output.
Okay,
that's the first point. The
second
is its overview, which is its
panel information: how
many instances are currently active,
how many chats are active, and
whether scheduled tasks are enabled.
Let's look at them one by one.
First,
I've configured a Telegram channel.
If you've configured other apps like Lark,
Discover,
or WhatsApp, their configuration information
will be displayed here.
Actually, we
won't configure them on this webpage later;
we'll configure them through terminal commands,
but the configuration information will still be
displayed here.
Next, there are the
instances, which are
our clients.  After
connecting to OpenClaw, the
next step is the conversation.
We
interact with OpenClaw from which terminals?
First, there's an agent name, which is
our chat window.
Then, if I interact with it via Telegram,
a new chat window will appear.
Here, you can see
its usage status,
management, and scheduled tasks.
For example, we can create a daily briefing,
sending me the previous day's AI information at 9 AM every day, and
we can create the scheduled task here.
Next,
this is quite important, the
agent section.
Currently,
we only have one default agent, the
main agent.
All our tasks are
completed through this agent.
Later, based on
different task characteristics,
we can set up multiple agents.
So, on the left, there
's a list.
You can configure main, coding,
social media,
and various other types.
Under each agent, there
are tools.
First, there are
some pre-built files
for this agent: agent.MD,
soul.md,
tools.md,
its identity information,
user information,
heartbeat packets,
and memory files.
We can refer to the manual.
Inside, you can look at agent.md.
Its purpose
is to define operation instructions,
continuity rules, and
important memories.
soul.md
defines the agent's personality,
tone, and boundaries.
tools.md
contains environment-specific tool descriptions.
user.md
stores our own user information,
preferences,
and project background.
identity.md contains the user's identity,
including their name, emoji, and avatar. memory
is long-term memory.
We can click into these files to
take a look.
They all contain preset configurations.
For example, in the conversation,
we defined its name as "Crawler Shrimp," and
its identity as my AI assistant. We
preferred a simple and professional approach, so it
automatically
extracts some content from our conversation
and writes it into the corresponding
configuration files.
This is what we mentioned earlier—
why OpenClaw becomes smarter the more you use it.
Because
it extracts and summarizes each conversation
and writes it into the corresponding categorized files. Each time
we create a new conversation,
it injects these preset files
into the current conversation window. In other words, with
each new conversation,
it understands us better.
Okay,
this is the first core function it uses.  The
second core function we'll use
is its built-in tools,
such as file reading, writing, and editing, as
well as terminal command operations.
Execution requires commands.
This manages background processes, allowing
polling,
termination, and
viewing lists.
For webpage operations, there
are keyword searches,
content
extraction, and Markdown conversion.
Further down, there's a memory function for
searching and
retrieving memories. This section
manages conversation processes,
allowing viewing all conversations,
history,
sending conversations,
creating sub-agents, and
checking conversation status.
This section
controls the
browser, allowing opening,
keyword searches, and
webpage manipulation.
This section controls the canvas,
used for things like screenshots,
and navigation.
Below that is information management, and then there
are automation tasks and gateways.
These are all tools that come with OpenClaw after installation and
don't require any additional setup.
Here's
a little trick: right after
installation,
we can use it as
a learning tool,
an entry point for learning OpenClaw.
For example, we can directly ask
what components OpenClaw offers,
such as the skills command.
What tools are available to
help you complete the task? It
needs to search project files
and view the official library.
Because after installation, the
entire project library and
files are already on our local machine.
I can directly send this command and
see how it responds.
Based on local documentation and installed components,
OpenClaw's main architecture is as follows:
First, there's the gateway.
Then, there are the channels for message connection. Available
tools
include read,
write,
and edit tools, as well as tools for version patch management. Then there are
some operations on the webpage: session
management,
message and channel management,
device and node management, and
memory management.
This is the
same interface we just saw; it
matches.
So, OpenClaw itself has a
very deep understanding of itself.
If you have any usage questions,
whether about commands,
functions,
or scenario boundaries, you
can directly communicate with it, and it
will help you organize them.
Below, there's
also a prompt about skills. It lists
all the skills I currently have installed, as well as some
commonly used command lines. The
search location is the
project package installed locally.
Regarding skills...
We'll focus on this later
because skills are crucial for leveraging OpenClaw's capabilities. Upon entering,
we'll see an interface like this.
First, we can search for
relevant skills using keywords.
Then, here are some pre-installed skills;
you can decide whether to install them based on their descriptions.
Besides these,
we can also install skills from the app store.
After installation, they will be displayed here.
Next, we see information
about the agent:
its configured channel information, the
current working folder, the
model it uses,
its identity information,
and the location of our communication channel.
Finally, we see information
about scheduled tasks.
If you've created scheduled tasks, they
will also be displayed here.
Through this structure,
we can understand what OpenClaw can do. The
core is that when a user sends information,
it routes it to an agent through the gateway panel,
for example, the main agent.
Under the main agent, there are
tools and sections: its
file (
background information),
its preset commands, its pre-
installed tools,
and the skills we install.
These, combined with external functions,
help us complete tasks.
And after the task is completed...
It will return to a terminal we specify,
and
we can also set up scheduled tasks to
make it execute automatically.
This is basically the
capability framework of OpenClaw.
Before talking about skills, let's
take a look at the
directory structure of OpenClaw's workspace to help
us better
understand its underlying logic
and how we can
make changes and configurations to the functions.
After installation, you
will have a folder named .Openclaw in your user directory. The same applies to
other IDE tools you install, such as
claude, codeex, docker, Gemini, and OpenClaw. After installation, you
will have a corresponding folder named . in the root directory of your user directory,
such as .claude, .codeex,
.docker, Gemini, and .OpenClaw.
Opening it will show
a file structure like this.
Let's take a look. The
core structure is these structures. The
first is the main configuration
file, OpenClaw.json.
This file is the
most important configuration file for the entire OpenClaw project.
The model, API,
telegram (the
channel you connect to),
and settings for multiple agents and sub-
agents are all
managed and configured in this file. The
second important one is...  The
workspace
corresponds to the agent's workspace.
As we saw earlier,
we have a main agent (`main`),
and below it are these files,
tools, and
skills. The
corresponding workspace is located here. Inside, you
'll see these files, which
correspond to the
files we saw in the Web UI.
All the default information is contained here,
including the files generated when creating new tasks. If
you create multiple agents,
for example, a coding agent, a new workspace will be generated
here after creation.
Each agent corresponds to one workspace, and
all generated content and
default information are contained
in this folder.
So this is quite important. The
third folder is the `
agents` folder. The `
agents` folder
stores the agent's dialogue
history.
For example, clicking on it will
show all our
previous dialogue history.
Next
is the `skills` folder.
Since I haven't installed skills yet,
if I install skills later,
a new skill will be created here.
Skills added here
can then be retrieved by the agent.
Then, the important files used to complete the tasks
are these.
Understanding the
structure of
this project folder will help you
understand the principles of OpenClaw.
Next,
we'll focus on the
functionality of OpenClaw skills, which are essential to
fully utilize its capabilities.
Skills can be
continuously added; the
more task types and
subdivisions you have, the more skills
you can add, and the more powerful
its task completion capabilities become. There
are three ways to install skills. The
first is through the built-in tools, as
we've already seen here. It
has inline skills, which are pre-
installed.
If needed,
you can directly click to install them in the management panel. The
second way to install skills is through
OpenClaw's official
plugin skills marketplace, which
integrates hundreds or thousands of officially collected skills
as well as user-uploaded skills.
I'll demonstrate the installation.
First,
let's return to the terminal command.
Similarly, I'll open it in Antigravify.
So, for the first installation and use...  First,
you need to install the Clawhub CLI tool. This
means you
can download the corresponding commands through Clawhub's marketplace.
Press Enter to execute.
After that,
you can go to the plugin marketplace.
For example, if you want to install a specific command,
you can search for it here.
I want to install
a network search skill.
So, click in,
copy the skill's name,
for example, tavily-search.
Then, go back to the terminal and
enter the command: `
clawhub install tavily-search`.
Paste the name into the search bar and
press Enter to execute.
Okay,
now it's
installing. After it's finished, you
can see
a new "skills" folder in this workspace.
Under this "skills" folder, you'll find the external skill "
tavily search" installed.
Below are its configuration file, the
skill's MD file,
and the skill's scripts. This
means the skill
has been installed into the agent, and
you can see that "
tavily skill" has been successfully installed in the management panel.  The
management panel in this backend can also read the information.
Next, we have the
third installation method, which is used
when the built-in skills are
not available, or when you can't
find the skills you need in the official plugin marketplace.
This is a very mainstream and
recommended way to install skills.
This method
is applicable to OpenClaw and
other IDE tools or CLI tools such as CodeX, Claude Code, etc.
It is
a command-line tool for skill installation launched by Vercel. To
install it,
simply type `npx skills add` followed by the
name of the skill package. There
are several ways to do this. The first
is to directly enter the
repository name on GitHub.
The second is to
directly
paste the link of a specific skill.
Alternatively, if
you want to install
a specific skill from the entire repository (
e.g., if the repository contains 5 skills and
you only want to install one skill), you can paste
the skill link.
Here,
I'll use the example created by Teacher Baoyu.  Let's take
this skills repository as an example. This
skills repository
contains skills in
three main categories:
content generation and publishing,
AIGC content generation (
e.g., image generation), and
content formatting (e.g.,
converting web links to Markdown).
It's a skills package suitable for creators. To
install this skills library, simply
copy this command (
you can see it here: `
npx skills add`).
Then, copy the address of the skills package, which
corresponds to the repository
name: `jimliu/baoyu-skills`.
This installs the entire skills package,
meaning all the skills in this repository.
You can install them all with one click.
If you only want to
install a specific skill,
you can directly navigate to
the skills folder.
For example, if you only want to install
the image generation skill,
copy its address,
return to the terminal, and
type the command `npx skills add`.
Paste the link of the skill you want to install into this folder and
press Enter.
This will bring up an installation panel
where you can choose
where to install it:
Antigravity or Claude Code.
Or perhaps it's OpenClaw.
This command-line installation
tool is very convenient.
We can use it to install skills for almost any tool
we want to add
skills to.
Here, I'll choose OpenClaw and
press Enter to execute.
It will then ask us whether to
install it for this specific project
or globally. The
default is to install globally.
Okay,
click the first option.
OK,
installation is complete!
Afterwards, you'll see
a newly added skills folder,
baoyu-images-gen. Now,
I'll demonstrate a
use case for skills.
For example, if
I want OpenClaw to automatically
fetch some news and
publish an article on a WeChat official account,
we can also use
Baoyu's skills library. It
has a skill called "
post to Wechat," which
publishes articles to WeChat.
Let's look at its introduction. There
are two modes for publishing content to an official account article: the first
is publishing images, and the
second is publishing articles.
Publishing can be done
through a browser
or directly through the WeChat official account
API.
I'll demonstrate how to use it.
First, install this skill.
Go to the domain name of this skill,
copy the domain name, and go back to the
terminal to execute the
installation command for this skill. The
installation steps are the same as before.
Install globally.
After the installation is complete, the
skill will also be displayed.
The first step of installing baoyu-images-gen,
post to Wechat, was
also successfully installed.
Now let's take a look at the
usage introduction of this skill and
see what its MD file looks like. The
language can be ignored.
Here are some of the scripts it publishes, which
can also be ignored.
Next is the
preference settings for this skill.
Here
we can set the theme color scheme of the article,
as well as the publishing method,
whether to publish through a browser or
through the API, the
author comment switch,
and the fan exclusive switch.
We can configure these parameters here
before we can use it.
Further down, let's look at the prerequisites.
First, we need to obtain the API credentials.
After that, we need to
set it in the environment variables.
Because during the process of calling this skill,
it will read the environment
variables to see if there are API credentials
before it can publish automatically. The
corresponding environment variable
can be placed in the root directory, that
is, the user folder.
~/.baoyu-skills/.env
is fine.
So here,
we need to complete two actions. Let's
do them one by one.
First is the preference settings MD file.
So let's go back here and
create a new file
named extend.md.
It has an example input.
Let's just copy it.
First is the theme. The
default theme. The
color is blue. The
publishing method is API.
Then
change the author to your own name.
Next is enabling comments.
Here it's only for fans to comment.
We can leave it off by default. There's
also a browser configuration address.
If you're publishing through the API, you do
n't need to configure this. Just
delete it.
Okay,
the first step is complete.
Now, about configuring these parameters,
this skills.md file
has an introduction.
For example, there are preset colors:
blue, green, vermilion, yellow, and purple.
You can choose according to your preference.
Next
is the second configuration.
We need to put the WeChat Official Account API key in the
.env folder.
Okay,
let's go back to the user's folder
and create a
.baoyu-skills folder.
In this folder, create a .env file.
Initially, this folder is empty.
Next, we need to fill in these parameters.
First, we need to paste the WeChat APP ID and WeChat APP key.
The way to obtain these
is to go to the WeChat Official Account backend and find them
in the Development and Settings.
I won't demonstrate the specific steps here;
there are many tutorials online. Just
fill in the ID and key. At
this point, our
skill configuration is
complete. After that, we
return to the dialog window and
create a new session.
We can also open a mode called "
/verboss". Enabling this mode allows
us to display the task's history
instead of just returning the result.
Like the tasks we completed before,
it only gave us the result
without showing the process.
With this mode enabled,
it will display the process.
For example, my task
is to collect all the latest core information about the Deepseek V4 model and
write a beautifully formatted
WeChat Official Account article suitable for AI developers based on this information.
Finally, we
push it to the WeChat Official Account backend.
Saved to drafts for
one-click publishing.
Okay, it's already
executing.
First, the
website searches for information.
Then, it
calls this skill
because it's for sending WeChat official account articles.
It automatically reads "
Baoyu Post to Wechat"
and calls this online search skill
to get information about Deepseekv4.
Below is the information crawling and news retrieval process.
We can see it
executing the task step by step throughout the whole process. The
entire task
took about 10 minutes. The
task result is returned: it
has been successfully published and
placed in the drafts folder of the WeChat official account backend.
Information collection
is done through multi-channel searches to obtain
core information about Deepseek V4,
its native multimodal capabilities, the
context of 1 million tokens,
and the expected upcoming release.
The article is titled "Deepseek V4 Quietly Arrives: A
Domestic Large-Scale Model with Multimodal and Contextual Double Kill,"
covering core intelligence overview,
in-depth analysis of technical highlights and comparison with v3,
geopolitical game,
developer practice, etc.
We go to the backend of the WeChat official account and
can see this article.  It's
already saved to our drafts.
Click to see the title,
then this is the overview:
Intelligence Summary,
Release Time (
earliest next week),
Core Highlights,
Architectural Features,
Market Strategy,
Technical Highlights, In-
depth Analysis,
Below are some interpretations, a
comparison with v3,
geopolitical technical maneuvering,
developer practice,
and application scenarios.
Finally, there
's a summary
and a disclaimer:
based on publicly available information;
technical details are subject to the official release.
This way, we use OpenClaw to call external
skills to automatically collect information,
and then the article is automatically published to the official account. The
whole process is completely automated; we
don't need to do anything manually. We
just give it a topic, and it automatically
collects this information
and pushes it
to the WeChat official account backend. All
we need to do is
publish the article.
This is
just a demonstration of a small function.
Of course, in actual use,
you can also request it to generate images,
such as a cover image,
and insert relevant images in appropriate places in the article.
It also has an image generation skill;
you can request it to first use the
image generation skill to generate images, and then
push it after everything is completed.  The
WeChat Official Account article backend also works.
This is a practical use case of using OpenClaw to
call external skills.
Once you're familiar with this process,
you can combine the capabilities of skills to
complete various automated tasks and
connect to different platforms,
whether it's Xiaohongshu, WeChat Official Accounts,
Twitter, YouTube,
etc. Here's another tip
about using skills:
in the Vercel
skills marketplace, there
's a "find" skill.
After installing it,
we can use the "find"
skill to search for the skills we want and
install them.
The steps remain the same.
After installation, you
can see that "
find skills" is
ready. Then, in the dialog window,
ask what skills are currently available.
It will list the current system configuration and
available skills, such as
ClawHub
Coding Agent.
Here are some skills I installed previously. If the "
find skill" isn't found,
we can restart OpenClaw by
typing "OpenClaw Gateway restart" in the terminal.
Then, use common CLI commands like these...  I've organized everything
on this webpage I created.
I'll
add the link to this webpage to the video description later.
For example, it includes tools for checking
status, stopping, restarting,
configuration wizards,
and automatic repair commands if problems occur.
Okay,
restarting is complete. Let's
create a new conversation. The
reply includes these skills:
first, the system-built-in ones;
then, the custom-installed ones. You
can see the "find skill," which
is for discovering and installing agent skills,
has been successfully added.
Now, let me use myself as an example.
I'm a YouTuber, and
I want it to help me find skills related to
YouTube video creation.
We can use this skill to
find new skills. It
will automatically call the "find
skill" to complete this task.
OK,
the result is out.
It executed the command `npx skills find YouTube video`,
and below it shows "YouTube video," which
should be an analysis skill, a
video theme research skill, and a
video intro skill.
It lists the address of each skill,
i.e., its installation command.
To use it,
we can simply copy the command
and install it directly in the terminal.
Or, if you see a suitable skill,
you can simply ask it to install the specified skill for you, and
OpenClaw will automatically complete the installation process.
This is another tip about installing skills.
In fact,
skills play a very important role in OpenClaw,
holding significant permissions.
Therefore, I've dedicated a large portion of this video
to explaining how to install them, the
different installation methods,
techniques,
and
how to actually use them after installation.
I've provided detailed demonstrations of all of these.
Next,
we'll discuss multi-agent functionality.
In the background, we can see that
currently, there's
only one master agent;
all dialogues and
tasks are
completed within this master agent. However,
if you have different categories of tasks—
coding,
social media, and
various other sub-tasks—
putting them all under a single agent isn't suitable.
Therefore, OpenClaw
allows the creation of multiple agents.
Next,
I'll demonstrate the creation process.
Return to the terminal and
enter the command `openclaw agents add`. The
first part is fixed,
and the second part
is the name of the new agent you want to add. You
can name it according to your task type.
For example, if you're writing code,
you can name it "coding".
Or, Vibecoding is also okay.
Here,
I'll demonstrate with DailyNews, which is a
daily news and
information assistant.
I'll name it that and
press Enter to execute.
Then,
it will automatically run a setup wizard
to help us complete the agent configuration.
First, it
creates the workspace. You
can see it's named
workspace-dailynews under the OpenClaw folder.
We'll press Enter by default. Next,
it asks if we want to
copy the identity profile from the main agent.
If your agent settings are similar and
you don't want to repeat the settings,
then choose yes.
If you want to configure a completely new agent,
you can choose no.
Next, it asks if we want to configure a new model.
I'll also choose no here.
You can also
automatically configure different models for different agents based on the complexity of the task.
Next, it
asks us to configure the channel.
I choose yes.
Here,
we choose Telegram,
select manual configuration,
and then
add a new account.
Because
we used the Kimi 2.5 model
for the main agent as our general assistant, and for
DailyNews,
I can create a separate bot.
For example, let's go back to this bot.
Father, create a new bot
named "Daily AI News".
Enter a bot account name,
making sure it ends with "BOT".
The new bot is now created.
First, you'll need to enter the account ID.
Copy the
first line of numbers and use it as the ID.
Press Enter.
Then, enter the complete token.
Next, pair the Telegram
account with the agent you just set up.
Click "yes".
A new
agent is now successfully created.
You'll
see a new workspace named "
Daily News" created. The
following files will be
automatically created. Go
back to the management
panel and refresh; you
'll see a sub-
agent has been successfully created.
Its configuration file,
tools,
and skills are all
configured.
Go back to Telegram, click "
Chat," and then "
Start".
The first time you run it, you'll need an authorization code.
Copy it,
go back to the terminal, and send it.
OK,
authorization successful.
Let it introduce itself. The
reply is "Just online,
blank."
Let's set its identity:
who it is, its name, its
status,
and some of our information.
This
completes the creation of a brand new agent.
We
can also switch models here.
Enter `/model` followed by the
model provider, model
name, and then `to switch` to
switch the model.
This is a configuration for multiple agents.
Based on this mechanism,
you can
set different agents for different tasks
and automate them to
complete different tasks.
This improves both the
quality and completion rate of the task,
and it also saves on tokens
because each agent has its own specific task,
reducing the amount of pre-set information,
including the memory you need to input.
Finally, let's
discuss another concept:
when using OpenClaw,
simple tasks are
completed within the main process and
main dialog window. However, for
complex tasks,
such as batch tasks
or concurrent tasks,
we can use OpenClaw's sub-agent mechanism. This means that
multiple sub-agents can be created under one main agent.
These sub-agents
can help us complete tasks concurrently and in batches.
Regarding the invocation of sub-agents...
It doesn't require us to configure anything. The
main agent will automatically spawn child agents to complete the task based on its type.
For example, in the
main agent's dialog window, I can
send a command to
schedule child agents to query the
real-time weather for Beijing, Shanghai, Hangzhou, Tianjin, and Shenzhen today.
This is a concurrent task.
Okay, you
can see the task is already running. The
subagent queries the weather for Beijing,
Shanghai, Hangzhou, Tianjin,
and Shenzhen.
They are executing sequentially.
After each child agent completes its run,
it returns the results to the main agent. Later,
we can also run the command `
/subagents list`
to list which child agents are
currently in the main agent for this task and
their status. You
can see that there are currently
1, 2, 3, 4, and 5 active child agents.
This shows the agents active in the last 30 minutes. There are
none yet
because this is our first time creating the task.
We just need to understand the basic
concept
and framework.
In most cases, the
main agent
will automatically determine the difficulty of the task and,
when necessary,
automatically spawn child agents
to help us complete the task.
You don't need to manually configure anything.
Once all child agents complete their tasks, the
dialog window for each child agent will automatically close,
and the result will be returned to the main agent.
This is the mechanism. So,
we've basically covered OpenClaw from installation
and basic configuration to
advanced uses,
such as skill installation,
multi-agent configuration,
and configuring child agents. We've thoroughly explained
these core aspects.
After watching this tutorial, I
believe you'll be able to use OpenClaw
and maximize its capabilities.
Finally,
to help you better understand
what tasks OpenClaw can accomplish,
besides the example of sending messages to a WeChat official account demonstrated in the video, it
can be integrated into many other
work scenarios.
Here, I recommend a project
on GitHub called "Awesome OpenClaw Use Cases." The
author has
compiled many currently popular and
feasible use cases,
such as
daily article summaries for social media platforms like Reddit and
YouTube,
below which are examples of creative and building
workflows for YouTube content creation and
multi-agent content production workflows.  Let's take a look at a
workflow orchestration productivity example.
For instance, let's see a
use case for the YouTube daily summary.
After clicking,
it explains
how to use
it, what the prompt command is, and
which skills are required.
For example, this scenario
relies on the YouTube-four skill.
First,
we need to install this skill.
It also tells you how to install it:
first, tell OpenClaw to install the skill.
After installation,
the skill will automatically apply for an
account and API key for the corresponding platform.
Its logic and
commands are written
in the skills.md file.
Specifically,
it uses TranslatorAPI.com to
register an account
and apply for a key on this platform.
Okay,
after that,
we can use it like this:
For example, if you want to see a summary of a specific channel,
you can send this command: "
Every morning at 8 AM,
crawl the summaries of these YouTube channels
and return them to us."
First, it needs to transcribe the content,
then summarize it into
two or three key points,
including the video title, channel name,
and link.  This guide
covers the use of channel summaries
and keyword summaries,
explaining the
usage methods for each scenario. It
also outlines the functions of multi-agent content creation, including the
problems it solves and the
required skills.
You can install these skills sequentially and
configure them as follows.
After installation, you can send a prompt command to
obtain the results for that scenario.
This repository of usage scenarios is invaluable
for advanced use of
OpenClaw.
I'll also include this link in the video description. Once
you've mastered all the configurations and
basic skills, you
can refer to these scenarios
to better leverage OpenClaw's capabilities. You
can also adapt it to your own work needs,
as it contains many resources, ideas, and directions.
So, that concludes the
quick start guide to OpenClaw.
Reflecting on my own
experience,
I believe OpenClaw's value lies
not in its power,
new inventions,
cutting-edge technologies,
or new features,
but in finding an excellent entry point to bridge the gap
between AI and practical work.
The distance becomes closer than ever before,
which is what I think is its most unique feature.
When dozens of agents
run concurrently in the background, and
hundreds of skills are on standby,
you see your
rules being executed accurately time and time again. Then
you realize
that the future is already here;
it's just that the distribution is uneven.
Some people know how to use it, some
don't,
and some use it very well—
that's the difference.
So, through this video, I
hope you can stand at the forefront of this map.