Hi everyone,
if you're interested in AI, you've
probably heard of Hugging Face a lot,
but what exactly is Hugging Face?
In short,
it's a platform that specifically collects various AI models.
You can think of it as the App Store for AI, offering a
wide variety of AI models for you to try out.
In today's video,
I'll introduce how to make good use of Hugging Face's AI models,
including operating them directly in your browser
and downloading them to your computer
for greater freedom.
Okay, after opening the Hugging Face website,
first, click the "Sign Up" button in the upper right corner
to register a new account.
On the user information page, check the box to agree to the terms of service and
click "Create."
In the top navigation bar,
there's a "Models" button, which contains
over 2.5 million AI models. The easiest way to
find an AI model that meets your needs from such a huge library
is by "Task Type."
For example, if you want to generate images,
you can enable the "Text to Image" category below. In
addition, there's a very useful sorting function in the upper right corner.
You can select "Trending" to view recently popular models,
or apply different sorting criteria such as "Most Likes" and "Most Downloads."
Okay, let's jump right into the first model and
see what's interesting inside.
This model is called Z-Image, and the
development team is Alibaba's "Tongyi Lab".
Below the model name, there's a row of labels
listing the model's most important features and related information,
such as the main supported languages,
links to the model's papers, and licensing types.
Below that, there's some text and image information, which
is basically the model's "user manual,"
introducing the model's development background
and some usage precautions.
Okay, so how do we use this model?
For beginners, the
simplest way is through the Inference Providers section.
Inference Providers are
essentially service providers that help you "run models."
Users don't need to worry about their computer's capabilities
or installation and setup issues.
Hugging Face offers free users a $0.10 monthly credit.
If you feel this isn't enough,
you can upgrade to a Pro account, which
will have a $2 monthly credit. Alternatively,
you can switch to a pay-as-you-go plan. For
this plan,
you need to link a credit card to Hugging Face.
After linking,
you can switch to the next tab and
click the Add button to top up.
Of course, you don't necessarily have to go through Hugging Face.
If you're already a paying user of an AI service provider,
simply go to the "Settings" tab,
find the service provider's name,
and enter the API key you obtained from them.
When you use these models on Hugging Face, the
cost will be directly deducted from the service provider's account.
Okay, here's a random prompt:
ask the AI ​​to generate a young woman with long hair. The
background is an alleyway in a European town.
Clicking "Generate"
will generate an image that matches our description.
Okay, besides using Inference Providers,
another quick way to experience AI models is through Spaces.
If you think of an AI model as a "product,"
then Spaces are like "personal stores" in an online marketplace.
Each store uses its own way to package and display its products,
and even provides some value-added services.
In the navigation bar above,
you can find the Spaces button.
Clicking it will take you to a display page.
We can explore different Spaces through the categories below.
For example, here I've entered the "Image Generation" category.
Clicking on Z-Image,
you'll find that although the same AI model is running behind this Space,
this page offers more interactive options.
For example, you can specify in the "Negative Hints" field that the
generated image should not contain "trees."
You can also specify the image resolution
and aspect ratio,
such as applying a 16:9 aspect ratio for widescreen.
Finally, clicking "Generate"
will generate an image of a puppy playing with a ball on the grass.
Okay, you'll notice
a small green label at the top of the page. The text
inside says "Running on Zero,"
which is a "GPU sharing" feature from Hugging Face.
It differs from the Inference Providers we introduced earlier in that
it charges based on the user's "duration."
Free users have about 4 minutes of usage per day,
while upgrading to a Pro account
extends this to 25 minutes,
giving you more time to explore different AI applications.
Okay, let's try another Space.
For example, this time we'll play with "speech synthesis." We'll
enter the first Qwen3-TTS
AI model, which can convert your input text into speech.
However, be careful; if you input Traditional Chinese, the
AI ​​might generate Cantonese narration.
Therefore, I've highlighted the sentence and
used the right-click menu to convert it to Simplified Chinese. Then, I'll
briefly describe the speech style and
click "Generate."
Okay, let's listen to it.
(No, stop talking!)
(I've heard enough of those high-sounding reasons!)
(Tonight, I just want to know whether you chose me
or chose to escape!)
OK, Hugging Face also has a feature that's great for beginners to experience AI models
called Hugging. Chat
's interface is very similar to ChatGPT; it
's basically a large chat window.
You can switch between different open-source AI models in the lower left corner.
For example, I chose Kimi-K2.5, which has been generating a lot of discussion online recently.
Then we can
start chatting or enter questions through the dialog box at the bottom. We
can also upload files or pictures from our computer and
ask the AI ​​to do key summaries and data analysis.
Note that Hugging Chat
will also consume your account's usage limit.
Therefore, if your usage is relatively large,
remember to link your credit card and top up your account first.
This way, you don't have to worry about running out of credit during use.
Okay, after trying some AI models on the Hugging Face website,
you might want to make some customized adjustments to a model
and integrate it into your own project. At
this time, we can consider
deploying these AI models on our local computer or on a cloud platform.
One popular
and beginner-friendly platform is Google Colab.
It's a cloud computer that you can use freely and
even provides free GPU computing resources.
Hugging Face has excellent integration with Google Colab,
and Hugging Face also provides a
very simple syntax called pipeline. This
allows you to
quickly load Hugging Face's AI models with just a few lines of code. For
example, let's say
I want to find an AI model that
can analyze whether customer reviews are positive or negative.
I can switch to the "Task" category and
use "Text Classification" as the filter.
Once found,
you can go directly to the Google Colab homepage and
click "Add Notebook." To
use Hugging Face's pipeline syntax in Google Colab,
we must first import the pipeline from a toolbox called "Transformers"
and then execute this line of code.
After execution,
we can type "pipeline" at the bottom
to call the AI ​​model we want to use. The
first parameter is the "Task" type, which is the
filter we just applied in Hugging Face.
So, I would type "text-classification" within the parentheses. The
second parameter is the model's "name." For this,
we just need to go back to Hugging Face,
click the "Copy" button next to the name, and
then return to Google Colab to paste it.
Okay, let's give this line of code a name.
For example, let's call it a "sentiment analyzer."
We can input any sentence and
let the AI ​​determine whether it represents a "positive" or "negative" sentiment.
Finally, we use the `print` syntax to
display the analysis results on the screen.
Okay, let's do a test. The
first time we run it, it will take a while
because Google Colab needs to download the AI ​​model from Hugging Face.
After it finishes running,
we can see the analysis results below, showing
that the AI ​​has 99% confidence
that the text expresses a "positive" sentiment.
However, you might find this analysis result
not very intuitive for the average user.
So, we can consider adjusting the code
to extract the keyword "positive" and
change it to Chinese.
So, I entered a set of square brackets and 0 after the original syntax to
indicate that we want to extract the first set of data within the square brackets. The
data's label name is "label."
Then I pressed Ctrl + Enter to
re-execute the code.
In this way, the
output only contains the keyword "positive."
Next, we can use a simple `IF` syntax
to check if the "analysis result" is positive.
We'll change the display to
show the Chinese characters for "positive emotions" or "negative emotions."
Okay, let's run the code again.
This time, the output will be "positive emotions."
If I change the sentence,
for example, complaining that no one is commenting on my posts, the
AI ​​will interpret it as expressing "negative emotions."
Google Colab, while very convenient, is
primarily designed for testing and learning, with
limitations on usage time and resource sharing.
Therefore, if you want a more stable environment
and to run an AI model for an extended period,
you can consider deploying the AI ​​model on your local computer for
complete control.
Before starting,
we need to complete some basic environment settings. The
first step is to install Python on your computer.
It's a well-known programming language
and a fundamental tool required for most AI models.
After downloading, simply
double-click the installer and
keep clicking "Next" to complete the installation.
If you are using Windows,
remember
to check the "Add to system path" option during installation
to ensure Python runs smoothly. The
second tool we need to install
is VS Code. The Visual Studio Code editor
makes writing and managing code easier. After downloading and installing VS Code, you can open it directly. First, create a new folder on your desktop or anywhere else and give it any name.
Then, return to VS Code and click "
Open Folder"
to point
the path to this new folder. New files will then be automatically stored in this project folder. Since running AI models locally requires installing some special packages and tools, to prevent
these tools from affecting other projects
on your computer, we need to create a separate workspace for it—a "virtual environment." So, I go to the sidebar, open the extensions panel, enter "Python" as the keyword to install its extensions, and then press Ctrl + Shift + P to select "Create Virtual Environment." For virtual environment management, we'll
directly use
Python's built-in Venv. As for the Python version, we'll choose the latest version downloaded from the official website. After
creating the virtual environment,
we must enable it. So, I press Ctrl + Shift + P again to bring up the command palette and select the second option, "Select Interpreter." Then, apply the `venv`
option
you just used. After applying it, if you open the terminal window and see `venv` before the command, it means the
virtual environment is
enabled. Now we can safely install necessary tools within this virtual environment. For example, AI models often use a suite called
PyTorch,
and the pipeline syntax we just practiced uses the
Transformers suite. Okay, in the window below, type `pip install` (the syntax for installing packages) to
enter the names of these two packages and press Enter to start the
installation. After installation, we can do a test. You can open the right-click menu in the
blank space of the sidebar
to create a new Python file. Then paste the syntax we just wrote in Google Colab into it,
press Ctrl + S to save, and then type `python main.py` at the bottom to execute the file. If the settings are
correct,
we will see the same result as Google Colab in the terminal. Okay, of course, what we can do
locally is
not just execute a simple pipeline command. You can also make more in-depth adjustments and optimizations according to your needs,
such as integrating multiple different AI models. To build more complex applications, and best of all, even if you're not good at
programming, don't worry,
because we can use AI assistants like Claude or Gemini to handle the code. You just
need to write a prompt,
explaining your computer's hardware specifications and requirements. For example, you might want the AI ​​to recognize the
image you provide
and pronounce what it sees. Okay, so I pasted the prompt and pressed Enter. After the AI ​​gave its
suggestions,
we can scroll down the page, copy the necessary package syntax, paste it into the terminal window, and press
Enter to start the installation. After the package is installed, we also copy the code provided by Gemini and paste it into the
original Python file.
Okay, let's do a test. Gemini mentioned that the image must be named test_image, so I dragged
this image file into the VS Code window and executed the code. Similarly, the first time you execute it, it needs to
download the AI ​​model file,
so it takes a long time. If an error message appears during the process, you just need to
paste the message into Gemini. Just
ask it to help fix and update the code. If everything goes smoothly, we'll
see the newly generated audio file in the sidebar.
Click "Play" to listen to the AI's recognition results (in this
image).
(We can see a wooden round table) (on which sits a magazine and a cup of coffee) (the
magazine cover has several interior design photos). Okay, but sometimes we might encounter a situation where our computer's hardware isn't powerful enough to run some larger AI models. In
this case, you can consider using a cloud server for AI computation, which is the Inference Providers
service
we introduced earlier. For example, suppose I want to use the "cloud" to run the
Wan 2.2
video to generate an AI model. Then we must first obtain a key from Hugging Face so that the cloud service provider
can verify our identity. So I click "Create New Token," give it any name, and check "Send Request to
Inference Providers." Finally, I scroll to the bottom and click "Create." Now we can copy the key. Next, we can go back to the model page and click "Use this model" in the upper right corner. In the Inference Providers section,
you'll see a piece of code.
You can copy it by pressing Copy. Since this code uses the Hugging
Face Hub suite,
in VS Code,
you'll first need to install it into the virtual environment using `pip install`. Then, paste the
Hugging Face code
into the window above. As for the API key we just copied, you can paste it directly
into the API Key line.
One important point to note is that the code provided on the official website doesn't automatically save the
generated video as a video file. Therefore, we must manually create an MP4 file. Type `wb` to represent "write" and "binary". The
MP4 file is currently empty, so we need to continue using the `
write` syntax to write the AI-generated video into it. Finally,
close and save the file. Okay, let's test it using the default prompt, "A young man is walking on the street". After a while, an MP4 file will appear in the sidebar. Click on it to see the
generated video.
Okay, finally, if you're using Hugging Face... Seeing some useful Spaces and wanting to run them on your
local computer is no problem.
For example, this Space is mainly used to repair blurry old photos. If you want to download it
to your computer, you can choose "Run Locally." This will show you a piece of Docker code. Docker is a well-known software that can package code and make it usable anywhere. So, let's go to the Docker website and click "Download" to install Docker on our computer.
Then, start it directly. Following Hugging Face's instructions, we need to
go to Docker's settings page to enable the Containerized engine feature.
Click "Enable," then close Docker
and reopen it to apply the new settings. Now, we can copy this code. Open a
terminal in the lower right corner of Docker and paste the code using Ctrl + V. We're ready to install this Space. After installation,
a URL will be displayed at
the bottom of the terminal. Clicking it will open a browser with the same functionality as the original Space. Okay, let's do a test. I dragged a photo from my computer folder... Take a slightly blurry old photo, then
click "Submit" at the
bottom. Docker
will then launch its local AI model to generate a
high-quality version with significantly improved clarity.
Okay, managing installed Spaces in Docker is also very simple. You can use the buttons next to them to start or stop them. And if you no longer need
the Space, just click the trash can button on the far right. Okay
, that's all for today's introduction to Hugging Face.
See you next time! Bye!