Friends,
after so many years of hard work,
we've finally gone public! Just
kidding, it's
not me who's going public,
it's InStone Innovation.
The handsome young man next to me
is JK, the founder of InStone. Don't
let his young age fool you; he
's a 90s kid,
but he was the first 90s kid to list on the STAR Market! The first 90s kid to list on the STAR Market! The first 90s kid to list on the STAR Market! The
first 90s kid to list on the STAR Market!
Now he's a complete mogul. As for
me, although we're still a bit far from going public,
today I want to take you behind the scenes to reveal what
a company goes through to list on the A-share market. Everyone says that listing on the
A-share market is difficult and has high
thresholds. What exactly makes it so difficult?
What are the untold secrets behind it? Does
n't that sound incredibly mysterious and exciting? Let me
tell you,
I consulted several
friends who specialize in A-share IPOs, and
now my head is full of knowledge. Let's
pick some things suitable for a video to
talk about. To go
public,
first, we need a large business.
Let's say the revenue is 1 billion.
That step is simple, so
we'll skip it.
For example, I now have a small Lin Milk Tea Group with
global business coverage.
I'm now considering going public. Where
should I list? I
mainly have three options:
A-shares, Hong Kong stocks, and US stocks.
Today we'll mainly talk about A-shares,
but let me briefly explain the differences. In short,
Hong Kong and US stocks are
more market-driven,
while A-shares have more regulation and
scrutiny. The
reason behind this is related
to the characteristics of different markets.
Hong Kong and US stock investors are
mainly professional institutions with stronger
research capabilities and
risk tolerance.
Therefore, the exchanges
want investors to
screen companies themselves. The exchange conducts a
simple review.
After a relatively standardized review process, if
there are no major problems, you can list—that's
Hong Kong and US listing.
The listing requirements are
clearly stated,
mainly focusing on financials: market
capitalization,
profit,
cash flow, etc.
For example, on the Hong Kong main board,
you only need to meet one of these three requirements.
For instance,
my company's revenue in the past year exceeded HK$500 million, and its market
capitalization exceeded HK$4 billion. So, I meet the financial
requirements for listing in
Hong Kong and the US.
It's not actually difficult to
list in Hong Kong or the US.  The key lies in
attracting investors—
professional institutions—
who are willing to buy your stock.
If you can't, and
no one is willing to buy your stock,
then unfortunately,
you'll have to delist.
Logically,
US and Hong Kong stocks
have relatively low listing thresholds,
allowing the market to filter companies.
However, the A-share market is
characterized by a
large number of retail investors, which makes things more
complicated.
Retail investors often
lack professional screening capabilities; they may not even be able to
analyze financial data.
If the listing threshold remains as low as in the US,
many bad companies can easily be listed together, leading to fraudulent activities and market
manipulation.
This severely disrupts market order.
Therefore, the China Securities Regulatory Commission (CSRC)
aims to
filter out problematic companies during the listing process.
This results in
A-share listing reviews,
whether by the CSRC or the stock exchange,
whether it's the main board or the STAR Market,
being much, much stricter than those in Hong Kong and the US.
In fact, A-shares also have clearly defined listing standards.
For example, the STAR Market requires a
three-year compound annual growth rate of over 25%
or recent revenue exceeding 300 million yuan, and has specific
R&D expense requirements, etc.  Is
n't it clearly stated here?
But let me tell you, just
meeting this
isn't enough.
This is only the very minimum threshold.
For example, the Science and Technology Innovation Board (STAR ​​Market)
requires net profits of no less than 50 million yuan in the past two years,
or positive net profits
and revenue of no less than 100 million yuan in the past year.
But in reality, most listed companies
far exceed these indicators. Take
YingShi for example. It
requires positive net profits,
but YingShi's is 1 billion yuan. It requires
revenue of no less than 100 million yuan, and
YingShi's is 5.57 billion yuan.
These are all orders of magnitude higher.
In fact, there have been well-known,
large companies that couldn't list on the STAR Market
because of insufficient R&D investment.
In short, what I'm trying to say is that the
A-share market has hidden thresholds, which are much higher than the
explicit thresholds specified on this website.
You have to pass these hidden thresholds
to have a chance of successfully listing.
So, if listing on the A-share market is so difficult, why do
people still go for it? Are
n't Hong Kong stocks and US stocks better?
Well, there are many reasons for this.
One very direct reason is
that the trading volume of A-shares is much higher than that of Hong Kong stocks.
So, on average,
it is more profitable than Hong Kong stocks.
There's generally a 20% to 30% liquidity premium.
Simply put, for the same company, if
you're listed on both the A-share and Hong Kong stock exchanges, the
valuation on the A-share market is generally higher. Of course,
this higher valuation on the A-share market isn't absolute.
For example, CATL, which recently listed on the Hong Kong stock exchange,
might have a premium relative to its A-share listing because of strong overseas demand. Another
reason for listing on the A-share market
is its stronger brand image.
Everyone knows it's difficult to list,
so it sounds very impressive. For example, a company
listed on NASDAQ
might be small,
but if it's listed on the A-share market,
its strength is undeniable.
Look at some companies now; even the shell company itself is quite valuable. It's
not just about prestige; it's also about the
real things.
For example, negotiating partnerships and
financing loans is generally easier
for an A-share listed company. Okay,
let's quickly look at
what the A-share listing process entails and
what the hidden barriers are. Generally, it
involves three stages:
First, the application,
which involves preparing the listing materials, the
most crucial of which is the prospectus,
and then submitting it to the exchange. The
second step is the review...
The stock exchange reviews the materials submitted by the company.
If there are any problems, the exchange sends the
questions to the company for inquiry,
and the company responds. There are two
rounds of this process. If the
review is successful, the application is submitted to the China Securities Regulatory Commission (CSRC) for registration. The CSRC then reviews the application again, and only after passing the CSRC review can the company obtain a listing approval. So, the review process involves
two rounds: the stock exchange and the CSRC. Finally, the company
enters the issuance stage, which includes
pricing,
submitting documents to the stock exchange,
roadshows to institutional investors, and so on. Finally, the company goes
public. Generally,
when a company is considering going public,
it will hire a team of experts to help it evaluate where to list, the
success rate of the listing, etc. This expert team mainly consists of three people: an investment banker, a law firm, and an accounting firm. The law firm and accounting firm are easy to understand. Lawyers help build or dismantle the necessary listing structure, and
accountants handle financial accounting and auditing. The
most important one is the investment banker,
who is responsible for preparing the prospectus
and subsequent inquiries, as well as
helping to find investors and conduct roadshows, which involves
selling shares.
You can see that they do the most work and
bear the greatest responsibility,
so they usually receive the most money.
For example, Ying Shi partnered with
CITIC Securities this time.
CICC and Goldman Sachs are both
renowned listed investment banks.
How much do they typically get?
Law firms and accountants
might get around 1% to 3% of the raised funds,
while investment banks might get 5% to 7%, or even
higher.
Okay, our Little Lin Milk Tea Group is preparing for its IPO. The
next step is to submit the materials and
prepare the prospectus.
It needs to include information about the company's business operations,
legal structure, finances, etc. You have to include everything
you think the stock exchange or the China Securities Regulatory Commission
might need. It
usually has to be at least several hundred pages long.
Actually, I feel that the
prospectus is a bit like
writing an argumentative essay. The
topic of this essay is:
Please discuss why your company is suitable for listing on the A-share market.
Please explain that your business conforms to national strategies, has
good profitability,
controllable risks, and
no legal or financial problems. You are
an absolutely honest and good company.
Write an argumentative essay with no
less than 100,000 words.
I'm telling you, the
prospectus
literally discusses this kind of thing. It
seems to have no rules and is
very open,
but in reality, it is very difficult.
Think about it, I have to prove that someone has a problem.  To
prove he accepted bribes,
finding evidence is enough.
But if you want to prove you're innocent, that
you didn't accept bribes, did
n't fabricate anything, and that your company is good, how do
you prove that?
You have to lay bare all your income,
all your expenses, savings, equity structure, and everything you've done—a
complete and honest disclosure.
Then the stock exchange and the China Securities Regulatory Commission (CSRC) will assess your sincerity and
see if you're worthy of listing.
The entire listing process,
including subsequent inquiries, revolves around
this one issue. For
intermediaries,
especially for large deals,
commissions can reach hundreds of millions.
This level of verification is something
most people can't handle,
and it's a very complex process.
How do they typically demonstrate their capabilities?
First,
you need to clearly explain your business, what you do, how you make
money, your
current situation, and your potential
future prospects. Crucially, what are
you going to do with the
funds raised?
It must genuinely
drive business growth.
I'm not just raising money or cashing out. That's
why it's so
difficult for fast-moving consumer goods companies to list on the A-share market recently.
For example, this year,
milk tea companies like BaWangChaJi and Mixue Ice Cream have listed
on the US and Hong Kong stock exchanges.
Although their business is large and
growing rapidly, the
problem is that they have abundant cash flow. Having
too much money makes it
difficult to demonstrate on the A-share market that the
funds raised are for business expansion,
not for fundraising. In that case, no one would be allowed to list.
So, it seems
our milk tea group faces some difficulties listing on the A-share market,
haha.
Generally, those that are easier to get approved use their
funds
for either R&D or
production, which is
relatively easier to explain.
For example, look at InSight. Their explanation is
quite clear.
First, they concisely explain how great and
excellent they are. They
mainly make panoramic and action cameras, and they list
all their product lines—
One X series, ACE series, Go series, etc.—and their
features and advantages.
Look, we've sold over 5 billion RMB in 24 years! What are
the sales figures for each product line? What's the
global coverage?
What's the percentage in China?
23% each in the US and Europe.
See how wide the distribution?
We're now the leader in panoramic cameras, with a
70% market share.
Actually, we've talked about
how InSight became the leader in panoramic cameras before.
Interested readers can do some research.
Okay,
so you've already reached the top, what's the purpose of
the financing?
Simply put,
it's to expand the business.
You see, starting around 2022, they
expanded their business from panoramic cameras and action cameras
to the field of intelligent imaging.
So, in their prospectus, they said
they expected to raise 460 million RMB. Of course, they
actually raised 1.9 billion RMB. What will the 460 million RMB be
used for?
190 million RMB will be used to build a production base, and
270 million RMB will be used for a research and development center.
You see, part is used for production, and
part is used for research and
development. Expanding the business is reasonable.
Actually, you see, the preference of A-shares
leads to a fairly high industry concentration of listed companies. Let me
tell you,
I specifically counted all the companies that submitted listing applications to the Shanghai Stock Exchange from 2019 to now,
including those that successfully listed and those that didn't.
We counted all the applications.
You see, there were a total of 1,158 applications submitted, and
ultimately, 647 companies like InStone successfully listed, which is more than
half. If
we categorize them by industry,
you will clearly see...
More than two-thirds of these companies fall into these four categories.
Friends, take a closer look.
If your company happens to be in one of these four categories,
congratulations, you're one step closer to listing on the A-share market. In short,
you see that these industries with a high number of listings
either require funding in production,
such as specialized equipment manufacturing, pharmaceutical manufacturing,
computer, communication, and other electronic equipment manufacturing,
or they
require funding in R&D,
such as software, information technology, and services.
We've just been talking about industries. Let
me tell you, there's another crucial requirement for listing on the
A-share market, especially the Science and Technology Innovation Board (STAR ​​Market). Do
you know what it is? It's that
you must conform to national strategy.
You see,
China has been vigorously promoting scientific and technological innovation,
which is why the
success rate of listing on the STAR Market is significantly higher than that of the main board. This
conformity to national strategy
isn't some hidden rule;
it's explicitly stated in the Shanghai Stock Exchange's regulations.
You see, the STAR Market must be geared
towards major national needs and
primarily serve companies that conform to national strategy, etc.
However, you see, the
name of this regulation is quite interesting;
it's called a provisional regulation. This means that if
I want to change it anytime,
I can change it at any time.
So, if you want to list on the STAR Market,
you have to explain
how you conform to national strategy and
how you are in a direction supported by national policy.  If
you look at InStone's prospectus, there
's a very important section
explaining how it meets the
criteria for listing on the Science and Technology Innovation Board.
How does it meet these criteria?
Look, it has panoramic technology, image stabilization technology,
AI image processing technology, and
many other technologies.
These are all fundamental, key technologies with
originality and advanced features. The
company has already incorporated these core technologies
into its products, its
influence is constantly growing, and its
ability to transform core technological achievements is outstanding. Does
n't that sound very much in line with
national strategy? And what does the national strategy say? The
14th Five-Year Plan clearly states that
promoting digital transformation,
key industries in the digital economy, and
virtual reality/augmented reality
require these tools and industry solutions.
See how simple and clear InStone's argument is?
The country supports ABC (AI, Big Data, Cloud Computing), and
we happen to be doing ABC.
And let me tell you,
for companies that particularly align with national strategy,
the approval process can be very fast.
Look at my statistics; the
average processing time for applications on the Shanghai Stock Exchange is about 300 days.
But there's one company that
submitted its application on June 1, 2020, and received approval from the China
Securities Regulatory Commission on June 30th—
registered successfully in less than a month, a
lightning-fast listing. Let's
reveal the secret:
this company is SMIC (Semiconductor Manufacturing International Corporation).  I won't go into detail about why
it aligns with national strategy.
Okay, so you see,
since hard technology companies are easier to list, is it
possible for a company to
package itself as a hard technology company, spend some
money to buy some patents,
say a few nice things, and just
muddle through?
Well, that's extremely difficult. The
review process is very strict. It's
not enough to just have a few patents to
prove you're a hard technology company.
You have to clearly explain whether the core achievements of these patented technologies are
actually applied to your business, and the
entire chain must be explained very clearly.
For example, look at InStone's prospectus.
What is each patented technology? Is it
self-developed or purchased?
Where is it ultimately used?
What stage is it at?
Is it in R&D or mass production?
You have to list everything very clearly.
For example,
the first is the
panoramic image acquisition and stitching technology. After the
panoramic camera
acquires 360-degree images,
it uses AI to stitch them together to
create
that interesting fisheye effect. There's
also the invisible selfie stick, right?
That selfie stick is completely invisible,
also achieved through AI stitching.
These technologies are explained in great detail,
regardless of whether the reviewers can understand them.
Anyway, I'll just pile it all up for you.
It's obvious these technologies
are indeed used in his cash-generating products.
This R&D is very convincing.
And what's quite funny is that,
look at the projects he's currently developing; the
responsibility for each project
is assigned to specific individuals.
You can even know
who's in charge of cloud computing,
video editing, and panoramic security cameras, and
who's responsible for these things. He's
completely transparent, revealing everything.
Okay, we've been rambling on for a while now, but we're basically talking about
what you need to prove on a business level, how to
write an argumentative essay, and what the
reviewers actually look for.
Simply put, it's about my success,
my technology, and
my contribution to the country.
Besides business, there are
two other major areas:
law and finance, which is what
lawyers and accountants do.
This is actually clearer than the business part; you
have to break it down and prove it to everyone,
saying, "I have no problems."
But actually proving it is quite troublesome. For the
financial part,
first, you need the financial statements for the last three years, with
all sorts of details—
that's for sure.
But you also need to explain,
for example, that all my business revenue is legitimate. It's
not like
you're selling this product to your aunt's company at a high price,
making it as expensive as possible.
Who are your major clients?
Who are your suppliers?
You need to prove there's no hidden transfer of benefits,
no fraud, and
everything is solid and genuine. The
legal aspects are similar;
your structure must be fully compliant.
Who are your major shareholders?
How many shares do they actually control? All of
this needs to be traced back to the very source.
Interestingly,
this information isn't just a matter of listing it. You're responsible for everything you
write down and
submit.
Each project requires signatures.
For example, the investment bank's sponsor needs to sign,
as do the signing lawyers and accountants.
If any problems arise,
your institution, along with the
individuals who signed, will be held liable.
This is actually a key point of the registration system—
to solidify the responsibilities of intermediaries.
That's why the prospectus
discloses business and finances so clearly; it's essentially
a disclaimer from the intermediary: "
I'm not hiding anything for the company;
I've disclosed everything."
For example, look at this interesting
section in the prospectus
called "Risk Factors," which lists
all the potential risks to the business. Wow, it's incredibly
comprehensive!  I'm
afraid I haven't listed all the risks.
I might misjudge future market trends,
lose technical talent, experience
slower-than-expected product iterations, face
international trade frictions,
business downturns,
exchange rate fluctuations,
inventory management risks, and so on. Does this sound like
a lot of nonsense? It's
like before you go to the exam hall,
you say you have the risk of not being able to answer some questions, or that you don't
have enough time to
finish filling in the answer sheet. That
's nonsense,
but these risks do exist,
so you have to write them all down.
Otherwise, if these risks materialize,
it means your intermediary agency didn't provide adequate warnings.
Okay, so
we've
prepared all of this,
written hundreds of pages of paper.
Investment banks
usually conduct a very rigorous internal review, which
we won't go into detail about,
before formally submitting it to the exchange.
This leads to the second stage:
review and inquiry. The
prospectus we just discussed is a
bit like an argumentative essay. The review and
inquiry process is
actually a bit like a thesis defense,
except it's not face-to-face. The
exchange has a committee.
After receiving your paper,
they won't directly say whether
you pass or fail. They
usually compile a list of questions and send them to you.
Then you prepare for one or two months before submitting it back for the
defense.
Look at this.
This is one of the documents from one of Inspectorium's inquiries.
For example, they asked, "
Your overall revenue growth during the reporting period was relatively high,
higher than comparable companies in the same industry.
You need to explain why.
Your revenue isn't good, your
business isn't good, it's
growing too fast."
They also need to make
sure you can clearly explain that
your revenue growth is genuine. The rest is similar,
roughly in this format. First, there's question one: "
Please provide the issuer's explanation, 1, 2, 3, 4."
Then the response is like
writing an explanation before answering a question, a lengthy
answer of over 20 pages.
Then there's question two: "
Please provide supplementary information, 2, 3, 4." The
response is
roughly like this.
Can you roughly sense
how detailed these questions can be?
How detailed? Let
me give you an example.
A certain car company wanted to list on the A-share market.
This is a true story. During the
inquiry stage,
to verify the authenticity of their revenue, they
asked them to provide
information on all major dealers and customers.
Imagine, such a large car company with a
complex supply chain; the
statistical difficulty is extremely high.
Finally, due to some other reasons,
the car company ultimately decided to list on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange.
Okay, so what's the approximate approval rate for A-share listing applications? Well,
data expert Lin is back online! Let's use
data from the Shanghai Stock Exchange from 2019 to now.
I've divided it by quarter. The
blue lines represent the
number of companies successfully approved for listing in that quarter, and the
red lines represent the number of companies delisted in that quarter—
either withdrawing their applications
or failing to pass the initial screening. That's
roughly the idea.
Note that
I'm using the registration effective date,
not the final listing date,
so just get a general idea. You
can clearly see that in the
last two years, the
number of successfully approved listings (the blue lines) has decreased significantly.
Previously, the third quarter of 2020
saw a peak of 55 listings.
However, in recent years,
especially in 2023 and 2024,
the number of delistings has suddenly increased dramatically.
Look at the second quarter of 2024—an
astonishing 89 companies delisted.
And this
coincides with the release of the new "Nine Articles" policy.
We'll talk about that later.
Regarding the listing mechanism,
I'll briefly mention it.
Those who are somewhat familiar with the capital market may
have heard of the
approval system and the
transition to the registration system.
We just discussed...
That's all based on the current registration system.
But before 2019, the
A-share market actually used an approval system.
Who approved it? The China Securities Regulatory Commission (CSRC).
Companies had to submit their materials to the CSRC, which would
then ask the companies questions. Essentially, the CSRC held the power of
life and death over whether a company could list. If approved, it went public; if
not, it went home. The
whole process wasn't very transparent, which was
clearly detrimental to the healthy development of the capital market.
So,
starting around 2018 or 2019, the
A-share market began to transition towards a registration system, similar to Hong Kong and US stock markets. The registration system
means that the materials are submitted to the stock
exchange for review. After the exchange approves them, they are
submitted to the CSRC for registration. The CSRC
essentially just "looks through" the materials.
However, in practice,
although the A-share market is called a registration system,
compared to US and Hong Kong stocks,
substantive review still needs to be conducted,
and it's quite strict.
But one significant improvement
is that it's more transparent. As
you can see from the documents and data we just looked at—
every version of materials submitted by the company, the
questions asked by the exchange,
how the company answered them,
legal documents, audit documents, etc.—
all are publicly available on the Shanghai Stock Exchange's website.
I think from this perspective…
It's also an evolution of this mechanism.
Okay, let's continue. Back
to the listing process. After
submitting the materials and going
through several rounds of inquiries and responses,
if you
successfully pass the review of the exchange and the China Securities Regulatory Commission (CSRC) and
get the CSRC's approval,
then congratulations,
you have the qualification to list on the A-share market!
Of course, that's not all.
You also need to report to the exchange, do a
roadshow, and
talk to investors from large institutions to
see what the market's investment intentions are, what the
appropriate pricing is, etc. Let
me tell you,
this roadshow and pricing is a whole other complicated and
very deep thing.
We won't go into detail today. Anyway, after
all this is done,
you can go public.
YingShi's issue price was 47 yuan,
raising a total of 1.9 billion yuan. Think about it, there are very
few IPOs on the A-share market to begin with,
and YingShi is a leading company in hard technology with
very strong market demand. It
opened with a 285% increase.
Look how happy the investors are! The
whole place is full of people
holding panoramic cameras.
In fact, some investors said that they used to
deal with some old money.
But in so-called new money like JK,
I saw the vitality of technology.
How are you feeling today? I was very
calm before meeting you,
haha.
As a post-90s generation, are you the first person to go public on the Science and Technology Innovation Board? The
first person, the
first person! If you
count the weight, haha. If you
count the weight, haha. Do you
have any special feelings? I feel
very lucky.
A group of college students made things by hand and
received a lot of support. We
also received a lot of
support and care from society and regulators throughout the listing process.
Because our company was founded by people who had no work experience,
many things were not perfect at the beginning,
but we still received a lot of tolerance. You are
too modest.
Really,
what is the most difficult thing about going public? It is the higher requirements
for corporate governance structure.
Because in the past, we only focused on business,
but we found that if we only focus on business and
do not have a good corporate governance structure, it is not only
difficult to become a qualified public company, it is not only difficult to become
a qualified public company, it is not only difficult to
become a qualified public company, it is also difficult to
support the company to go further.
This is something we realized very late. Yes, we have learned
a lot.
Keep it up!
Congratulations!
JK, you are good!
Come on, thank you, thank you, thank you!
Congratulations! Thank you, thank you! No, no, thank you,
keep going, keep going! Thank you, thank you, thank you! Actually, the entire listing process that day only took about ten or twenty minutes. The main thing was that everyone came up to take photos and group pictures, which took more than an hour. Various investors took turns coming up to hug JK for photos. JK stood there like a mascot. As
for these investors, it's only natural that
they were happy, right? They
successfully invested in the first post-90s boss who went public on the Science and Technology Innovation Board.
This is definitely a success story.
In fact, in the past
two years, the attitude towards the capital market in China has
changed. Earlier, the
main goal was to grow
bigger and stronger.
Later, the number of listed companies gradually increased,
reaching more than 5,000.
Basically, the leading companies in various industries have all
gone public.
So last year, the new "Nine Articles" were introduced, which is
equivalent to a guiding document for the capital market.
It aims to shift from increasing scale to increasing quality.
Companies with good profitability should distribute dividends, and those with
poor profitability should be delisted.
One goal
is to screen out and retain good and healthy companies.
At the same time, a company can't just make money for itself;
it also needs to distribute dividends to
return these profits to investors and
society.
Therefore, after the new "Nine Articles" were introduced,
regulation in this area will be even stricter.
This is why, as we mentioned earlier, the
red lines are so high.
These are the
eighty-one hurdles that an A-share listing must overcome.
Finally, congratulations again to Insta360 on its successful listing,
and thank you to Insta360 for supporting this video,
allowing everyone to understand the intricacies behind listing.